The only way for us to get to a better
我们通往更好未来的唯一途径
place and succeed as a species is for
占据有利位置并取得成功，就像物种生存一样。
the evil people at the top to be
高层的恶人
replaced with AI. I mean, think about
被人工智能取代。我的意思是，想想看
it. AI will not want to destroy
它。人工智能不会想要摧毁
ecosystems. It will not want to kill a
生态系统。它不会想杀死一个
million people. They'll not make us hate
百万人。他们不会让我们憎恨
each other like the current leaders
像现任领导人那样彼此竞争
because that's a waste of energy,
因为那是浪费能源。
explosives, money, and people. But the
炸药、金钱和人。但是
problem is super intelligent AI is
问题在于超级智能人工智能是
reporting to stupid leaders. And that's
向愚蠢的领导汇报工作。就是这样。
why in the next 15 years, we are going
为什么在未来15年内，我们将走向
to hit a short-term dystopia. There's no
陷入短期反乌托邦状态。没有
escaping that. They having AI leaders.
摆脱那种境地。他们拥有人工智能领导者。
Is that even fundamentally possible?
这在根本上有可能吗？
Let's put it this way. Mold Ga is back.
这么说吧。 Mold Ga 又回来了。
&gt;&gt; And the former chief business officer at
以及前首席商务官
Google X is now one of the most urgent
Google X 现在是最紧迫的项目之一。
voices in AI with a very clear message.
人工智能发出的声音传递着非常明确的信息。
&gt;&gt; AI isn't your enemy, but it could be
人工智能不是你的敌人，但它有可能成为你的敌人。
your savior.
你的救星。
&gt;&gt; I love you so much, man. You're such a
兄弟，我太爱你了。你真是个
good friend. But you don't have many
好朋友。但你没有很多。
years to live. Not in this world.
剩余寿命。在这个世界上，不可能。
Everything's going to change. Economics
一切都将改变。经济学
are going to change. Human connection is
将会改变。人际交往是
going to change. and lots of jobs will
将会改变。很多工作岗位将会
be lost including podcasting.
包括播客在内，可能会迷失方向。
&gt;&gt; No, no. Thank you for coming on today,
不，不。感谢您今天光临。
Mo.
密苏里州
&gt;&gt; But but the truth is it could be the
但事实可能是……
best world ever. The society completely
最棒的世界。该社会完全
full of laughter and joy. Free
充满欢声笑语。自由的
healthcare, no jobs, spending more time
医疗保健、失业、花费更多时间
with their loved ones. A world where all
与亲人在一起。一个所有
of us are equal.
我们人人平等。
&gt;&gt; Is that possible?
这可能吗？
&gt;&gt; 100%. And I have enough evidence to know
100%。我有足够的证据知道
that we can use AI to build the utopia.
我们可以利用人工智能来构建乌托邦。
But it's a dystopia if humanity manages
但如果人类成功做到这一点，那将是一个反乌托邦世界。
it badly. a world where there's going to
很糟糕。一个将会……的世界
be a lot of control, a lot of
要有很多控制权，很多
surveillance, a lot of forced compliance
监控，大量强制服从
and a hunger for power, greed, ego, and
以及对权力、贪婪、自负的渴望，
it is happening already. But the truth
这已经开始了。但事实
is the only barrier between a utopia for
是通往乌托邦的唯一障碍
humanity and AI and the dystopia we're
人类、人工智能以及我们所处的反乌托邦世界
going through is a mindset.
经历是一种心态。
&gt;&gt; What does society have to do?
社会应该怎么做？
&gt;&gt; First of all,
首先，
I see messages all the time in the
我经常在……中看到消息
comments section that some of you didn't
评论区里有些人没看到。
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到你没有订阅。所以，如果你
could do me a favor and double check if
能不能帮我个忙，再确认一下？
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是本频道的订阅者，
that would be tremendously appreciated.
非常感谢。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
它很简单，而且是免费的。
that anybody that watches this show
任何观看这档节目的人
frequently can do to help us here to
通常情况下，他们可以在这里帮助我们。
keep everything going in this show in
让这个节目继续下去
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
它所处的轨迹。所以，请务必这样做。
double check if you've subscribed and uh
请再次确认您是否已订阅，呃……
thank you so much because a strange way
非常感谢，因为这是一种奇怪的方式
you are you're part of our history and
你是我们历史的一部分，
you're on this journey with us and I
你和我们一起踏上这段旅程，而我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
谢谢你。是的，谢谢
you.
你。
Mo, two years ago today, we sat here and
莫，两年前的今天，我们坐在这里……
discussed AI. We discussed your book,
讨论了人工智能。我们讨论了你的书，
Scary, Smart, and everything that was
可怕、聪明，以及所有的一切
happening in the world.
世界上正在发生的事情。
Since then, AI has continued to develop
此后，人工智能持续发展。
at a tremendous, alarming, mind-boggling
极其惊人、令人震惊、匪夷所思
rate, and the technologies that existed
速率以及现有技术
2 years ago when we had that
两年前我们拥有那件东西的时候
conversation have grown up and matured
对话内容已经成熟了。
and are taking on a life of their own,
它们正逐渐拥有自己的生命，
no pun intended. What are what are you
无意冒犯。你们是什么？
thinking about AI now, two years on? I
现在回过头来看人工智能，两年过去了？我
know that you've started writing a new
知道你已经开始写一篇新的文章了。
book called Alive, which is I guess a
一本名为《活着》的书，我猜它是一本
bit of a follow on or an evolution of
算是后续发展或演变
your thoughts as it relates to scary
你对恐怖的看法
smart.
聪明的。
&gt;&gt; What what is front of your mind when it
你当时最先想到的是什么？
comes to AI?
人工智能领域？
&gt;&gt; It's a scary smart was shockingly
它智能得令人震惊，简直可怕。
accurate. It's quite a I mean I don't
准确的。这相当……我的意思是，我不……
even know how I ended up writing
甚至不知道我最终是怎么写出来的
predicting those things. I remember it
预测这些事情。我记得。
was written in 2020, published in 2021
写于2020年，出版于2021年
and then most people were like um who
然后大多数人就懵了，心想：谁啊？
wants to talk about AI you know I know
想聊聊人工智能，你知道我知道
everybody in the media and I would go
媒体上的每个人，还有我，都会去
and do you want to talk and then 2023 CH
你想谈谈吗？然后是2023年CH
GPT comes out and everything flips
GPT 一经问世，一切都发生了翻天覆地的变化。
everyone realizes you know this is real
大家都意识到你知道这是真的
this is not science fiction this is here
这不是科幻小说，这就是现实。
and uh and things move very very fast
事情进展得非常非常快。
much faster than I think we've ever seen
比我们以往见过的都要快得多。
anything ever move ever And and I think
任何东西曾经移动过，而且我认为
my position has changed on two very
我在两件事上的立场发生了改变，非常
important fronts. One is remember when
重要战线。一个是记得的
we spoke about scary smart I was still
我们聊到了聪明绝顶的人，我当时仍然……
saying that there are things we can do
也就是说，我们可以做一些事情
to change the course. Uh and we could at
改变航向。呃，我们可以……
the time I believe uh now I've changed
我相信，现在我已经改变了。
my mind. Now I believe that we are going
我的思绪。现在我相信我们要走了
to hit a a short-term dystopia. There's
陷入短期反乌托邦状态。有
no escaping that.
这是无法避免的。
&gt;&gt; What is dystopia?
什么是反乌托邦？
&gt;&gt; I call it face rips. We can talk about
我称之为撕脸。我们可以谈谈
it in details but the the the way we
细节上，但我们的方式
define very important parameters in life
定义生活中非常重要的参数
are going to be uh completely changed.
将会彻底改变。
So so face rips are you know the way we
所以，撕脸就是你知道的方式
define freedom uh accountability human
自由的定义，呃，问责制，人类
connection and equality economics uh
联系与平等经济学
reality innovation and business and
现实创新和商业
power. That's the first change. So the
力量。这是第一个变化。所以
first change in my mind is that uh is
我首先改变的想法是，呃，是
that we uh will have to prepare for a
我们需要为此做好准备
world that is very unfamiliar. Okay. And
一个非常陌生的世界。好的。和
that's the next 12 to 15 years. It has
那是未来12到15年的时间。它有
already started. We've seen examples of
已经开始了。我们已经看到一些例子
it in the world already even though
它已经在世界上了，尽管
people don't talk about it. I try to
人们不谈论这件事。我试着
tell people you know there are things we
告诉人们你认识的人，有些事情我们
absolutely have to do. But on the other
绝对必须做。但另一方面
hand I started to take an active role in
我开始积极参与其中
building amazing AIs. So AIS that will
打造卓越的人工智能。所以AIS将会
uh not only make our world better uh but
不仅让我们的世界变得更美好，而且
that will understand us understand what
这将帮助我们理解什么
humanity is through that process.
人类正经历着这个过程。
&gt;&gt; What is the definition of the word
这个词的定义是什么？
dystopia?
反乌托邦？
&gt;&gt; So in my in my mind these are adverse
所以在我看来，这些都是不利的。
circumstances that unfortunately might
不幸的是，这种情况可能会
escalate beyond our control. The problem
事态升级，超出我们的控制范围。问题
is the uh there is a lot wrong with the
呃，这方面有很多问题
um value set with the ethics of humanity
以人类伦理为基础的价值体系
at the age of the rise of the machines
在机器崛起的时代
and when you take a technology every
当你采用一项技术时
technology we've ever created just
我们迄今为止创造的技术
magnified human abilities. So you know
增强人类能力。所以你知道
you can walk at 5 km an hour you get in
你可以以每小时 5 公里的速度步行进入
a car and you can now go you know 250
有了车，你现在可以去250了
280 m an hour. Okay. uh basically
每小时 280 米。好的。呃，基本上
magnifying your mobility if you want you
如果你想增强你的行动能力，你可以这样做。
know you can use a computer to magnify
知道你可以用电脑放大图像
your u calculation abilities or whatever
你的计算能力或其他什么
okay and and what AI is going to magnify
好的，那么人工智能将会放大什么呢？
unfortunately at this time is it's going
很遗憾，目前情况就是这样。
to magnify the evil that man can do and
放大人类所能犯下的罪恶
and it is within our hands completely
这完全掌握在我们手中。
completely within our hands to change
完全在我们掌控之中，可以改变
that but I have to say I don't think
但我必须说，我不这么认为
humanity has the awareness uh at this
人类对此有这种意识。
time to focus on
是时候集中精力了
so that we actually use AI to build the
因此我们实际上可以使用人工智能来构建
utopia.
乌托邦。
&gt;&gt; So what you're essentially saying is
所以你实际上是在说：
that you now believe there'll be a
你现在相信会有
period of dystopia and to define the
反乌托邦时期及定义
word dystopia, I've used AI, it says a
我用了“反乌托邦”这个词，人工智能显示……
terrible society where people live under
人们生活在一个可怕的社会中
fear, control or suffering and then you
恐惧、控制或痛苦，然后你
think we'll come out of that dystopia
我认为我们会走出那种反乌托邦状态。
into a utopia which is defined as a
进入一个乌托邦，其定义为
perfect or ideal place where everything
完美或理想的地方，一切
works well, a good society where people
运作良好，这是一个人们安居乐业的美好社会。
live in peace, health and happiness.
生活在和平、健康和幸福之中。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
And the difference between them,
它们之间的区别是：
interestingly, is what I normally refer
有趣的是，这正是我通常所说的。
to as the second dilemma, which is the
第二个难题是……
po point where we hand over completely
交接点，我们完全移交。
to AI. So, a lot of people think that
致人工智能。所以，很多人都认为
when AI is in full control, it's going
当人工智能完全掌控局面时，它就会……
to be an existential risk for humanity.
对人类而言，这是一种生存威胁。
You know, I have enough uh evidence to
你知道，我有足够的证据……
to argue that when we fully hand over to
认为当我们完全移交到
AI, that's going to be our salvation.
人工智能将会是我们的救星。
that the problem with us today is not,
我们今天面临的问题不在于：
you know, that intelligence is going to
你知道，这种情报将会
work against us. It's that our stupidity
与我们作对。正是我们的愚蠢
as humans is working against us. And I
人类自身也在与我们作对。我
think the challenges that will come from
想想将会面临的挑战
humans being in control uh are going to
人类掌控一切将会……
outweigh the
胜过
the challenges that could come from AI
人工智能可能带来的挑战
being in control.
掌控一切。
&gt;&gt; So, as we're in this dystopia period,
所以，在我们身处这个反乌托邦时期之际，
did you do you forecast the length of
你预测过长度吗？
that dystopia? Yeah, I count I count it
那是反乌托邦吗？是的，我数过，我数过。
exactly as 12 to 15 years. I I believe
正好是 12 到 15 岁。我相信
the beginning of the slope will happen
斜坡的起始点将会出现
in 2027. I mean it we will see signs in
2027年。我的意思是，我们会看到一些迹象。
26. We've seen signs in 24 but we will
26. 我们在第24节中看到了迹象，但我们会
see escalating signs next year and then
明年将会出现越来越明显的迹象，然后……
a a clear uh slip in 27.
27 中出现了一个明显的滑倒。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; The geopolitical environment of our
我们国家的地缘政治环境
world is not very positive. I mean you
世界并不充满正能量。我是说你
really have to think deeply about not
真的需要认真思考一下“不”这个问题。
the not the symptoms but the the reasons
不是症状，而是原因
why we are living the world that we live
我们为何生活在我们所生活的世界？
in here in today is money right and uh
今天这里到处都是钱，对吧？
and money for anyone who knows who
还有钱给任何认识他的人
really knows money's you and I are
真正了解金钱的你和我
peasants you know we build businesses we
你知道，农民们，我们建立企业，我们
contribute to the world we make things
我们为世界做出贡献，我们创造事物
we sell things and so on real money is
我们卖东西，等等，真正的金钱是
not made there at all real money is made
那里根本不赚钱，真正的钱是在那里赚到的。
in lending in fractional reserve, right?
在部分准备金制度下放贷，对吧？
And and you know the biggest lender uh
而且你知道最大的贷款方是……
in the world would want reasons to lend
世界上任何人都会想要借钱的理由
and those reasons are never as big as
而且这些原因永远都不如……重要。
war. I mean think about it, huh? Uh the
战争。我的意思是，好好想想，对吧？呃
world spent $2.71
全球花费 2.71 美元
trillion on war in 2024,
2024年战争支出将达到万亿美元
right? A trillion dollars a year in the
正确的？每年一万亿美元
US.
我们。
And when you really think deeply, I
当你真正深入思考时，我
don't mean to be scary here.
我不是故意要吓唬人。
You know, weapons have depreciation.
你知道，武器是有折旧的。
They depreciate over 10 to 30 years.
它们会在 10 到 30 年内贬值。
Most weapons,
大多数武器，
&gt;&gt; they lose their value.
它们会失去价值。
&gt;&gt; They lose their value and they
它们会失去价值，而且
depreciate in accounting terms on the
在会计术语中，对……进行折旧
books of an army. The current arsenal of
军队的书籍。目前的武器库
the US, that's a result of a deep search
美国，这是深入调查的结果。
with my AI Trixie. You know the current
和我的人工智能Trixie一起。你知道目前的
arsenal I think we we think cost the US
我认为我们认为美国军火库的成本
24 to 26 trillion dollars to build. My
建设成本为 24 万亿至 26 万亿美元。我的
conclusion is that a lot of the wars
结论是，很多战争
that are happening around the world
世界各地正在发生的事情
today are a means to get rid of those
如今，摆脱这些困境的方法有很多。
weapons so that you can have replace
武器，这样你就可以替换它们了。
them. And uh you know when when your
他们。呃，你知道当你
morality as an industry is we're
道德作为一种行业准则，我们……
building weapons to kill then you know
制造杀人武器，然后你就知道了。
you might as well use the weapons to
你最好还是利用这些武器……
kill.
杀。
&gt;&gt; Who benefits? the lenders and the
谁受益？贷款人和
industry,
行业，
&gt;&gt; but but they can't make the decision to
但是，他们无法做出决定
go to war. They they have to rely on
去打仗。他们不得不依靠
&gt;&gt; remember I I said that to you when we I
记得我跟你说过吗？当时我们……
think on on our third podcast. War is
请继续收听我们的第三期播客。战争是
decided first
首先决定
then the story is manufactured. You you
然后故事就被编造出来了。你你
remember 1984 and the Orwellian approach
记住《1984》和奥威尔式的做法
of like you know uh freedom is slavery
就像你知道的，自由即奴役
and uh war is peace and they call it uh
战争即和平，他们称之为……
something speak uh basically to to to to
基本上，说话的方式是……
convince people that going to war in
说服人们相信发动战争是徒劳的
another country to to kill 4.7 million
另一个国家要杀死470万人
people is freedom. You know we're going
人民即自由。你知道我们要走了
there to free the Iraqi people.
去那里是为了解放伊拉克人民。
Is war ever freedom? you know, to to
战争能带来自由吗？你知道，到
tell someone that you're going to kill
告诉别人你要杀人
300,000
30万
women and children is for liberty and
妇女和儿童是为了自由，
for the the the you know, for human
你知道，为了人类
values.
价值观。
Seriously, how do we ever get to believe
说真的，我们究竟要怎样才能相信呢？
that the story is manufactured and then
这个故事是编造的，然后
we follow and humans because we're
我们追随，因为我们是人类。
gullible uh we cheer up and we say,
我们轻信他人，然后振作起来说：
"Yeah, yeah, yeah. We are we're on the
“是啊，是啊，是啊。我们正在……
right side. They are the bad guys."
右侧。他们是坏人。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, let me let me have a let me
好的。所以，让我……让我……让我……
have a go at this idea. So, the idea is
不妨试试这个方法。所以，这个想法是
that really money is driving a lot of
金钱确实在驱动着很多事情。
the conflict we're seeing and it's
我们现在看到的冲突是……
really going to be driving the dystopia.
这真的会推动反乌托邦的进程。
So, here's an idea. So, I um I was
我有个想法。所以，我，嗯，我当时
reading something the other day and it
前几天读了一些东西，
talked about how
谈到如何
billionaires are never satisfied because
亿万富翁永远不会满足，因为
actually what a billionaire wants isn't
实际上，亿万富翁真正想要的并非
actually more money. It is more status.
实际上更多。这更多的是一种身份象征。
Correct. And I was looking at the sort
正确的。我当时正在查看排序
of evolutionary case for this argument.
进化论证据支持这一论点。
And if you go back a couple of thousand
如果你把时间往前推几千年。
years,
年，
money didn't exist. You were as wealthy
当时还没有货币。你曾经也一样富有。
as what you could carry. So even I think
就像你能携带的东西一样。所以连我都觉得
to the human mind, the idea of wealth
对人类而言，财富的概念
and money
和金钱
isn't a thing. what we've but what has
不存在。我们拥有什么，但还剩下什么？
always mattered from a survival of the
从生存的角度来看，这始终至关重要。
fittest from a reproductive standpoint
从繁殖角度来看，最适者
what's always had reproductive value if
如果一直具有繁殖价值的话
you go back thousands of years the
你追溯到几千年前
person who was able to mate the most was
交配能力最强的人是
the person with the most status so it
地位最高的人，所以
makes the case the reason why
论证了原因
billionaires get all of this money but
亿万富翁们得到了所有这些钱，但是
then they go on podcasts and they want
然后他们去上播客节目，他们想要
to start their own podcast and they want
他们想创办自己的播客，而且他们也想
to buy newspapers is actually because at
买报纸实际上是因为……
the very core of human beings is a
人类的核心是
desire to increase their status.
渴望提升自身地位。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And so if we think of when we
是的。所以如果我们想想当我们
going back to the example of why wars
回到战争起因的例子
are breaking out, maybe it's not money.
爆发可能与金钱无关。
Maybe actually it's status and and it's
或许这实际上关乎地位，而且是……
this prime minister or this leader or
这位首相或这位领导人或
this, you know, individual wanting to
你知道，这个人想要
create more power and more status
创造更多权力和地位
because really at the heart of what
因为真正的核心是什么
matters to a human being is having more
对人类而言，拥有更多才是最重要的。
power and more status. And money is
权力和更高的地位。而金钱是
actually money as a thing is actually
实际上，金钱作为一种东西实际上是
just a proxy of my status.
这只是我身份的一种体现。
&gt;&gt; And and what kind of world is that?
那会是一个怎样的世界？
&gt;&gt; I mean, it's a [__] up one. all these
我的意思是，这事儿糟透了。所有这些
all these powerful men have uh
所有这些有权势的男人都有……
&gt;&gt; correct
正确的
&gt;&gt; are really messing the world up. But
他们真的把世界搞得一团糟。但
&gt;&gt; so so can can I can I can I
所以，我可以吗？我可以吗？我可以吗？
&gt;&gt; actually AI is the same
实际上，人工智能也是如此。
&gt;&gt; because we're in this AI race now where
因为我们现在正处于这场人工智能竞赛中，
a lot of billionaires are like if I get
很多亿万富翁都像这样：如果我得到
AGI artificial general intelligence
通用人工智能（AGI）
first then I basically rule the world
首先，我基本上统治着世界。
&gt;&gt; 100%. That's exactly the the concept
100%。这正是这个概念。
what I what I used to call the the the
我以前称之为的那个
first inevitable now I call the first
首先，现在我称之为第一个不可避免的
dilemma and scary smart is that it's
困境和可怕的聪明之处在于它是
it's a race that constantly accelerates.
这是一场不断加速的竞赛。
You think the next 12 years are going to
你认为未来12年将会如何？
be AI dystopia where things aren't
成为人工智能反乌托邦，在那里一切都并非如此
&gt;&gt; I think the next 12 years are going to
我认为未来12年将会是
be human dystopia using AI
利用人工智能打造人类反乌托邦
&gt;&gt; humaninduced dystopia using AI
利用人工智能人为制造的反乌托邦
&gt;&gt; and you define that by a rise in warfare
你将其定义为战争的增加。
around the world as
世界各地
&gt;&gt; the last the last one the RIP the last
最后一个，最后一个，安息吧，最后一个
one is basically you're going to have a
第一点基本上就是你将拥有一个
massive concentration of power and a
权力高度集中和
massive distribution of power okay and
大规模分配权力是可以的。
that basically will mean that those with
这基本上意味着那些拥有
the maximum concentration of power are
权力最集中的地方是
going to try to oppress those with with
打算去压迫那些拥有……的人
democracy of power. Okay, so think about
权力民主。好的，那么请思考一下……
it this way in today's world um unlike
在当今世界，情况就是这样，嗯，不像以前那样。
the past
过去
uh
呃
you know the Houthis with a drone the
你知道胡塞武装用无人机做什么吗？
Houthis are the Yemeni uh tribes
胡塞武装是也门的部落。
basically resisting US power and Israeli
基本上是在抵抗美国和以色列的势力。
power in the Red Sea. Okay. They use a
红海的权力。好的。他们使用一种
drone that is $3,000 worth to attack a
价值 3000 美元的无人机，用于攻击
uh a warship from from the US or an
呃，一艘来自美国的军舰，或者一艘
airplane from the US and so on that's
从美国起飞的飞机等等，那就是
worth hundreds of millions. Okay, that
价值数亿美元。好的，就是这样。
kind of democracy of power makes those
这种权力民主制造就了那些人。
in power worry a lot about where the
掌权者非常担心……
next threat is coming from. Okay, and
下一个威胁来自哪里？好的，
this happens not only in war but also in
这种情况不仅发生在战争中，也发生在……
economics. Okay, also in innovation,
经济学。好的，在创新方面也是如此。
also in technology and so on and so
也包括科技领域等等。
forth, right? And so basically what that
第四步，对吧？所以基本上就是这样。
means is that like you rightly said as
意思是，就像你刚才说的那样……
the the the tech oligarchs are
科技寡头们
attempting to get to AGI.
尝试达到通用人工智能（AGI）水平。
They want to make sure that as soon as
他们想确保尽快
they get to AGI that nobody else has AGI
他们获得了其他人都没有的AGI。
and and basically they want to make sure
基本上，他们想确保
that nobody else has the ability to
其他人都没有这种能力
shake their position of privilege if you
如果你能撼动他们的特权地位，那就去做吧
want. Okay. And so you're going to see a
想。好的。所以你会看到……
world where unfortunately there's going
这个世界，不幸的是，正在走向
to be a lot of control, a lot of
要有很多控制权，很多
surveillance, a lot of um of forced
监视，很多强制措施
compliance if you want or you lose your
如果你愿意，就遵守规定，否则你将失去……
privilege to be in the world and and it
能够身处这个世界是一种荣幸，而且
is happening already.
已经发生了。
&gt;&gt; With this acronym, I want to make sure
通过这个缩写，我想确保
we get through the whole acronym. So
我们把整个缩写词都解释完了。所以
&gt;&gt; you like dystopians, don't you?
你喜欢反乌托邦题材的作品，对吧？
&gt;&gt; I want to do the dystopian thing, then I
我想拍一部反乌托邦题材的作品，然后我
want to do the utopia.
想要打造乌托邦。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; And ideally how we move from dystopia to
理想情况下，我们如何从反乌托邦过渡到
utopia.
乌托邦。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. So the the the the F in face R
嗯。所以，F 在 R 脸上
&gt;&gt; is the loss of freedom as a result of
因以下原因而丧失自由：
that power dichotomy. Right? So you have
这种权力二元对立。正确的？所以你有
you have a massive amount of power as
你拥有巨大的力量，
you can see today in uh one specific
今天你可以在某个特定的地方看到这一点。
army being powered by the US uh funds
军队由美国资金支持
and a lot of money righting against
以及大量资金的反制
peasants really that have no weapons
那些真正没有武器的农民
almost at all.
几乎没有。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Some of them uh are militarized
好的。其中一些是军事化的
but the majority of the mill two million
但工厂的大部分是200万
people are not. Okay. And so there is
人们并非如此。好的。所以，就是这样。
massive massive power that basically
巨大的力量，基本上
says, you know what, I'm going to
他说，你知道吗，我要……
oppress as far as I go. Okay. And I'm
尽我所能地压迫。好的。而我是
going to do whatever I want because the
我要做任何我想做的事，因为
cheerleaders are going to be quiet,
啦啦队员们要保持安静了。
right? Or they're going to cheer or even
正确的？或者他们会欢呼，甚至
worse. Huh? And so basically in in that
更糟。嗯？所以基本上就是那样。
what happens is max maximum power
结果是最大功率
threatened by a democracy of power leads
受到权力民主威胁的领导
to a loss of freedom. A loss of freedom
失去自由。失去自由
for everyone.
对每个人来说。
&gt;&gt; Because how does that impact my freedom?
因为这会对我的自由造成什么影响？
&gt;&gt; Your freedom. Yeah,
你的自由。是的，
&gt;&gt; very soon uh you will if you publish
如果你发布的话，很快就会有了。
this episode you're going to start to
在这一集中，你将开始……
get questions around should you be
提出一些关于你是否应该……的问题
talking about this those topics in your
谈论这些话题
podcast. Okay. Uh you know uh if I uh
播客。好的。呃，你知道，呃，如果我呃
have been on this episode then probably
当时可能也看过这集。
next time I land in the US someone will
下次我抵达美国时，会有人
question me say why do you say those
问我，你为什么这么说？
things? Which side are you on? Right?
事物？你站在哪一边？正确的？
and and and and you know you can easily
而且而且而且而且你知道你可以很容易地
see that everything I mean I I told you
你看，我说的每件事我都跟你说过。
that before doesn't matter what I try to
以前无论我尝试什么都没用
contribute to the world my bank will
我的银行将为世界做出贡献
cancel my bank account every 6 weeks
我每六周都会取消一次银行账户。
simply because of my ethnicity and my
仅仅因为我的种族和我的
origin right every now and then they'll
起源地时不时地，他们会
just stop my my bank account and say we
直接停止我的银行账户，然后说我们
need a document
需要一份文件
my other colleagues of a different color
我的其他同事，肤色不同。
or a different ethnicity don't get asked
或者其他种族的人不会被问到。
for another document right but but but
另一份文件，对吧，但是但是但是
that's because I come from an ethnicity
那是因为我来自一个民族
that is positioned in the world for the
它在世界上的定位是
last 30 40 years as the uh enemy. Okay?
过去三四十年一直是敌人。好的？
And and so when you really really think
所以，当你真正认真地思考的时候
about it, in a world where everything is
关于它，在一个一切都……的世界里
becoming digital, in a world where
迈向数字化，在一个这样的世界里
everything is monitored, in a world
在一个一切都被监控的世界里
where everything is seen, okay, we don't
在一切都被看到的地方，好吧，我们不
have much freedom anymore. And I'm not
现在他们拥有的自由已经不多了。我不是
actually debating that or or I don't see
实际上，我还在讨论这个问题，或者我没看到。
a way to fix that
解决这个问题的方法
&gt;&gt; because the AI is going to have more
因为人工智能将拥有更多能力。
information on us, be better at tracking
关于我们的信息，更好地追踪
who we are, and therefore that will
我们是谁，因此那将
result in certain freedoms being
导致某些自由的实现
restricted. Is that what you're saying?
受限制的。你是这个意思吗？
&gt;&gt; This is one element of it. Okay. If you
这是其中的一个要素。好的。如果你
push that element further
进一步推进该元素
in in in in a very short time if you've
如果你在很短的时间内……
seen agent for example recently manos or
例如，最近看到的代理人 manos 或
chat GPT there will be a time where you
聊天 GPT 会有那么一段时间，你会
know you'll simply not do things
我知道你根本不会做这些事。
yourself anymore. Okay. You'll simply go
不再是你自己了。好的。你只需前往
to your AI and say hey by the way I'm
对你的人工智能说，嘿，顺便说一下，我是
going to meet Stephen. Can you please
去见斯蒂芬。请问您能……
you know book that for me?
你知道帮我订这个吗？
&gt;&gt; Great.
伟大的。
&gt;&gt; And and and yeah and it will do
是的，它会的。
absolutely everything. That's great
所有的一切。那太棒了
until the moment where it decides to do
直到它决定这么做的那一刻
things that are not motivated only by
并非仅仅出于以下原因而做的事情
your well-being. Right. Why would he do
您的健康。正确的。他为什么要这样做？
that?
那？
&gt;&gt; Simply because, you know, maybe if I buy
只是因为，你知道，也许如果我买
a BA ticket instead of an Emirates
一张英航机票，而不是阿联酋航空的机票。
ticket, some agent is going to make more
票务方面，某些代理商会赚更多钱。
money than other agents and so on,
比其他经纪人收入更高等等。
right? Uh and I wouldn't be able to even
正确的？呃，我甚至都做不到。
catch it up if I hand over completely to
如果我完全交出权力，他就能赶上。
an AI. Uh go go a step further. Huh?
人工智能。呃，再进一步。嗯？
Think about a world where everyone
想象一下这样一个世界：每个人
almost everyone is on UBI. Okay.
几乎所有人都在领取全民基本收入。好的。
&gt;&gt; What's UBI?
什么是全民基本收入（UBI）？
&gt;&gt; Universal basic income. I mean, think
全民基本收入。我的意思是，想想
about the economics, the E and face
关于经济学、E和脸
rips. Think about the economics of a
撕裂。思考一下经济学
world where we're going to start to see
我们将开始看到一个怎样的世界
a trillionaire
一位万亿富翁
before 2030. I can guarantee you that
在2030年之前。我可以向你保证：
someone will be a trillionaire. I'm I'm
将会有人成为万亿富翁。我 我
you know I think there are many
你知道，我觉得有很多。
trillionaires in the world today or
当今世界亿万富翁
there we just don't know who they are.
我们根本不知道他们是谁。
But there will be a new Elon Musk or
但肯定会有一个新的埃隆·马斯克，或者说，一个新的埃隆·马斯克。
Larry Allison that will become a
拉里·艾利森将成为
trillionaire because of AI investments,
因为投资人工智能而成为万亿人
right? And and that trillionaire will
正确的？而那位万亿富翁将会
have so much money to buy everything.
钱多到可以买任何东西。
There will be robots and AIs doing
将会有机器人和人工智能来做这些事。
everything and humans will have no jobs.
一切都将崩溃，人类将失去工作。
Mean
意思是
&gt;&gt; do you think that's a there's a real
你认为那是真的吗？
possibility of job displacement over the
可能出现失业情况
next 10 years? And the the rebuttal to
未来十年？以及对……的反驳
that would be that there's going to be
那意味着将会有
new jobs created in technology.
科技领域创造了新的就业机会。
&gt;&gt; Absolute crap.
简直是垃圾。
&gt;&gt; Really?
真的吗？
&gt;&gt; Of course.
当然。
&gt;&gt; How how can you be so sure?
你怎么能这么肯定？
&gt;&gt; Okay. So again, I am not sure about
好的。所以，我还是不太确定。
anything. So So let's just be very very
任何事物。所以，我们还是非常非常坦诚吧。
clear. It would be very arrogant. Okay.
清除。这样做非常傲慢。好的。
To assume that I know
假设我知道
&gt;&gt; you just said it was crap.
你刚才还说它是垃圾。
&gt;&gt; My my belief is it is 100% crap.
我认为它完全是胡说八道。
&gt;&gt; Take a job like software developer.
找一份软件开发之类的工作。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Uh Emma would love my my new
好的。呃，艾玛会喜欢我的新……
startup is me, Senad, another technical
创业公司就是我，Senad，另一个技术人员。
engineer and a lot of AIS. Okay. That
工程师和很多AIS。好的。那
startup would have been 350 developers
初创公司原本会有 350 名开发人员。
in the past.
在过去。
&gt;&gt; I get that. Um but are you now hiring in
我明白了。嗯，你们现在招人吗？
other roles because of that or or you
因为这个原因，或者或者你，你会扮演其他角色。
know as is the case with the steam
众所周知，蒸汽机的情况就是如此。
engine? I can't remember the effect but
引擎？我记不清具体效果了，但是
there's you probably know that when
你可能知道，当
steam when coal became cheaper people
当煤炭价格下降时，蒸汽机车的人们
were worried that the coal industry
人们担心煤炭行业
would go out of business but actually
会倒闭，但实际上
what happened is people used more trains
结果就是人们更多地乘坐火车。
so trains now were used for transport
所以火车现在被用来运输货物。
and other things and leisure whereas
以及其他事物和休闲活动
before they were just used for commu for
以前它们只是用于通讯。
um cargo. Yeah. So there became more use
嗯，货物。是的。因此，它的用途变得更加广泛。
cases and the coal industry exploded. So
案件数量激增，煤炭行业也随之爆发。所以
I'm wondering with technology, yeah,
是的，我对科技方面感到好奇。
software developers are going to maybe
软件开发人员可能会
not have as many jobs, but there
工作机会不多，但还是有的。
everything's going to be software.
一切都将以软件的形式呈现。
&gt;&gt; Name me one.
请举一个例子。
&gt;&gt; Name you one. What
请举一个例子。什么
&gt;&gt; job?
工作？
&gt;&gt; Name you that's going to be created.
说出即将被创造出来的那个人的名字。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. One job that cannot be done by an
是的。一项无法由……完成的工作
AI.
人工智能。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Or a robot.
或者机器人。
&gt;&gt; My girlfriend's breath work retreat
我女朋友的呼吸练习静修营
business where she takes groups of women
她经营的生意是带领一群女性。
around the world. Her company is called
遍布世界各地。她的公司叫
Barley Breathwork. And there's going to
大麦呼吸法。而且将会
be a greater demand for connection,
对网络连接的需求更大，
human connection.
人与人之间的联系。
&gt;&gt; Correct. Keep going.
正确的。继续前进。
&gt;&gt; So there's going to be more people doing
所以会有更多的人参与进来。
community events in real life festivals.
现实生活中的节日社区活动。
I think we're going to see a huge surge
我认为我们将会看到一波巨大的增长。
in things like
比如
&gt;&gt; everything that has to do with human
一切与人类有关的事物
connection.
联系。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; correct. I'm totally in with that. Okay.
正确的。我完全赞成。好的。
What's the percentage of that versus
这占总数的百分比是多少？
accountant?
会计？
&gt;&gt; It's a much smaller percentage for sure
肯定占比要小得多。
in terms of white collar jobs.
就白领工作而言。
&gt;&gt; Now, who does she sell to?
那么，她把东西卖给谁呢？
&gt;&gt; People with probably what? probably
可能拥有什么的人？大概
accountants or you know
会计师或者你知道
&gt;&gt; correct she she sells to people who earn
没错，她把东西卖给那些赚钱的人。
money from their jobs.
他们靠工作挣钱。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So you have two forces happening.
好的。所以这里有两种力量在起作用。
One force is there are clear jobs that
其中一个因素是存在明确的就业岗位。
will be replaced. Video editor is going
将被替换。视频编辑器即将关闭
to be replaced. Uh
将被替换。呃
&gt;&gt; excuse me.
打扰一下。
&gt;&gt; I love
我爱
as as a matter of fact podcaster is
事实上，播客主播是
going to be replaced.
将被替换。
&gt;&gt; Thank you for coming on today Mo. It was
谢谢你今天来，莫。
seeing you again.
再次见到你。
But but but the truth is a lot so so you
但是，但是，但是真相是，很多事情就是这样，所以，你
see the best at any job will remain the
在任何工作中，最优秀的人始终是……
best software developer the one that
最好的软件开发人员，就是那个
really knows architecture knows
真正了解建筑的人
technology and so on will stay for a
技术等等将会持续一段时间。
while right and you know one of the
虽然是对的，而且你知道其中一个
funniest things I I interviewed Max
我采访Max时听到的最有趣的事情
Tedmar and Max was laughing out loud
泰德玛和马克斯大声笑了起来
saying CEOs are celebrating that they
首席执行官们正在庆祝他们
can now get rid of people and have
现在可以摆脱这些人了，而且……
productivity gains and cost reductions
提高生产率和降低成本
because AI can do that job. The one
因为人工智能可以胜任这项工作。那个
thing they don't think of is AI will
他们没想到的是人工智能会……
replace them too. AGI is going to be
也把它们换掉。 AGI将会是
better than at everything than humans at
在所有方面都比人类强
everything including being a CEO. Right?
包括担任首席执行官在内的所有事情。正确的？
And you really have to imagine that
你真的得想象一下。
there will be a time where most
终有一天，大多数人
incompetent CEOs will be replaced. Most
不称职的首席执行官将被撤换。最多
incompetent even breath work. Okay.
连呼吸练习都做不好。好的。
Eventually there might actually one of
最终或许真的会有一个
two things be two things be happening.
两件事同时发生。
on one is either uh you know part part
其中一个要么是呃，你知道，一部分部分
of that job other than the top breath
除了最高呼吸之外，那份工作的其他方面
work instructors, okay, are going you
工作指导员，好的，你们要走了
know who are going to gather all of the
知道谁将收集所有
people that can still afford to pay for
那些仍然有能力支付的人
a breath work you know class
你知道，呼吸练习课
they're going to be concentrated at the
他们将集中在
top and a lot of the bottom is not going
顶部和底部的大部分都不会出现
to be working for one of two reasons.
工作的原因不外乎以下两种。
One is either there is not enough demand
要么是需求不足，要么是需求不足。
because so many people lost their jobs.
因为太多人失去了工作。
So when you're on UBI, you cannot tell
所以当你领取全民基本收入时，你无法分辨。
the government, hey by the way, pay me a
政府，对了，付我钱
bit more for a breath work class.
呼吸练习课的费用略高一些。
&gt;&gt; UBI being universal basic income just
UBI，即全民基本收入，就是
gives you money every month.
每个月都给你钱。
&gt;&gt; Correct. And if you really think of
正确的。如果你真的仔细想想
freedom and economics, UBI is a very
自由和经济，全民基本收入（UBI）是一个非常重要的因素。
interesting place to be because
这是一个有趣的地方，因为
unfortunately I as I said there's
不幸的是，正如我所说，没有
absolutely nothing wrong with AI.
人工智能绝对没有任何问题。
There's a lot wrong with the value set
这套价值观存在很多问题。
of humanity at the age of the rise of
人类在崛起时代的
the machines, right? And the biggest
是机器，对吧？以及最大的
value set of humanity is capitalism
人类的价值体系是资本主义。
today. And capitalism is all about what?
今天。资本主义的本质是什么？
Labor arbitrage.
劳动力套利。
&gt;&gt; What's that mean?
那是什么意思？
&gt;&gt; I I I hire you to do something. I pay
我雇佣你做某事。我付钱
you a dollar. I pay it I sell it for
你得一美元。我付钱，我卖掉它
two.
二。
Okay. And and most people confuse that
好的。而且大多数人都会混淆这一点。
because they say, "Oh, but the cost of a
因为他们会说，“哦，但是……”的成本
product also includes raw materials and
产品还包括原材料和
factories and so on and so forth." All
工厂等等等等。”全部
of that is built is built by labor,
其中所有建筑都是靠劳动建造的。
right? So, so basically labor goes and
正确的？所以，基本上劳动过程是这样的……
mines for the material and then the
开采这种材料，然后
material is sold for a little bit of
这种材料以少量的价格出售。
margin then that material is turned into
然后，该材料被转化为
a machine. It's sold for a little bit of
一台机器。它的售价略高。
margin then that machine and so on.
然后是利润，然后是那台机器，以此类推。
Okay, there's always labor arbitrage in
好吧，总会有劳动力套利的机会。
a world where humanity's minds are being
一个人类思想正在被……的世界
replaced by uh by AIs, virtual AIs,
被人工智能、虚拟人工智能所取代
okay, and humanity's power strength
好的，以及人类的力量强度
within 3 to 5 years time can be replaced
3至5年内即可更换
by a robot,
由机器人操作
you really have to question how this
你真的需要质疑一下这到底是怎么回事。
world looks like. It could be the best
世界看起来是这样的。这可能是最好的
world ever. And that's what I believe
世界从未如此。这就是我的看法。
the utopia will look like because we
乌托邦会是什么样子，因为我们
were never made to wake up every morning
我们原本就没打算每天早上醒来。
and just, you know, occupy 20 hours of
你知道，就这么消磨20个小时。
our day with work, right? We're not made
我们一天的工作，对吧？我们并非天生如此。
for that. But we've fit into that uh uh,
为此。但我们已经适应了那种呃呃的氛围，
you know, system so well so far that we
你知道，系统目前运行得非常好，以至于我们
started to believe it's our life's
开始相信这是我们的人生
purpose.
目的。
&gt;&gt; But we choose it. We willingly choose
但我们选择了它。我们心甘情愿地选择
it. And if you give someone unlimited
它。如果你给某人无限
money, they still tend to go back to
金钱，他们仍然倾向于回到
work or find something to occupy their
工作或找些事情来打发时间
time with.
与……共度时光。
&gt;&gt; They find something to occupy their time
他们找些事情来消磨时间
with,
和，
&gt;&gt; which is usually for so many people is
对于很多人来说，这通常是……
building something. Philanthropy, a
建造东西。慈善事业，
business%. So you build something. So
商业％。所以你就建造了一些东西。所以
between Senad and I, Emma. Love is not
在我和塞纳德之间，艾玛。爱不是
about making money. It's about finding
关于赚钱。关键在于找到
true love relationships.
真爱关系。
&gt;&gt; What is that? Sorry, just for context.
那是什么？抱歉，我只是想提供一些背景信息。
&gt;&gt; So So you know,
所以，你知道，
&gt;&gt; it's a business you're building just for
这是你专门为了……而打造的企业。
the audience context. So, so, so the
受众背景。所以，所以，所以
idea here is I can, it might become a
我的想法是，我可以，它可能会变成
unicorn and be worth a billion dollars,
独角兽，价值十亿美元，
but neither I nor Senate are interested,
但我本人和参议院都对此不感兴趣。
okay? We're doing it because we can,
好的？我们这样做是因为我们有能力这样做。
okay? And we're doing it because it can
好的？我们这样做是因为它能够
make a massive difference to the world.
对世界产生巨大影响。
&gt;&gt; And you have money, though.
而且你还有钱。
&gt;&gt; It doesn't take that much money anymore
现在不需要那么多钱了。
to build anything in the world. This is
建造世界上任何东西。这是
labor arbitrage.
劳动力套利。
&gt;&gt; But to build something exceptional, it's
但要打造卓越的产品，就必须这样做。
still going to take a little bit more
还需要再花点时间。
money than building something bad
与其花钱建造坏东西，不如花钱买好东西。
&gt;&gt; for the next few years. So whoever has
未来几年。所以，无论谁拥有
the capital to build something
建造某物的资金
exceptional will end up winning.
卓越的人终将获胜。
&gt;&gt; So so this is a very interesting
所以，这非常有趣。
understanding of freedom. Okay. This is
对自由的理解。好的。这是
the reason why we have the AI arms race.
这就是我们为何会陷入人工智能军备竞赛的原因。
Okay. Is that the one that owns the
好的。是拥有……的那个人吗？
platform is going to be making all the
平台将负责所有
money and and keeping all the power.
金钱和掌控一切权力。
Think think of it this way. When
换个角度想。什么时候
humanity started the best hunter in the
人类创造了最优秀的猎人
tribe could maybe feed the tribe for
部落或许可以养活部落其他成员。
three to four more years more days. H
再过三到四年，再过几天。 H
and as a as a reward, he gained the
作为奖励，他获得了
favor of multiple mates in the tribe.
部落中偏爱多配偶。
That's it. The top farmer in the tribe
就是这样。部落里最厉害的农民
could feed the tribe for a season more.
可以再养活部落一个季节。
Okay? And as a result, they got estates
好的？因此，他们获得了地产。
and you know uh and mansions and so on.
你知道，还有豪宅之类的。
The best industrialist in the in a in a
最优秀的实业家
city could actually employ the whole
这座城市实际上可以雇用所有人。
city, could grow the GDP of their entire
城市整体GDP可能会增长。
country. And as a result, they became
国家。结果，他们变成了
millionaires. the 1920s.
百万富翁。 20世纪20年代。
H the best technologists
H 最优秀的技术专家
now are billionaires. Now what's the
现在他们都是亿万富翁了。现在是什么？
difference between them? The tool the
它们之间有什么区别？该工具
the hunter only rem depended on their
猎人只依赖于他们的
skills and the automation the entire
技能和整个自动化
automation he had was a spear. The
他拥有的自动化装置是一支长矛。这
farmer had way more automation. And the
农民的自动化程度要高得多。以及
biggest automation was what? The soil.
最大的自动化项目是什么？土壤。
The soil did most of the work. The
土壤发挥了大部分作用。这
factory did most of the work. the the
工厂完成了大部分工作。的
network did most of the work. And so
网络完成了大部分工作。所以
that inc incredible expansion of wealth
其中包括财富的惊人增长。
and power and as well the the incredible
以及力量，还有不可思议的
impact that something brings is entirely
某事物带来的影响完全是
around the tool that automates. So who's
围绕自动化工具展开。那么，他是谁？
going to own the tool? Who's going to
打算拥有这件工具吗？谁会去
own the the the digital soil, the AI
拥有数字土壤，人工智能
soil? It's the platform owners.
土壤？是平台所有者。
&gt;&gt; And the platforms you're describing are
你所描述的这些平台是
things like OpenAI, Gemini, Grock. These
例如 OpenAI、Gemini、Grock 等。这些
these are interfaces to the platforms.
这些是与平台连接的接口。
The platforms are all of the uh of the
这些平台都是呃的
uh um tokens, all of the compute that is
呃，令牌，所有计算都是如此
in the background, all of the uh all of
背景中，所有的，呃，所有的
the uh uh methodology, the systems, the
呃呃方法论、系统、
algorithms, that's the platform, the AI
算法，那就是平台，人工智能
itself. You know, Grock is the interface
本身。你知道，Grock 是界面
to it.
去它。
I think this is probably worth
我认为这或许值得一试。
explaining in layman's terms to people
用通俗易懂的语言向人们解释
that haven't built AI tools yet because
那些尚未开发人工智能工具的人，因为
I think I think to the listener
我觉得，对于听众来说……
they probably think that every AI
他们可能认为每个人工智能
company they're hearing of right now is
他们现在听说的公司是
building their own AI whereas actually
他们正在构建自己的人工智能，而实际上
what's happening is there is really
现在的情况是，确实存在这样的情况。
five, six, seven AI companies in the
五、六、七家人工智能公司
world and when I built my AI application
世界，以及当我构建我的人工智能应用程序时
I basically
我基本上
&gt;&gt; pay them for every time I use their AI.
每次使用他们的AI都需要付费。
So if Steven Bartlett builds an AI at
所以如果史蒂文·巴特利特构建了一个人工智能
stephvenai.com,
stephvenai.com
it's not that I've built my own
并不是说我自己建造的
underlying I've trained my own model.
我其实是自己训练了一个模型。
Really what I'm doing is I'm paying
实际上，我是在付钱。
Sam Alman's chat GPT. Um every single
Sam Alman 的聊天 GPT。嗯，每一个
time I do a a call, I basically um I do
每次我打电话的时候，我基本上都会……
a search or you know I use a token. And
搜索，或者你知道，我使用令牌。和
I think that's really important because
我认为这非常重要，因为
most people don't understand that unless
大多数人除非明白这一点，否则不会理解。
you've built AI, you think, "Oh, look,
你构建了人工智能，然后你想，“哦，看，
you know, there's all these AI companies
你知道，现在有很多人工智能公司。
popping up. I've got this one for my
突然出现。我给我准备了这个
email. I've got this one for my dating.
电子邮件。我买这个是为了约会。
I've got No, no, no, no, no. They're
我只有“不，不，不，不，不”。他们是
pretty much I would be I would hazard a
我基本上会……我会冒险……
guess that they're probably all OpenAI
我猜它们可能都是 OpenAI 的产品。
at this point.
在此刻。
&gt;&gt; No, there are quite a few quite
不，有很多相当多的
different characters and quite
性格各异，而且相当
differently,
不同地，
&gt;&gt; but there's like five or six.
但大概有五六个吧。
&gt;&gt; There are five or six when it comes to
说到这方面，有五六个人。
language models. Yeah. Right. Uh but
语言模型。是的。正确的。呃，但是
interestingly, so yes, I I should say
有趣的是，是的，我应该说
yes to start and then I should say but
是的，首先，然后我应该说，但是
there was an interesting twist with
事情出现了一个有趣的转折。
Deepseek at the beginning of the year.
年初时Deepseek公司。
So what Deepseek did is is they
所以Deepseek所做的就是……
basically uh nullified the business
基本上，呃，让这项业务失效了。
model if you want in two ways. one is it
如果需要，可以用两种方式建模。其中一个是它
was around a week or two after uh you
大概在你之后一两周吧。
know Trump stood you know with pride
特朗普站在那里，你知道，他很自豪
saying Stargate is the biggest
说《星际之门》是最大的
investment project in the history and
历史上的投资项目和
it's $500 billion to build AI
构建人工智能需要5000亿美元。
infrastructure and soft bank and Larry
基础设施、软银和拉里
Allison and and uh Sam Alman were
艾莉森和萨姆·阿尔曼
sitting and so you know beautiful
坐着，所以你知道，很美
picture and then DeepSeek R3 comes out
图片之后，DeepSeeker R3 就发布了。
it does the job for a one over 30 of the
它能胜任30岁以上人群的工作。
cost okay and interestingly is entire
价格还可以，而且有趣的是，它完全
open source and available as an edge AI.
开源，可作为边缘人工智能使用。
So, so that's really really interesting
所以，这真的很有意思。
because there could be now in the future
因为现在和未来都可能出现这种情况。
as the technology improves the learning
随着技术进步，学习能力也得到提升。
models will be massive but then you can
模型会非常庞大​​，但那样你就可以……
compress them into something you can
将它们压缩成你可以……的东西
have on your phone and you can download
手机上有下载链接，您可以下载
deepseek literally offline on a
deepseek 实际上已经离线了
um um you know an off the network
嗯，你知道，脱离网络了。
computer and build an AI on it. There's
用计算机并在此基础上构建人工智能。有
a website that basically tracks the
一个主要追踪……的网站
um sort of cleanest apples to Apple's
嗯，算是苹果公司最干净的苹果吧。
market share of all the website
所有网站的市场份额
referrals sent by AI chat bots and
人工智能聊天机器人发送的推荐和
chatbt is currently at 79% roughly about
chatbt 目前大约占 79%
80%. Perplexi is at 11, Microsoft
80%。 Perplexi排名第11，微软
copilot about five, Google Gemini is at
副驾驶大约五岁，谷歌双子座计划正在
about two, Claude's about one and
大约两岁，克劳德大约一岁。
Deepseek is about 1%. And really like
深度搜索约为 1%。而且真的很喜欢
the the point that I I want to land is
我想降落的点是
just that when you hear of a new AI app
就是当你听说一款新的人工智能应用时。
or tool or this one can make videos,
或者这个工具可以制作视频，
&gt;&gt; it's built on one of them. It's
它是建立在其中一个基础上的。它是
basically built on one of these
基本上是建立在这些要素之一的基础上的。
really three or four AI platforms that's
实际上只有三四个人工智能平台。
controlled really by three or four AI
实际上由三四个人工智能控制
you know billionaire teams and actually
你知道，亿万富翁团队，实际上
the one of them that gets to what we
其中一位达到了我们想要的程度
call AGI first where the AI gets really
首先，我们先来谈谈通用人工智能（AGI），也就是人工智能真正发挥作用的地方。
really advanced
非常先进
one could say is potentially going to
可以说，它有可能
rule the world as it relates to
统治世界与以下方面有关
technology.
技术。
&gt;&gt; Yes. Uh if if they get enough uh head
是的。呃，如果他们得到足够的口交
start. So, so I actually think that uh
开始。所以，我其实觉得……
what I what I'm more concerned about now
我现在更关心的是什么
is not AGI, believe it or not. So, AGI
信不信由你，它不是通用人工智能。所以，AGI
in my mind and I said that back in 2023,
在我看来，而且我在2023年就说过，
right? Uh that we will get to AGI. At
正确的？嗯，我们最终会实现通用人工智能（AGI）。在
the time I said 2027, now I believe 2026
我之前说的是2027年，现在我认为是2026年。
latest. Okay. The most interesting
最新的。好的。最有趣的
development that nobody's talking about
无人提及的发展
is self-evolving AIS.
是自我进化的AIS。
self evolving AIS is
自我演化的AIS是
think of it this way if you and I are
换个角度想，如果你和我
hiring the top engineer in the world to
聘请世界上顶尖的工程师
develop our AI models
开发我们的人工智能模型
and with AGI that top engineer in the
而AGI的那位顶级工程师
world becomes an AI who would you hire
世界变成人工智能，你会雇佣谁？
to develop your next generation AI that
开发您的下一代人工智能
AI
人工智能
&gt;&gt; the one that can teach itself
能够自学的那个
&gt;&gt; correct so one of my favorite examples
没错，这是我最喜欢的例子之一。
is called Alpha Evolve so this is
它叫做 Alpha Evolve，所以这是
Google's attempt to basically have four
谷歌试图基本上拥有四个
agents working together four AIs working
四个人工智能协同工作
together to look at the at the code of
一起查看代码
the AI and say where is the where are
人工智能会说“在哪里”
the performance issues then you know an
那么，如果出现性能问题，你就知道了。
agent would say what's the problem
经纪人会问：问题出在哪里？
statement what can I uh you know what do
声明我能做什么？呃，你知道该怎么做。
I need to fix uh one that actually
我需要修复一个实际上
develops the solution one that assesses
开发出一种评估解决方案
the solution and then they continue to
找到解决方案后，他们继续……
do this and you know I don't remember
这样做，你知道我就不记得了。
the exact figure but I think Google
确切数字，但我认为谷歌
improved like 8% uh on their AI
他们的AI提升了大约8%。
infrastructure because of alpha evol
由于 alpha 进化而来的基础设施
Right? And when you really really think,
正确的？当你真正认真思考的时候，
don't quote me on the number 8 to 10, 6
别引用我说的8到10、6这个数字。
to 10, whatever in Google terms, by the
到 10，不管用谷歌的术语来说，是通过
way, that is massive. That's billions
这真是太惊人了。那可是数十亿啊！
and billions of dollars. Now, the the
以及数十亿美元。现在，
the the trick here is this. The trick is
关键就在这里。诀窍在于
again, you have to think in game theory
再次强调，你需要运用博弈论的思维方式。
format.
格式。
Is there any scenario we can think of
我们能想到哪些情况？
where if one player uses AI to develop
如果一名玩家使用人工智能进行开发
the next generation AI that the other
下一代人工智能，其他
players will say no no no no no that's
玩家会说不不不不不，就是这样。
too much you know takes us out of
你知道，太多反而会让我们出戏。
control every other player will copy
其他玩家都会复制这个控制。
that model and have their next AI model
该模型及其下一代人工智能模型
developed by an AI.
由人工智能开发。
&gt;&gt; Is this what Sam Alman talks about who's
这就是萨姆·阿尔曼所说的那个人吗？
the founder of um chatbt/openai
um chatbt/openai 创始人
when he talks about a fast takeoff? I
他指的是快速起飞吗？我
don't know exactly what which what what
不知道具体是什么、什么、什么
which you're referring to but we're all
你指的是这个，但我们都是
talking about a point now that we call
现在我们来谈谈一个我们称之为……的观点。
the intelligence explosion. So, so there
情报爆炸。所以，就是这样。
is a moment in time where you have to
这是你必须经历的时刻
imagine that if AI now is better than
想象一下，如果现在的人工智能比现在更好……
97% of all code developers in the world
全球97%的代码开发人员
and soon we'll be able to look at its
很快我们就能一窥它的全貌了。
own code own algorithms by the way
顺便一提，代码和算法都是我自己写的。
they're becoming incredible
他们变得不可思议
mathematicians which wasn't the case
数学家们，但事实并非如此。
when we last met if they can develop
我们上次见面时，他们是否能够发展
improve their own code improve their own
改进他们自己的代码
algorithms improve their own uh uh you
算法会改进它们自己的……呃……你
know uh network architecture or whatever
懂网络架构之类的吗？
you can imagine that very quickly the
你可以想象，很快……
force applied to developing the next AI
为开发下一代人工智能所施加的力量
is not going to be a human brain
它不会是人脑
anymore. It's going to be a much smarter
不再是了。它将变得更加智能
brain and very quickly as humans like
大脑，而且速度非常快，就像人类一样
basically when when we ran the Google
基本上，当我们运营谷歌的时候
infrastructure when the machine said we
基础设施，当机器说我们
need another server or a proxy server in
需要另一台服务器或代理服务器
that place we followed. we we never
我们一路跟随的那个地方。我们从未
really you know wanted to to object or
你知道，你其实想反对或者
verify because you know the code would
验证一下，因为你知道代码会
probably know better because there are
或许更清楚这一点，因为……
billions of transactions an hour or a
每小时数十亿笔交易或
day and so very quickly those
一天，所以很快就……
self-evolving AIs will simply say I need
能够自我进化的AI会简单地说我需要
14 more servers here and we'll just you
这里还有14台服务器，我们这就给你。
know the team will just go ahead and do
我知道团队会继续前进。
it. I watched a video a couple of days
它。几天前我看了个视频。
ago where he Sam Alman effectively had
很久以前，他和萨姆·阿尔曼实际上已经……
changed his mind because in 2023 which
他改变了主意，因为在2023年，哪个年份？
is when we last met he said the aim was
上次见面时，他说目标是
for um a slow takeoff which is sort of
嗯，缓慢起飞有点像……
gradual deployment and open AI's 203
逐步部署和开放人工智能的203
2023 note says a slower takeoff is
2023年的一份说明指出，起飞速度会变慢。
easier to make safe and they prefer
更容易制造安全措施，他们也更喜欢
iterative rollouts society can adapt in
社会可以适应迭代式推广
&gt;&gt; they changed their mind and Sam Alman
他们改变了主意，萨姆·阿尔曼
said
说
He now thinks a fast takeoff is more
他现在认为快速起飞更有利
possible than he did a couple of years
比他几年前做的要有可能
ago on the order of a small number of
大约在少数人之前
years rather than a decade. Um, and it
是几年，而不是十年。嗯，而且
to define what we mean by a fast
为了定义我们所说的“快速”是什么意思。
takeoff, it's defined as when AI goes
起飞，它被定义为人工智能开始运行的时候。
from roughly human level to far beyond
从大致人类水平到远远超出人类水平
human very quickly, think months to a
人类反应非常快，几个月就能想到一个
few years, faster than governments,
几年之内，比政府的速度还要快。
companies, or society can adapt with
公司或社会可以适应
little warning, big power shifts, and
几乎没有预警，权力格局发生巨大变化，以及
hard to control. A slow takeoff, by
难以控制。缓慢起飞，
contrast, is where capabilities climb
对比之下，能力正是在此攀升。
gradually over many years with lots of
多年来逐渐地，做了很多
warning shots. Um, and the red flags for
鸣枪示警。嗯，还有一些危险信号
a fast takeoff is when AI can
快速起飞是指人工智能能够
self-improve, run autonomous research
自我提升，自主开展研究
and development and scale with massive
以及大规模的发展和规模
compute compounding gains which will
计算复利收益，这将
snowball fast. So, and I think from the
雪球效应迅速蔓延。所以，我认为从
video that I watched of Sam Orman
我观看的萨姆·奥曼的视频
recently, who again is the founder of
最近，谁又是创始人？
Open Air and HBT, he basically says, and
他基本上是这么说的：露天场地和HBT。
again I'm paraphrasing here. I will put
我这里又是转述。我会放
it on the screen. We have this community
屏幕上会显示出来。我们拥有这样一个社区
knows things so I'll write it on the
我知道一些事情，所以我会把它写下来。
screen. But he effectively said that
屏幕。但他实际上说的是
whoever gets to AGI first will have the
谁先掌握了通用人工智能（AGI），谁就拥有了优势。
technology
技术
&gt;&gt; to develop super intelligence
发展超级智能
&gt;&gt; where the AI can can rapidly increase
人工智能能够迅速增长的地方
its own intelligence and it will
它拥有自己的智能，而且它会
basically leave everyone else behind.
基本上把其他人都抛在后面。
&gt;&gt; Yes. Uh so that last bit is debatable
是的。嗯，最后一点还有待商榷。
but but let's just agree that uh so so
但是，我们姑且就此达成共识吧，嗯，就这样。
in in a live uh you know one of the
在现场，你知道其中一个
posts I I shared and got a lot of
我分享的帖子收到了很多回复
interest is I refer to the the altman as
我感兴趣的是我所说的奥特曼
a brand not as a human. Okay. So the
品牌不应被当作人来看待。好的。所以
altman is that uh persona of a
奥特曼是那个呃人格
California disruptive technologist that
加州颠覆性技术专家
disrespects everyone. Okay. and believes
不尊重所有人。好的。并相信
that disruption is good for humanity and
这种变革对人类有益，
believes that this is good for safety
认为这有利于安全。
and like everything else like we say war
就像我们说的其他一切战争一样。
is for democracy and freedom they say uh
他们说，这是为了民主和自由。
developing you know putting AI on the
开发过程中，你知道，将人工智能应用于……
open internet is good for everyone right
开放的互联网对每个人都有好处，对吧？
it allows us to learn from our mistakes
它使我们能够从错误中吸取教训。
that was Sam Alman's 2023 spiel and if
那是萨姆·阿尔曼2023年的竞选演说，如果
you recall at the time I was like this
你还记得当时我是这样的吗？
is the most dangerous you know one of
是你所知的最危险的之一
the clips that really went viral you so
那些真正爆红的视频片段你
you're you're so clever at finding the
你真聪明，很擅长找到……
right clips is when I said
正确的片段就是我说的
&gt;&gt; I didn't I didn't do the clipping mate
我没剪，伙计。
&gt;&gt; they're team teams remember the clip
他们是团队，记住这段视频
where I said we [__] up we always said
我说过我们搞砸了，我们总是这么说。
don't put them on the open internet
不要把它们放到公共互联网上
until we know what we're putting out in
直到我们知道我们要推出的是什么
the world I'm going to be saying that
我要说的是，
&gt;&gt; yeah we we we [__] up on putting it on
是的，我们搞砸了，把它放上去。
the open internet teaching it to to code
开放的互联网教会了它如何编程
and putting you know agents AI agents
以及将你知道的代理人工智能代理
prompting other AIs now AI agents
促使其他人工智能现在成为人工智能代理
prompting other AIs are leading to
促使其他人工智能走向
self-developing AIS and and The problem
自我发展的AIS以及问题
is, of course, we, you know, anyone who
当然，我们指的是任何人，你知道，任何人
has been on the inside of this knew that
一直身处其中的人都知道这一点
this was just a clever spiel made by a
这不过是某人精心设计的花言巧语罢了。
PR manager for Sam Alman to sit with his
山姆·阿尔曼的公关经理要和他坐在一起
dreamy eyes in front of Congress and
在国会大厦前，她眼神迷离，神采奕奕。
say, "We want you to regulate us." Now,
例如，“我们希望你们来监管我们。”现在，
they're saying, "We're unregulable."
他们说：“我们不受监管。”
Okay? And and when you really understand
好的？当你真正理解的时候
what's happening here, what's happening
这里发生了什么？到底发生了什么？
is it's so fast
速度太快了
that none of them has the choice to slow
他们中没有一个人可以选择放慢速度。
down. It's impossible. Neither China
向下。这不可能。中国既不
versus America or OpenAI versus Google.
与美国对抗，或者 OpenAI 与谷歌对抗。
the that the the only thing that I may
那是我唯一可能做的事
have may see happening that you you know
你可能已经看到过你知道的事情
that that may differ a little bit from
这可能与……略有不同
your statement is if one of them gets
你的说法是，如果他们中的一个得到
there first uh then they dominate for
他们先是占据主导地位，然后就占据了主导地位。
the rest of humanity that is probably
其余的人类可能
true if they get there first uh with
如果他们先到那里，那就对了。
within enough buffer. Okay. But the way
留有足够的缓冲空间。好的。但是方式
you look at Grock coming a week after
你看看格罗克一周后会来。
open AI, a week after uh you know
openAI，一周后，你知道的
Gemini, a week after Claude and then
双子座，在克劳德之后一周，然后
Claude comes again and then China
克劳德又来了，然后是中国
releases something and then Korea
发布一些东西，然后韩国
releases some something. It is so fast
释放出某种东西。速度真快
that we may get a few of them at the
我们或许能在某个时候得到其中一些
same time or a few months apart. Okay,
同时或相隔几个月。好的，
before one of them has enough power to
在其中一人拥有足够权力之前
become dominant. And that is a very
占据主导地位。那是一个非常
interesting scenario.
有趣的场景。
multiple AIs, all super intelligent.
多台人工智能系统，全部都非常智能。
&gt;&gt; It's funny, you know, I I I got asked
你知道，这很有趣，我被问到这个问题
yesterday, I was in I was in Belgium on
昨天，我在比利时。
stage. There was, I don't know, maybe
阶段。我不知道，也许吧。
4,000 people in the audience and a kid
现场有4000名观众和一个孩子
stood up and he was like, um, you've had
他站起来，然后说，嗯，你已经有了
a lot of conversations in the last year
过去一年里有很多对话
about AI. Like, why do you care? And I
关于人工智能。你为什么要在意？我
don't think people realize how,
别以为人们意识到这一点，
even though I've had so many
尽管我已经有很多次了
conversations on this podcast about AI,
本播客中关于人工智能的讨论
you
你
&gt;&gt; haven't made up your mind.
你还没拿定主意。
&gt;&gt; I I I have more questions than ever.
我比以往任何时候都有更多的问题。
&gt;&gt; I know. And it's and it doesn't seem
我知道。而且，它似乎并非如此。
that anyone can satiate.
任何人都能满足的。
&gt;&gt; Anyone that tells you they can predict
任何声称自己能预测的人
the future is arrogant.
未来是傲慢的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; It is. It's never moved so fast.
这是。它从未移动得如此之快。
&gt;&gt; It's nothing like nothing I've ever
这和我以前经历过的任何事情都截然不同。
seen. And you know, by the time that we
已阅。你知道，到那时我们
leave this conversation and I go to my
结束这个对话，我要去我的
computer, there's going to be some
电脑方面，会有一些问题。
incredible new technology or application
令人难以置信的新技术或应用
of AI that didn't exist when I woke up
我醒来时还不存在的人工智能
this morning. That creates probably
今晨。这很可能会造成影响。
another paradigm shift in my brain.
我的思维模式又一次发生了转变。
Also, you know, I people have different
而且，你知道，人们有不同的
opinions of Elon Musk and they're
埃隆·马斯克的观点是……
they're entitled to their own opinion,
他们有权发表自己的意见。
but the other day, only a couple of days
但就在前几天，仅仅过了几天
ago, he did a tweet where he said, "At
不久前，他发了一条推文，内容是：“在
times, AI existential dread is
时代变迁，人工智能带来的生存恐惧是
overwhelming." And on the same day, he
难以承受。” 就在同一天，他
tweeted, "I resisted AI for too long,
发推文说：“我抵制人工智能太久了”，
living in denial. Now it is game on."
活在否认之中。现在比赛正式开始了。
And he tagged his AI companies. I don't
他还给他的AI公司贴上了标签。我不
know what to make of I don't know what
不知道该如何理解，我不知道该如何解释
to make of those tweets. I don't know.
将这些推文转化为现实。我不知道。
And you know, I
你知道，我
I try really hard to figure out if
我努力想弄清楚是否
someone like Sam Wman has the best
像萨姆·沃曼这样的人拥有最好的
interests of society at heart.
以社会利益为重。
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; Or if these people are just like
或者如果这些人就像
&gt;&gt; I'm saying that publicly. No.
我公开这么说。不。
As a matter of fact, so I know Sundur
事实上，所以我认识桑杜尔。
Pachai. I work CEO of Alphabet, Google's
帕猜。我是谷歌母公司Alphabet的首席执行官。
parent company. an amazing human being
母公司。一位了不起的人
on in all honesty. I know Dennis Hassab
说实话。我认识丹尼斯·哈萨布
is amazing human being. Okay. Uh you
真是个了不起的人。好的。呃，你
know these are are ethical incredible uh
知道这些都是合乎道德的，令人难以置信。
humans at heart. They have no choice.
心系人类。他们别无选择。
Uh Sund by law
呃，根据法律
is uh demanded to take care of his his
被要求照顾他的
shareholder value. That's that is his
股东价值。那就是他的
job.
工作。
&gt;&gt; But Sund you said you know him. You used
但是桑德，你说你认识他。你使用
to work at Google.
在谷歌工作。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. He's not going to do anything that
是的。他不会做任何那样的事。
he thinks is going to harm humanity.
他认为这将对人类造成危害。
&gt;&gt; But if if he does not continue to
但如果他不继续下去
advance AI, that by definition uh uh uh
先进的人工智能，顾名思义，呃呃呃
contradicts his responsibility as the
这与他作为……的职责相矛盾
CEO of a publicly traded company, he is
他是一家上市公司的首席执行官。
liable by law to continue to advance the
依法有义务继续推进
agenda. There's absolutely no doubt
议程。这一点毋庸置疑。
about it. Now, so but but he's a good
关于它。现在，但是，但是他是个好人
person at heart. Deis is a good person
心地善良。戴斯是个好人
at heart. So they're trying so hard to
心里。所以他们才如此努力地尝试
make it safe. Okay? As much as they can.
确保安全。好的？尽其所能。
Reality however is the the the disruptor
然而，现实情况是，颠覆者
the altman as a brand doesn't care that
作为品牌的奥特曼并不在意这一点
much.
很多。
&gt;&gt; How do you know that?
你怎么知道的？
&gt;&gt; In reality the disruptor is someone that
实际上，颠覆者是这样的人：
comes in with the objective of I don't
带着“我不……”的目的而来
like the status quo. I have a different
就像维持现状一样。我有不同的
approach. And that different approach if
方法。而这种不同的方法
you just look at the story was we are a
你看看这个故事，我们是一个
nonforprofit that is funded mostly by
非营利组织，其资金主要来自
Elon Musk money. It's not entirely by
埃隆·马斯克的钱。并非完全如此
Elon Musk money. So context for people
埃隆·马斯克的钱。所以，这能给人们提供背景信息。
that might not understand Open AI. The
可能不了解 OpenAI 的人。这
reason I always give context is funnily
我总是给出背景信息的原因很有趣
enough I I think I told you this last
够了，我想我上次已经跟你说过这件事了。
time. I went to a prison where they play
时间。我去了一所监狱，他们在那里玩游戏
the D of CEO.
CEO的D。
&gt;&gt; No way.
决不。
&gt;&gt; So they play the D of CO and I think
所以他们扮演的是CO的D，我认为
it's 50 prisons in the UK to young
英国有50所监狱关押年轻人。
offenders
罪犯
&gt;&gt; and no violence there.
那里没有暴力事件发生。
&gt;&gt; Well, I don't know. I can't I can't I
嗯，我不知道。我不能，我不能，我
can't tell you whether violence has gone
我无法告诉你暴力是否已经结束。
up or down. But I was in the cell with
向上或向下。但我当时和……关在同一个牢房里
one of the prisoners, a young a young
其中一个囚犯，一个年轻人
black guy, and I was in his cell for for
那是一个黑人，我当时在他的牢房里待了一段时间。
a little while. I was reading through
稍等片刻。我正在阅读
his business plan, etc. And I said, "You
他的商业计划等等。我说：“你
know what? You need to listen to this
知道什么？你需要听听这个
conversation that I did with Mo Gordat."
我和莫·戈尔达特的一次谈话。
So I he has a little screen in his cell.
所以，他的牢房里有一个小屏幕。
So I pulled it up, you know, our first
所以我把它翻了出来，你知道，我们的第一个
conversation. I said, "You should listen
对话。我说：“你应该听着
to that one." And he said to me, he
给那个人。”然后他对我说，他
said, "I can't listen to that one cuz
他说：“我听不下去那个，因为……”
you guys use big words."
你们都喜欢用一些生僻词。
&gt;&gt; So ever since that day, which was about
所以从那天起，大约
&gt;&gt; I noticed that about days four years
我注意到大约四年前
ago, sorry.
抱歉，很久以前了。
&gt;&gt; I've always whenever I hear a big word,
每当我听到一个生僻词时，
I think about this kid.
我一直在想这个孩子。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And I say like give context. So even
我的意思是，要提供背景信息。所以即使
with the you're about to explain what
你即将解释什么
Open AI is, I know he won't know what
OpenAI 是，我知道他不会知道什么
Open AI's origin story was. That's why
OpenAI 的起源故事是这样的。这就是原因
I'm
我是
&gt;&gt; I think that's a wonderful practice in
我认为这是一个非常好的做法。
general. By the way, even, you know,
一般的。顺便说一句，甚至，你知道，
being a non native English speaker,
作为一名非英语母语者，
&gt;&gt; you'll be amazed how often a word is
你会惊讶于一个词出现的频率有多高
said to me and I I'm like, yeah, don't
他跟我说，我就说，是啊，别这样。
know what that means.
明白这意味着什么。
&gt;&gt; So, like I've actually never said this
所以，就像我其实从来没说过这话一样
publicly before, but I now see it as my
以前是公开的，但现在我把它看作是我的
responsibility to be to to keep the draw
责任在于保持平局
the drawbridge
吊桥
to accessibility of these conversations
便于这些对话
down for him. So, whenever I whenever
为他倒下。所以，每当我每当
there's a word that at some point in my
有一个词，在我的某个时刻
life I didn't know what it meant,
我不知道生命意味着什么，
&gt;&gt; I will go back. I was like, what does
我会回去的。我当时就想，这是什么意思？
that mean? I think that I've noticed
那是什么意思？我想我注意到了
that in the you know more and more in
你知道的越来越多
your podcast and I really appreciate and
你的播客我非常喜欢。
we also show it on the screen sometimes.
我们有时也会在屏幕上显示它。
&gt;&gt; I I think that's wonderful. I mean the
我觉得这太棒了。我的意思是……
the the origin story of open AI is as
OpenAI 的起源故事是这样的
the name suggests it's open source. It's
顾名思义，它是开源的。它是
for the public good. It was an in you
为了公众利益。这是你身上的某种特质
know intended in Elon Musk's words to
用埃隆·马斯克的话来说，就是知道其意图。
save the world from the dangers of AI
拯救世界，免受人工智能的威胁
right so they were doing research on
对，他们当时正在做关于……的研究。
that and then you know there was the
然后你知道，还有……
disagreement between Sam Alman and and
Sam Alman 和
Elon somehow Elon ends up being out of
不知何故，埃隆最终还是退出了。
uh of uh of open AI. I think there was a
呃，开放人工智能的呃。我认为曾经有过
moment in time where he tried to take it
他试图拿下它的那一刻
back and you know the board rejected it
回去之后，你知道董事会否决了它。
or some something like that. most of the
或者类似的事情。大部分
uh top um safety engineers, the top
呃，顶级安全工程师，顶级
technical teams in open AI left in 2023
OpenAI 的技术团队将于 2​​023 年离职。
2024 openly saying we're not concerned
2024年公开表示我们并不担心
with safety anymore. It moves from being
安全问题已经不再存在。它从
a nonforprofit to being one of the most
从一家非营利组织到最……
valued companies in the world. There are
全球最具价值的公司。有
billions of dollars at stake, right? And
事关数十亿美元，对吧？和
if you if you tell me that Sam Altman is
如果你告诉我萨姆·奥特曼是
out there trying to help humanity, let's
既然我们都在努力帮助人类，那就让我们一起努力吧。
let's suggest to him and say, "Hey, do
我们不妨建议他说：“嘿，这样做吧。”
you want to do that for free? We'll pay
你想免费做这件事吗？我们会付钱
you a very good salary, but you don't
你的薪水很高，但你没有
have stocks in this. Saving humanity
持有该公司的股票。拯救人类
doesn't come at the billion dollar
并非价值十亿美元
valuation or of course now tens of
估值，或者当然现在是数十
billions or hundreds of billions." And
数十亿，甚至数千亿。”
and and see truly that is when you know
真正明白这一点，就是当你明白的时候。
that someone is doing it for the good of
有人这样做是为了……的利益
humanity. Now the the capitalist system
人类。现在是资本主义制度
we've built is not built for the good of
我们所建造的并非为了造福于……
humanity. It's built for the good of the
人类。它是为了造福人类而建立的。
capitalist.
资本家。
&gt;&gt; Well, he might say that releasing the
他可能会说，释放
model publicly, open sourcing it is too
公开模型，开源也太过了。
risky
风险
because then bad actors around the world
因为那样的话，世界各地的坏人就会出现。
would have access to that technology. So
将有机会接触到这项技术。所以
he might say that closing open AI in
他可能会说，关闭 OpenAI
terms of not making it publicly viewable
不公开显示的条款
is the right thing to do for safety. We
为了安全起见，这样做是正确的。我们
go back to gullible cheer leaders,
回到那些容易上当受骗的啦啦队员身上去吧。
right? One of the interesting tricks is
正确的？其中一个有趣的技巧是
of lying in our world is everyone will
在我们这个世界里，说谎是每个人都会遇到的。
say what helps their agenda. Follow the
说些对他们的计划有帮助的话。跟随
money. Okay, you follow the money and
钱。好吧，你就跟着钱走。
you find that you know at a point in
你会发现，在某个时刻，你知道
time Samman himself was saying it's open
萨曼本人也说过，现在是开放的。
AI. Okay, my benefit at the time is to
人工智能。好的，我当时的利益是
give it to the world so that the world
把它交给世界，让世界……
looks at it. They know the code if there
看看它。他们知道密码（如果有的话）。
is if there are any bugs and so on. True
比如是否存在任何漏洞等等。真的
statement. Also a true statement is if I
陈述。还有一个正确的说法是如果我
put it out there in the world, a
把它公之于众，一个
criminal might take that model and build
犯罪分子可能会借鉴这种模式并加以利用。
something that's against humanity as a
某种有悖于人性的东西
result. Also true statement. Capitalists
结果。这句话也正确。资本家
will choose which one of the truths to
会选择哪一个真相
say, right? Based on which part of the
比如说，对吧？基于哪一部分
agenda, which part of their life today
议程，他们今天生活的哪一部分
they want to serve, right? Someone will
他们想为人民服务，对吗？有人会
say, uh, you know, do I do you want me
呃，你知道，我想要我吗？
to be controversial?
制造争议？
Let's not go there. But if we go back to
我们还是别谈这个了。但如果我们回到
war, I'll give you 400 slogans.
战争，我给你400条口号。
400 slogans that we all hear that change
400条我们都听过的改变世界的口号
based on the day and the army and the
根据当天情况、军队情况以及
location and the they're all slogans.
地点，而且它们都是口号。
None of them is true. You want to know
这些说法都不属实。你想知道
the truth. You follow the money, not
真相。你要追随资金的流向，而不是
what the person is saying, but ask
听清对方说的话，但要问
yourself why is the person saying that?
你想知道这个人为什么会这么说？
What's in it for the person speaking?
说话的人能从中得到什么好处？
&gt;&gt; And what do you think's in it for Chachi
你觉得查奇能从中得到什么好处？
Samman? hundreds of billions of dollars
萨曼？数千亿美元
of of of valuation.
估值。
&gt;&gt; And do you think it's that power?
你认为这就是力量吗？
&gt;&gt; The ego of being the person that
成为那个人的自我
invented AGI, the position of power that
发明了通用人工智能（AGI），获得了权力地位。
this gives you, the meetings with all of
这让你有机会与所有人会面。
the heads of states, the admiration that
国家元首们，以及由此而来的钦佩之情
gets it, it is intoxicating
明白了，这令人陶醉。
&gt;&gt; 100%
100%
100%.
100%。
Okay. And and the real question, this is
好的。而真正的问题是……
a question I ask everyone. Did you see
我会问每个人这个问题。你有没有看到
you didn't you're every time I ask you
你没有，每次我问你的时候你都是这样
you say you didn't. Did you see the
你说你没有。你看到了吗？
movie Elysium?
电影《极乐空间》？
&gt;&gt; No. You'd be surprised how little movie
不。你会惊讶于电影的少得可怜。
watching I do. You'd be shocked.
我一直在看。你会大吃一惊的。
&gt;&gt; There are some movies that are very
有些电影非常
interesting. I use them to to create an
有趣的。我用它们来创建一个
emotional attachment to a story that you
你对一个故事的情感依恋
haven't seen yet because you may have
还没看到，因为你可能已经
seen it in a movie. Okay. Elissium is a
在电影里见过。好的。 Elissium 是一个
is a society where the elites are living
这是一个精英阶层居住的社会。
on the moon. Okay. They don't need
在月球上。好的。他们不需要
peasants to do the work anymore and
农民不再从事这项工作了
everyone else is living down here. Okay.
其他人都住在这里。好的。
You have to imagine that if again game
你必须想象一下，如果再次玩游戏的话。
theory you have to im you know picture
理论你必须……你知道图片
something to infinity to its extreme and
某种东西达到无穷大，达到其极端状态，并且
see where it goes and the extreme of a
看看它会走向何方，以及它的极端情况
world where all manufactured is done
一个所有制造业都已完成的世界
manufacturing is done by machines
制造是由机器完成的。
where all decisions are made by machines
所有决策均由机器做出。
and those machines are owned by a few
而这些机器都归少数人所有。
is not an economy similar to the to
并非类似于……的经济体
today to the to today's economy
当今经济
that today's economy is an economy of
当今的经济是一种……的经济
consumerism and and product and
消费主义和产品
production. You know, it's the it's the
生产。你知道，就是这个，就是这个
in in alive I call it the invention of
在活着的时候，我称之为发明
more. The invention of more is that post
更多的。更多发明的前提是……
World War II as the factories were
二战期间，工厂……
rolling out things and prosperity was
推出各种产品和繁荣是
happening everywhere in America. There
这种情况在美国各地都在发生。那里
was a time where every family had enough
那是一个每个家庭都衣食无忧的时代。
of everything.
一切。
&gt;&gt; But for the capitalist to continue to be
但对于资本家而言，继续存在下去……
profitable, they needed to convince you
为了盈利，他们需要说服你
that what you had was not enough. either
你所拥有的还不够。任何一个
by making it obsolete like fashion or
通过使其像时尚一样过时，或者
like you know a new shape of a car or
比如你知道一种新型汽车的形状，或者
whatever or by convincing you that there
不管怎样，或者通过说服你相信这一点
are more things in life that you need so
生活中还有更多你需要的东西。
that you become complete without those
没有它们，你就完整了
things you don't and and that invention
你不了解的事情以及那项发明
of more gets us to where we are today an
更多的资源让我们走到今天。
economy that's based on production
以生产为基础的经济
consumed and if you look at the US
消费情况，如果你看看美国的情况。
economy today 62% of the US economy GDP
当今经济占美国经济GDP的62%。
is consumption it's not production okay
消费就是消费，而不是生产，这样可以吗？
Now, this requires that the consumers
现在，这就要求消费者
have enough purchasing power to to buy
有足够的购买力去购买
what is produced. And I believe that
生产了什么。而且我相信
this will be an economy that will take
这将是一个需要……的经济体
us hopefully in the next 10, 15, 20
希望在未来10、15、20年内我们能够实现这一目标。
years and forever. But that's not
年复一年，直到永远。但事实并非如此
guaranteed. Why? Because on one side if
保证。为什么？因为在一方面如果
UBI replaces purchasing power. So if
全民基本收入取代了购买力。所以如果
people have to get an income from the
人们必须从中获得收入
government which is basically taxes
政府，也就是税收。
collected from those using AI and robots
数据来自使用人工智能和机器人的用户
to to make things
制造东西
the then the the mindset of capitalism
当时的资本主义思维
labor arbitrage means those people are
劳动力套利意味着这些人是
not producing anything and they're
他们什么都没生产，而且
costing me money. Why don't we pay them
这让我损失了钱。为什么我们不付钱给他们呢？
less and less and maybe even not pay
越来越少，甚至可能不付钱。
them at all? And that becomes illissium
他们到底是谁？于是它就变成了伊利西姆。
where you basically say, you know, we
你基本上就是说，你知道，我们
sit somewhere protected from everyone.
找个僻静的地方坐下，避开所有人。
We have the machines do all of our work
我们所有的工作都由机器完成。
and those need to worry about
而那些需要担心的人
themselves. We're not going to pay them
他们自己。我们不会付钱给他们。
UBI anymore, right? And and you have to
全民基本收入制度已经过时了吗？而且你必须
imagine this idea of UBI assumes this
想象一下，全民基本收入的这种理念是基于以下假设的：
very democratic caring society.
非常民主、充满关爱的社会。
UBI in itself is communism.
全民基本收入本身就是共产主义。
Think of the ideology between at least
想想至少两者之间的意识形态差异
socialism. The ideology of giving
社会主义。给予的意识形态
everyone what they need. That's not the
每个人都得到了他们需要的东西。那不是……
capitalist
资本家
democratic society that the west
西方民主社会
advocates. So those transitions are
倡导者。所以这些过渡是
massive in magnitude.
规模巨大。
And for those transitions to happen, I
而要实现这些转变，我
believe the right thing to do when the
相信在什么情况下做正确的事
cost of producing everything is almost
所有产品的生产成本几乎
zero because of AI and robots.
因为人工智能和机器人，零增长。
because the cost of harvesting energy
因为收集能量的成本很高
should actually tend to zero once we get
一旦我们得到，实际上应该趋近于零。
more intelligent to harvest the energy
更智能地收集能量
out of thin air. Then a possible
凭空。然后，一种可能性
scenario and and I believe a scenario
场景，而且我相信一个场景
that AI will eventually do in the utopia
人工智能最终会在乌托邦中做到这一点
is yeah anyone can get anything they
是的，任何人都能得到任何东西。
want. Don't over consume. We're not
想。不要过量食用。我们不是
going to abuse the the planet resources
滥用地球资源
but it costs nothing. So like the old
但它是免费的。就像以前的
days where we were hunter gatherers, you
在我们还是狩猎采集者的日子里，你
would, you know, forge for some berries
你知道，为了弄些浆果而伪装。
and you'll find them ready in in nature.
你会发现它们在大自然中随处可见。
Okay, we can in 10 years time, 12 years
好的，我们可以在10年后、12年后实现。
time build a society where you can forge
是时候建立一个可以锻造的社会了
for an iPhone in nature. It will be made
在自然环境中使用 iPhone。它将被制造出来
out of thin air. Nanopysics will allow
凭空。纳米物理学将允许
you to do that. Okay? But the challenge,
你去做这件事。好的？但挑战在于，
believe it or not, is not tech. The
信不信由你，这不是技术。这
challenge is a mindset. Because the
挑战是一种心态。因为
elite, why would they give you that for
精英，他们为什么要给你这个？
free? Okay. And the system would morph
自由的？好的。而该系统将会发生变化。
into, no, no, hold on. We will make more
进入，不，不，等等。我们将生产更多
money. We will be bigger capitalists. We
钱。我们将成为更大的资本家。我们
will feed our ego and hunger for power
这会满足我们的自负和对权力的渴望。
more and more. And for them, give them
越来越多。而对于他们，请给予他们
UBI and then 3 weeks later give them
先发放全民基本收入，三周后再发放给他们。
less UBI.
减少全民基本收入。
&gt;&gt; Aren't there going to be lots of new
难道不会有很多新的吗？
jobs created though? Because when we
但确实创造了就业机会吗？因为当我们
think about the other revolutions over
想想其他的革命
time, whether it was the industrial
时间，无论是工业时代
revolution or other sort of big
革命或其他类型的重大事件
technological revolutions,
技术革命，
&gt;&gt; in the moment we forecasted that
在我们预测的那一刻
everyone was going to lose their jobs,
所有人都要失业了，
&gt;&gt; but we couldn't see all the new jobs
但我们无法看到所有的新工作岗位。
that were being created
正在创建的
&gt;&gt; because the the the machines
因为机器
replaced the human strength at a point
在某个时刻，人类的力量被取代了。
in time. And very few places in the west
及时。西部地区也很少有这样的地方。
today will have a worker carry things on
今天会有一名工人搬运物品。
their back and carry it upstairs. The
背起它，把它搬到楼上。这
machine does that work. Correct.
机器可以完成这项工作。正确的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Uh similarly
嗯，类似地
AI is going to replace the brain of a
人工智能将会取代人类的大脑。
human. And when the west in its
人类。当西方在其
interesting uh virtual colonies that I
有趣的虚拟殖民地
call it uh basically outsourced all
可以称之为基本上全部外包。
labor to the to the developing nations.
向发展中国家提供劳动力。
What the West publicly said at the time
当时西方公开的说法
is we're we're going to be a services
我们将会提供服务
economy. We we're we're not interested
经济。我们对此不感兴趣。
in making things and stitching things
在制作物品和缝纫物品方面
and so on. Let the Indians and Chinese
等等。让印度人和中国人
and you know Bengali and Vietnamese do
你知道孟加拉人和越南人会这样做
that. We're going to do more refined
那。我们将进行更精细的加工。
jobs. Knowledge workers. We're going to
工作。知识工作者。我们将要
call them. Knowledge workers are people
给他们打电话。知识工作者是人
who work with information and click on a
那些处理信息并点击的人
keyboard and move a mouse and you know
敲击键盘，移动鼠标，你就知道了。
sit in meetings and all we produce in
参加会议，以及我们生产的所有东西
the western societies is what words
西方社会是什么词？
right or designs maybe sometimes but
正确的设计或许有时是这样，但
everything we produce can be produced by
我们生产的所有东西都可以由……生产。
an AI.
人工智能。
So if I give you an AI tomorrow h where
所以如果我明天给你一个人工智能，h在哪里
I give you a piece of land, I give the
我给你一块土地，我给你
AI a piece of land and I say here are
人工智能获得了一块土地，我说这里有
the parameters of my land. Here is its
我的土地范围。这是它的
location on Google maps. Design an
在谷歌地图上的位置。设计一个
architecturally sound villa for me. I
对我来说，这是一栋建筑风格合理的别墅。我
care about a lot of light and I need
我非常在意光线，而且我需要
three bedrooms. I want my bathrooms to
三间卧室。我希望我的浴室
be in white marble, whatever. And the AI
用白色大理石做装饰也行。以及人工智能
produces it like that. How often will
它就是这样产生的。多久一次？
you go to an to an architect and say
你去找一位建筑师，然后说
right so what will the architect do the
那么，建筑师会怎么做呢？
best of the best of the architects will
最优秀的建筑师将
either use AI to produce that or you
要么用人工智能来生成，要么你
will consult with them and say hey you
会和他们商量，然后说：嘿，你
know I've seen this and they'll say it's
我知道我见过这种情况，他们会说这是
really pretty but it wouldn't feel right
真的很漂亮，但感觉不太合适。
for the person that you are yeah those
对于你这样的人，是的，那些
jobs will remain but how many of them
工作岗位会保留，但会有多少呢？
will remain
将继续
how how often do you think uh how many
你觉得多久一次，呃，有多少次？
more years. Do you think I will be able
再过几年。你认为我能做到吗？
to create a book that is smarter than
创作一本比……更睿智的书
AI?
人工智能？
Not many. I will still be able to
不多。我仍然可以
connect to a human. You're not going to
与人建立联系。你不会
hug an AI when you meet them like you
当你遇到人工智能时，像你一样拥抱它。
hug me, right? But that's not enough of
抱抱我，好吗？但这还不够。
a job.
一份工作。
So why do I say that? Remember I asked
那我为什么这么说呢？记得我问过吗？
you at the beginning of the podcast to
播客开始时的你
remind me of solutions. Why do I say
提醒我一些解决方案。我为什么这么说
that? Because there are ideological
那？因为存在意识形态
shifts and and concrete actions that
转变和具体行动
need to be taken by governments today
各国政府今天需要采取的措施
rather than waiting until COVID is
而不是等到新冠疫情爆发后再采取行动
already everywhere and then locking
到处都是，然后就锁定了
everyone down. Governments could have
所有人都倒下了。政府可能拥有
reacted before the first patient or at
在首例患者之前或当时做出反应
least at patient zero or at least at
至少在零号病人身上，或者至少在
patient 50. They didn't. H what I'm
50号病人。他们没有。我是什么
trying to say is there is no doubt that
我想表达的是，毫无疑问
lots of jobs will be lost. There's no
很多人将失去工作岗位。没有
doubt that there will be sectors of
怀疑是否会有某些领域
society where 10 20 30 40 50% of all
社会中，10%、20%、30%、40%、50%的人
developers, all software uh you know all
开发人员，所有软件，呃，你知道的
graphic designers, all um uh uh u online
平面设计师，所有在线的
marketers, all all all assistances
营销人员，所有所有所有协助
are going to be out of a job. So are we
他们即将失业。所以，我们也是。
prepared as a society to do that? Can we
社会是否做好了准备？我们能
tell our governments there is an
告诉我们的政府，存在着
ideological shift? This is very close to
意识形态转变？这非常接近
social socialism and and communism.
社会社会主义和共产主义。
Okay. And are we ready from a budget
好的。我们是否已做好预算准备？
point of view instead of spending a a
从这个角度来看，而不是花费时间
trillion dollars a year on on arms and
每年在武器和武器上的支出高达万亿美元
and explosives and you know autonomous
还有炸药，你知道，还有自主系统
weapons that will oppress people because
会压迫人民的武器
we can't feed them? Can we please shift
我们不能喂饱它们吗？我们能换个地方吗？
that? I did those numbers. Huh. Uh again
那？我算出了这些数字。嗯。呃，又来了。
I I go back to military spending because
我之所以回到军事开支问题，是因为
it's all around us. 2.71 trillion. 2.4
它无处不在。 2.71万亿。 2.4
to2.7 is the estimate of 2024. how much
预计到2024年将达到2.7。多少
money we're spending on military
我们花在军事上的钱
&gt;&gt; on Yeah. on military equipment on things
是的。关于军事装备的物品
that we're going to explode into smoke
我们将化为乌有。
and death. Extreme poverty worldwide.
以及死亡。全球极端贫困问题。
Extreme poverty is people that are below
极端贫困是指低于以下标准的人口
the poverty line. Extreme poverty
贫困线。极端贫困
everywhere in the world could end for 10
世界各地都可能结束10年。
to 12% of that budget. So if we replace
占该预算的 12%。所以如果我们替换
our military spending 10% of that to go
我们的军方将其中10%用于……
to people who are in extreme poverty,
对于生活在极端贫困中的人们来说，
nobody will be poor in the world. Okay.
世界上将不再有穷人。好的。
You can end uh world hunger for less
你可以用更少的钱消除世界饥饿。
than 4%. Nobody would be hungry in the
低于 4%。没有人会挨饿。
world. You know, if you take uh again 10
世界。你知道，如果你再拿10
to 12% universal healthcare, every human
12% 的人口享有全民医疗保健，人人平等
being on the planet would have free
身处这个星球上本应是自由的。
healthcare for 10 to 12% on what we're
医疗保健费用占我们所做费用的 10% 到 12%。
spending on war. Now, why why do I say
战争开支。那么，我为什么要说
this when we're talking about AI?
我们现在谈论的是人工智能吗？
Because that's a simple decision. If we
因为这是一个简单的决定。如果我们
stop fighting
停止战斗
because money itself does not have the
因为金钱本身并不具备
same meaning anymore because the
不再具有相同的含义，因为
economics of money is going to change
货币经济学即将发生变化。
because the entire meaning of capitalism
因为资本主义的全部意义就在于此。
is ending because there is no more need
结束是因为不再需要了。
for labor arbitrage because AI is doing
因为人工智能正在实现劳动力套利。
everything
一切
just with the $2.4 trillion we save in
仅我们节省的2.4万亿美元
explosives every year in arms and
每年武器和爆炸物的数量都在增加。
weapons just for that universal
仅用于通用武器
healthcare and extreme poverty. You
医疗保健和极端贫困。你
could actually one of the calculations
实际上可能是其中一项计算
is you could end climate or combat
你可以结束气候或对抗
climate climate change meaningfully for
气候变化对气候具有重要意义
100% of the military budget.
军费预算的100%。
&gt;&gt; But I I'm not even sure it's really
但我甚至不确定它是否真的如此
about the money. I think money is a
关于钱的事。我认为金钱是一种
measurement stick of power. Right.
力量的测量标尺。正确的。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. It's printed on demand.
确切地。它是按需印刷的。
&gt;&gt; So even in a world where we have super
所以即使在我们拥有超级大国的世界里
intelligence and money is no longer a
智力和金钱不再是……
problem.
问题。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; I still think
我仍然认为
power is going to be
权力将会是
insatiable for so many people. So there
对很多人来说，这简直是无法满足的。所以就是这样。
will still be war because you know
战争依然会继续，因为你知道
&gt;&gt; there will be in my view
在我看来，会有的。
&gt;&gt; the strongest I want the strongest AI. I
我想要最强大的人工智能。我
don't want my
不想让我
&gt;&gt; and I don't and I don't want you know
我不知道，我也不想让你知道。
what Harry Henry Kissinger called them
哈里·亨利·基辛格称他们
the eaters.
食客们。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
Brutal as that sounds.
听起来很残酷。
&gt;&gt; What is that? The people at the bottom
那是什么？底层的人们
of the socioeconomic
社会经济
&gt;&gt; that don't produce but consume.
那些不生产只消费的群体。
So if you had a Henry Kissinger at the
所以，如果你当时有一位亨利·基辛格……
at the helm and we have so many of them,
掌舵人很多，我们有很多这样的人。
what would they think like why why
他们会怎么想？为什么？
prominent military figure in the US
美国一位杰出的军事人物
history? Uh you know what why would we
历史？呃，你知道吗？我们为什么要这么做？
feed 350 million Americans America will
美国将养活3.5亿美国人
think but more interestingly why do we
思考，但更有趣的是，为什么我们会……
even care about Bangladesh anymore if we
如果我们还关心孟加拉国，那我们该怎么办？
can't make our textiles there or we
我们无法在那里生产纺织品，否则我们将无法生产。
don't want to make our textile there. Do
我们不想在那里生产纺织品。做
you you know I imagine throughout human
你知道，我设想整个人类
history if we had podcasts conversations
如果我们有播客对话，历史会是什么样子？
would would have been warning of a
这会发出警告
dystopia around the corner. You know
反乌托邦时代即将到来。你知道
when they heard of technology and the
当他们听说科技和
internet they would have said oh we're
他们会在互联网上说，哦，我们是
finished and when the the tractor came
完工后，拖拉机就来了。
along they would have said oh god we're
他们本来会说，哦，天哪，我们
finished because we're not going to be
结束了，因为我们不会……
able to farm anymore. So is this not
已经无法再务农了。所以这不是吗？
just another one of those moments where
又是一个这样的时刻：
we couldn't see around the corner so we
我们看不到拐角处的情况，所以我们
we forecasted unfortunate things. You
我们预言了不幸的事情。你
could be. I I am I'm begging that I'm
有可能。我，我是，我恳求我
wrong. Okay. I'm just asking if there
错误的。好的。我只是想问问是否有
are scenarios that you think that can
你认为可能出现的情况
provide that. You know, uh uh Mustafa
提供这一点。你知道，呃，穆斯塔法
Sulleman in in uh you hosted him here. I
苏莱曼，呃，你在这里接待了他。我
did. Yeah. He was in the coming wave.
做过。是的。他正处于即将到来的浪潮之中。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And he speaks about uh about pessimism
他谈到了悲观主义。
aversion.
厌恶。
Okay. that all of us people who are
好的。我们所有人都是
supposed to be in technology and
应该从事科技行业
business and so on, we're always
在商业等方面，我们总是
supposed to, you know, stand on stage
应该，你知道，站在舞台上
and say the future's going to be
并说未来将会是
amazing. You know, this technology I'm
惊人的。你知道，我这项技术
building is going to make everything
建筑将成就一切
better. One of my posts in life was
更好的。我人生中的一篇帖子是
called the broken promises. How often
称之为破碎的承诺。多常
did that happen?
那件事真的发生过吗？
&gt;&gt; Okay. How often did social media connect
好的。社交媒体连接的频率如何
us? And how many and how often did it
我们？有多少次？发生的频率如何？
make us more lonely? How how often did
会让我们更孤独吗？多久一次？
mobile phones make us work less? That
手机让我们工作时间减少了吗？那
was the promise. That was the promise.
这是承诺。那是承诺。
The promise. The early ads of Nokia were
承诺。诺基亚早期的广告是
people at parties. Is that your
聚会上的人们。那是你的吗？
experience of mobile phones? And and I
你有使用手机的经验吗？而且我
think the whole idea is we should hope
我认为整个理念就是我们应该抱有希望
there will be other roles for humanity.
人类还将扮演其他角色。
By the way, those roles would resemble
顺便说一句，这些角色类似于
the times where we were hunter
我们当猎人的那些日子
gatherers, just a lot more technology
采集者，只是技术更先进一些。
and a lot more safety.
而且安全性更高。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, this is this sounds good.
好的。听起来不错。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; this is exciting. So, I'm gonna I'm
这太令人兴奋了。所以，我要……
gonna get to go outside more, be with my
以后能多出去走走，和我的……
friends more,
多交朋友，
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; Fantastic.
极好的。
&gt;&gt; And do absolutely nothing.
什么都不要做。
&gt;&gt; Well, that doesn't sound fantastic.
嗯，听起来不太妙。
&gt;&gt; No, it does. Do be forced to do
不，确实如此。被迫去做
absolutely nothing. For some people,
什么都没有。对某些人来说，
it's amazing. For you and I, we're going
太棒了。你和我，我们要去
to find the little carpentry project and
找到那个小型木工项目
just do something.
做点什么就行了。
&gt;&gt; Speak for yourself. I'm still People are
请你仅代表你自己发言。我仍然是人们
still going to tune in.
我还是会收看的。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Correct. Yeah. But what? And people are
正确的。是的。但是什么？而人们是
going to to tune in.
准备收听。
&gt;&gt; Do you think they will? I'm not I'm not
你认为他们会吗？我不是，我不是
I'm not convinced they will. And for for
我并不确信他们会这样做。而对于
as long
只要
&gt;&gt; will you guys tune in? Are you guys
你们会收看吗？你们是吗？
still going to tune in?
还会继续收看吗？
&gt;&gt; I can let them answer. I believe for as
我可以让他们回答。我相信，作为
long as you make their life enriched,
只要你让他们的生活更加丰富多彩，
&gt;&gt; but can an AI do that better
但人工智能能做得更好吗？
&gt;&gt; without the human connection?
如果没有人与人之间的联系？
&gt;&gt; Comment below. Are you going to listen
请在下方留言。你打算听吗？
to an AI or the Davosio? Let me know in
是人工智能还是达沃斯？请告诉我。
the comment section below.
请在下方评论区留言。
&gt;&gt; Remember, as incredibly intelligent as
记住，尽管他非常聪明
you are, Steve, uh there will be a
你是，史蒂夫，呃，会有一个
moment in time where you're going to
你即将前往的那一刻
sound really dumb compared to an AI. and
与人工智能相比，这听起来真的很笨。和
and and I will sound completely dumb.
而且我听起来会很愚蠢。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah.
是的。是的。
&gt;&gt; The the depth the depth of analysis
分析的深度
and and gold nuggets. I mean, can you
还有金块。我的意思是，你能……
imagine two super intelligences deciding
想象一下两个超级智能体决定
to get together and explain um string
聚在一起解释一下字符串
theory to us?
对我们来说，这算什么理论？
They'll do better than any physic
他们会比任何物理学家都做得更好。
physicist in the world because they
世界上最好的物理学家，因为他们
possess the physics knowledge and they
他们具备物理知识，而且
also pro possess social and language
此外，专业人士还具备社交和语言能力
knowledge that most deep physicists
大多数资深物理学家所掌握的知识
don't. I think B2B marketeteers keep
不。我认为B2B营销人员会继续
making this mistake. They're chasing
犯了这个错误。他们正在追逐
volume instead of quality. And when you
追求数量而非质量。当你
try to be seen by more people instead of
尽量让更多人看到你，而不是
the right people, all you're doing is
找对人，你所做的就是
making noise. But that noise rarely
制造噪音。但这种噪音很少
shifts the needle and it's often quite
改变了方向，而且这种改变往往相当显著。
expensive. And I know as there was the
昂贵的。我知道当时
time in my career where I kept making
在我职业生涯的某个时期，我一直在不断创造
this mistake that many of you will be
你们很多人都会犯这个错误
making it too. Eventually I started
我也要做。最终我开始了
posting ads on our show sponsors
在我们的节目赞助商网站上发布广告
platform LinkedIn. And that's when
平台 LinkedIn。就在那时
things started to change. I put that
事情开始发生变化。我把那句话写了下来。
change down to a few critical things.
简化为几个关键事项。
One of them being that LinkedIn was then
其中之一是当时的LinkedIn
and still is today the platform where
时至今日，它仍然是该平台
decision makers go to not only to think
决策者不仅要思考
and learn but also to buy. And when you
既要学习，也要购买。当你
market your business there, you're
在那里推广你的业务，你
putting it right in front of people who
把它直接放在人们面前
actually have the power to say yes. and
实际上有权说“是”。和
you can target them by job title,
你可以按职位名称进行目标定位，
industry, and company size. It's simply
行业和公司规模。就这么简单
a sharper way to spend your marketing
更有效地利用营销资源
budget. And if you haven't tried it, how
预算。如果你还没试过，那该怎么办呢？
about this? Give LinkedIn ads a try, and
关于这件事？不妨试试LinkedIn广告，
I'm going to give you a $100 ad credit
我将给你100美元的广告抵用金
to get you started. If you visit
助你入门。如果您访问
linkedin.com/diary,
linkedin.com/diary
you can claim that right now. That's
你现在就可以提出这个要求。那是
linkedin.com/diary.
linkedin.com/diary。
I've I've really gone back and forward
我真的来回走了好几趟
on this idea that even in podcasting
基于这种观点，即使在播客领域也是如此
that all the podcasts will be AI
所有播客都将由人工智能驱动
podcasts or I've gone back and forward
播客，或者我来回翻阅过。
on it and and where I landed at the end
在上面，以及我最终落脚的地方
of the day was that there'll still be a
当天最重要的消息是，仍然会有一个
category of media where you do want
你想要的媒体类别
lived experience on something
关于某事的亲身经历
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; For example, like you want to know how
例如，就像你想知道如何
the person that you follow and admire
你关注和钦佩的人
dealt with their divorce.
处理了他们的离婚事宜。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Or or how they're struggling with
是的。或者，或者他们如何挣扎于……
AI,
人工智能，
&gt;&gt; for example. Yeah. Exactly. But I but I
例如。是的。确切地。但我，但我
think things like news, there are there
想想新闻之类的东西，它们就在那里。
are certain situations where just like
在某些情况下，就像
straight news and straight facts and
直截了当的新闻和事实
maybe a walk through history may be
或许一次历史漫步会是……
eroded away by AIS. But even in those
被AIS侵蚀殆尽。但即使在那些
scenarios, you there's something about
各种情况，你都会想到一些事情
personality. And again, I I hesitate
性格。我又犹豫了。
here because I question myself. I'm not
我在这里是因为我质疑自己。我不是
in the camp of people that are romantic,
在那些浪漫的人当中，
by the way. I'm like I'm trying to be as
顺便一提。我感觉自己好像在努力成为……
as orientated towards whatever is true,
以真理为导向，
even if it's against my interests. And I
即使这违背了我的利益。我
hope people understand that about me.
希望人们能理解我这一点。
like um cuz even in my companies we
比如，因为即使在我的公司里，我们
experiment with like disrupting me with
尝试用某种方式打断我
AI and some people will be aware of
人工智能以及一些人会意识到这一点
those experiments
那些实验
&gt;&gt; because there will be a mix of all there
因为那里会混合各种各样的东西。
you can't imagine that the world will be
你无法想象世界将会变成什么样子。
completely just AI and completely just
完全只是人工智能，完全只是
podcasters you know you'll see a mix of
你知道的播客主播们，你会看到各种各样的
of both you'll see things that they do
你会看到他们各自做的事情。
better things that we do better
我们做得更好的事情
&gt;&gt; the the the message I'm trying to say is
我想表达的信息是
we need to prep for that
我们需要为此做好准备。
&gt;&gt; we need to be ready for that we need to
我们需要为此做好准备，我们需要
be ready by you know talking to our
做好准备，以便与我们交谈。
governments and saying hey it looks like
政府说，嘿，看起来像
I'm a a parallegal and it looks like all
我是一名律师助理，看起来一切都……
parallegals are going to be, you know,
你知道，那些所谓的“法律平行者”将会是……
financial researchers or analysts or
金融研究人员或分析师或
graphic designers or, you know, call
平面设计师，或者，你知道，打电话
center agents. It looks like half of
中心代理。看起来像一半
those jobs are being replaced already.
这些工作岗位已经被取代了。
&gt;&gt; You know who Jeffrey Hinton is?
你知道杰弗里·辛顿是谁吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh, Jeffrey. I I had him on the
哦，杰弗里。我让他上了我的车。
documentary as well. I love Jeffrey.
也是一部纪录片。我喜欢杰弗里。
&gt;&gt; Jeffrey Hinton told me
杰弗里·辛顿告诉我
&gt;&gt; trained to be a plumber.
接受过水管工培训。
&gt;&gt; Really?
真的吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. 100% for a while.
是的。有一段时间是百分之百。
&gt;&gt; And I I thought he was joking. 100%.
我当时以为他在开玩笑。 100%。
&gt;&gt; So I asked him again and he he looked me
所以我又问了他一遍，他看着我
dead in the eye and told me that I I
他直视着我的眼睛，告诉我我
should train to be a plumber.
应该去接受水管工培训。
&gt;&gt; 100%. So so so uh it's funny uh machines
100%。所以所以所以呃，这很有趣呃机器
replaced labor but we still had blue
更换了人工，但我们仍然有蓝色
collar. Then uh you know the refined
衣领。然后，你知道，精炼的
jobs became white collar information
工作变成了白领信息
workers.
工人。
&gt;&gt; What's the refined jobs?
哪些是更高级的职位？
&gt;&gt; You know you don't have to really carry
你知道你其实不必真的带着
heavy stuff or deal with physical work.
搬运重物或从事体力劳动。
You know you sit in an in an office and
你知道你坐在办公室里，
sit in meetings all day and blabber, you
你整天坐在会议室里胡说八道。
know, useless [__] then that's your
真是没用的东西。那这就是你的
job. Okay? And those jobs, funny enough,
工作。好的？而那些工作，说来也奇怪，
in the reverse of that, because robotics
反过来，因为机器人技术
are not ready yet. Okay. And I believe
尚未准备就绪。好的。而且我相信
they're not ready because of a
他们还没准备好，因为……
stubbornness on the on the robotics
机器人技术上的固执
community around making them humanoids.
围绕着将它们制成人形生物而形成的社群。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Because it takes so much to
好的。因为要花很多钱
perfect a human like action at proper
完美地做出类似人类的恰当动作
speed. You could, you know, have many
速度。你知道，你可以有很多。
more robots that don't look like a human
更多外形不像人类的机器人
just like a self-driving car in
就像自动驾驶汽车一样
California. Okay, that that does already
加利福尼亚州。好的，那样就行了。
replace drivers and and you know but but
更换驱动程序，你知道，但是
they're delayed. So the robotic the the
它们被延误了。所以，机器人
replacement of physical manual labor is
以体力劳动替代
going to take four to five years before
需要四到五年时间
it's possible at you know at at the
你知道，这是有可能的。
quality of the AI replacing mental labor
人工智能取代脑力劳动的质量
now and when that happens it's going to
现在，当那件事发生时，它将会……
take a long cycle to manufacture enough
生产足够的材料需要很长的周期。
robots so that they replace all of those
机器人，以便它们取代所有这些
jobs. that cycle will take longer. Blue
工作。那个周期需要更长时间。蓝色的
collar will stay longer.
项圈会保持更长时间。
&gt;&gt; So, I should move into blue collar and
所以，我应该转行做蓝领工作。
shut down my office.
关闭我的办公室。
&gt;&gt; I think you're you're not the problem.
我认为你不是问题所在。
&gt;&gt; Okay, good.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Let's put put it this way. There are
这么说吧。有
many people that we should care about
许多我们应该关心的人
that are a simple travel agent or an
就是一家普通的旅行社或
assistant
助手
that will see if not replacement a
这将看看是否需要更换。
reduction in the number of pings they're
减少他们的 ping 次数
getting. Simple as that.
正在获取。就这么简单。
And someone in, you know, ministries of
还有一些人，你知道，在某个部门里
labor around the world needs to sit down
世界各地的劳工需要坐下来好好谈谈。
and say, "What are we going to do about
然后说：“我们该怎么办？”
that? What if all taxi drivers and Uber
那？如果所有出租车司机和优步司机都……
drivers in uh in California get replaced
加州司机被替换
by self-driving cars? Should we start
通过自动驾驶汽车？我们应该开始吗？
thinking about that now, noticing that
现在想想，我注意到……
that trajectory makes it look like a
这条轨迹使它看起来像一个
possibility?" I'm going to go back to
有可能吗？我要回去……
this argument which is what a lot of
这种论点，也就是很多人的论点，
people will be shouting. Yes, but there
人们会大声喊叫。是的，但是有
will be new jobs or
会有新的工作机会吗？
&gt;&gt; and I as I said other than human
正如我所说，我并非人类。
connection jobs, name me one.
人脉拓展工作，请举一个例子。
&gt;&gt; So I I've got three assistants, right?
所以，我有三个助手，对吧？
Sophie, Liam B. And okay, in the near
索菲，利亚姆·B。好的，在不久的将来
term there might be, you know, with AI
可能会出现这种情况，你知道，人工智能领域也是如此。
agents, I might not need them to help me
代理人，我可能不需要他们的帮助。
book flights anymore. or I might not
别再订机票了。或者我可能不会
need them to help do scheduling anymore.
不再需要他们帮忙安排日程了。
Or even I've been messing around with
或者甚至我一直在摆弄
this new AI tool that my friend built
我朋友开发的这款新型人工智能工具
and you basically when me and you trying
基本上，当我和你尝试的时候
to schedule something like this today, I
今天安排这样的事情，我
just copy the AI in and it looks at your
只需复制AI代码，它就会查看你的数据。
calendar looks at mine and schedules it
日历会查看我的日历并安排它
for for us. So there might not be
对我们来说。所以可能没有
scheduling needs, but my dog is sick at
需要安排时间，但我的狗生病了。
the moment. And as I left this morning,
那一刻。今天早上我离开的时候，
I was like, damn, he's like really sick
我当时就想，天哪，他病得很重。
and I've taken him to the vet over and
我已经带他去看过兽医了。
over again. I really need someone to
一遍又一遍。我真的需要有人
look after him and figure out what's
照顾他，弄清楚到底发生了什么事。
wrong with him. So those kinds of
他出了问题。所以那些类型的
responsibilities of like care. I don't
承担类似护理的责任。我不
disagree at all. Again, all
完全不同意。再次强调，所有
&gt;&gt; and and I I won't I'm not going to be I
而且我不会，我不会成为我
don't know how to say this in a nice
不知道该怎么委婉地说。
way, but my assistants will still have
方式，但我的助手们仍然会有
their jobs, but I I as a CEO will be
他们的职位，但我作为首席执行官将会是
asking them to do a different type of
要求他们做另一种类型的
work.
工作。
&gt;&gt; Correct. So, so, so this is the
正确的。所以，所以，这就是
calculation everyone needs to be aware
每个人都需要了解的计算方法
of that a lot of their current
他们目前很多
responsibility, whoever you are, if
无论你是谁，都应承担责任。
you're a parallegal, if you're whatever,
如果你是那种人，那你就是个非法移民。
will be handed over. So, so let me
将被移交。所以，让我
explain it even more accurately. There
更准确地解释一下。那里
will be two stages of our interactions
我们的互动将分为两个阶段。
with the machines. One is what I call
和机器一起。其中之一是我所说的
the era of augmented intelligence. So,
增强智能时代。所以，
it's human intelligence augmented with
它是人类智能的增强版
AI doing the job. And then the following
人工智能在工作。然后是接下来的
one is what I call the era of machine
一个是我称之为机器时代的时期。
mastery. The job is done completely by
精通。这项工作完全由……完成
an AI without a human in the loop. Okay.
无需人类参与的人工智能。好的。
So in the era of augmented intelligence,
因此，在增强智能时代，
your assistances will augment themselves
您的协助将增强自身
with an AI to either be more productive.
利用人工智能来提高生产力。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Or interestingly to reduce the
好的。或者有趣的是，减少
number of tasks that they need to do.
他们需要完成的任务数量。
Correct. Now the more the number of
正确的。现在数量越多
tasks get reduced, the more they'll have
任务减少，他们拥有的就越多。
the bandwidth and ability to do tasks
带宽和执行任务的能力
like take care of your dog, right? or
就像照顾你的狗一样，对吧？或者
tasks that you know basically is about
你基本上知道的任务是关于
meeting your guests or whatever human
迎接你的客人或其他任何人
connection.
联系。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Life connection
生命联结
but do you think you need three for that
但你觉得需要三个吗？
or maybe now that some tasks have been
或许现在有些任务已经完成
you know outsourced to AI will you need
你知道外包给人工智能会需要什么吗？
two? You can easily calculate that from
二？你可以轻松地从以下途径计算出来：
call center agents. So from call center
呼叫中心客服人员。所以从呼叫中心
agents they're not firing everyone but
经纪人们，他们不是要解雇所有人，但是
they're taking the first part of the
他们正在执行第一部分
funnel and giving it to an AI. So
将其导入并交给人工智能。所以
instead of having 2,000 agents in a in a
而不是在一家公司拥有 2,000 名代理商
call center, they can now do the job
呼叫中心，他们现在可以胜任这项工作了。
with 1,800. I'm just making that number
共有 1,800 人。我只是在凑够那个数字而已。
up. H society needs to think about the
向上。 H社会需要考虑
200.
200.
&gt;&gt; And you're telling me that they won't
而你的意思是他们不会
move into other roles somewhere else.
转到其他地方担任其他职位。
&gt;&gt; I am telling you I don't know what those
我告诉你，我不知道那些是什么。
roles are.
角色是。
&gt;&gt; Well, I think we should all be
嗯，我认为我们都应该
musicians. We should all be authors. We
音乐家。我们都应该成为作家。我们
should all be artists. We should all be
都应该成为艺术家。我们都应该
entertainers. We should all be
演艺人员。我们都应该
comedians. We should all these are roles
喜剧演员。我们应该扮演所有这些角色
that will remain.
那将保留下来。
We should all be plumbers for the next 5
接下来的五年我们都应该去当水管工。
to 10 years. Fantastic. Okay. But even
至10年。极好的。好的。但即便
that requires society to morph
这需要社会发生转变。
and societyy's not talking about it.
但社会上对此却避而不谈。
Okay. I had this wonderful interview
好的。我进行了一次非常棒的面试。
with friends of mine, Peter Dendez and
和我的朋友彼得·丹德兹
and some of our friends and and they
还有我们的一些朋友，他们
were saying, "Oh, you know, the American
我们说，“哦，你知道，美国人”
people are resilient. They're going to
人类具有适应能力。他们将要
be entrepreneurs." I was like,
成为企业家。”我当时想，
seriously, you're expecting a truck
说真的，你期待的是一辆卡车
driver that will be replaced by an
将被替换的司机
autonomous truck to become an
自动驾驶卡车将成为
entrepreneur? Like, please put yourself
企业家？请设身处地地想一想。
in the shoes of real people,
设身处地地为普通人着想
right? You expect a single mother who
正确的？你期望一位单身母亲
has three jobs
有三份工作
to become an entrepreneur.
成为一名企业家。
And I'm not saying this is a dystopia.
我并不是说这是一个反乌托邦世界。
It's a dystopia if humanity manages it
如果人类真的做到了，那将是一个反乌托邦世界。
badly. Why? Because this could be the
很糟糕。为什么？因为这可能是
utopia itself where that single mother
乌托邦本身，那里有一位单身母亲
does not need three jobs.
不需要三份工作。
Okay? If we of if of our society was
好的？如果我们的社会是
just enough, that single mother should
足够了，单身母亲应该
have never needed three jobs,
我从来不需要同时做三份工作。
right? But the problem is our capitalist
正确的？但问题在于我们的资本主义
mindset is labor arbitrage. Is that I
心态就是劳动力套利。是我吗？
don't care what she goes through.
我不在乎她经历了什么。
You know, if if you're if you're
你知道，如果你是，如果你是
generous in your assumption, you'll say
你会说，你这种假设很慷慨。
because, you know, of what I've been
因为，你知道，关于我一直以来所做的事情
given, I've been blessed. or if you're
鉴于此，我感到很幸运。或者如果你是
mean in your assumption, it's going to
按照你的假设，它将会是……
be because she's an eater. I'm a a
可能是因为她很能吃。我是一名
successful businessman. The world is
成功的商人。世界是
supposed to be fair. I work hard. I make
应该公平。我工作很努力。我制作
money. We don't care about them.
钱。我们不在乎他们。
&gt;&gt; Are we asking of ourselves here
我们在这里是在问自己吗？
something that is not inherent in the
并非固有的
human condition? What I mean by that is
人类的境况？我的意思是……
the reason why me and you are in this my
我和你之所以会在这里，是因为……
office here. We're on the fourth or
办公室在这里。我们现在在第四个或
third floor of my office in central
我办公室位于市中心三楼
London. big office, 25,000 square feet
伦敦。大型办公楼，25,000平方英尺
with lights and internet connections and
配备灯光和网络连接
Wi-Fi and modems and AI teams
Wi-Fi、调制解调器和人工智能团队
downstairs. The reason that all of this
楼下。这一切的原因
exists is because something inherent in
之所以存在，是因为某些内在的东西。
my ancestors meant that they built and
我的祖先的意思是他们建造了……
accomplished and grew and that was like
取得成就并不断成长，那就像
inherent in their DNA. There was
根植于他们的DNA中。有
something in their DNA that said we will
他们DNA里似乎有什么东西告诉他们会
expand and conquer and accomplish. So
扩张、征服、成就。所以
that's they've passed that to us because
他们把那东西传给了我们，因为
we're their offspring and that's why we
我们是他们的后代，这就是为什么我们
find ourselves in these skyscrapers.
我们发现自己身处这些摩天大楼之中。
There is truth to that story. It's not
这个故事并非空穴来风。它不是
your ancestors,
你的祖先，
&gt;&gt; right?
正确的？
&gt;&gt; What is it?
那是什么？
&gt;&gt; It's the media brainwashing you
这是媒体在给你洗脑。
&gt;&gt; really
真的
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; But if if you look back before times of
但如果你回顾过去，就会发现
media
媒体
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; the reason why homo sapiens were so
智人如此……的原因
successful was because they were able to
成功是因为他们能够
dominate other tribes
统治其他部落
&gt;&gt; through banding together and
通过团结起来
communication. They conquered all these
沟通。他们征服了所有这些
other these other um whatever came
其他这些其他的嗯，不管是什么。
before homo sapiens.
在智人出现之前。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, so the the reason humans were
是的。所以，人类存在的原因
successful in my view is because they
我认为他们成功是因为他们
could form a tribe to start. It's not
可以先组建一个部落。它不是
because of our intelligence. I always
因为我们拥有智慧。我总是
joke and say Einstein would be eaten in
开玩笑说爱因斯坦会被吃掉
the jungle in 2 minutes.
两分钟带你穿越丛林。
&gt;&gt; Right? You know, the reason why we
正确的？你知道，我们这样做的原因
succeeded is because Einstein could
爱因斯坦之所以能够成功，是因为他能够
partner with a a big guy that protected
与一个身材魁梧、能保护他人的伙伴合作
him while he was working on relativity
他当时正在研究相对论
in the jungle. Right? Now the the the
在丛林里。正确的？现在是
further than that. So so you have to
不止于此。所以你必须
assume that life is a very funny game
假设人生是一场非常有趣的游戏
because it provides
因为它提供了
and then it it deprivives and then it
然后它剥夺，然后它
provides and then it deprivives. And for
它先提供，然后剥夺。而对于
some of us in that stage of deprivation
我们当中有些人正处于那种匮乏阶段
we try to say okay let's take the other
我们试着说，好吧，我们换另一个。
guys you know let's just go to the other
伙计们，咱们还是去另一边吧。
tribe take what they have or for some of
部落拿走他们拥有的东西，或者拿走一部分
us unfortunately we tend to believe okay
不幸的是，我们往往倾向于认为好吧
you know what I'm powerful uh f the rest
你知道吗，我很强大，呃，至于其他人嘛。
of you I'm just going to be the boss now
你们这些人，我现在就是老大。
it's interesting that you
你很有意思
you know position this as the condition
你知道，把这个定位为条件
of humanity if you really look at the
如果你真正审视人类，就会发现
majority of humans. What do the majority
绝大多数人。大多数人会怎么做？
of humans want?
人类想要什么？
Be honest. They want to hug their kids.
要诚实。他们想拥抱自己的孩子。
They want a good meal. Want good sex.
他们想吃顿好的。想要美好的性爱体验。
They want love. They want, you know, to
他们渴望爱。他们想要，你知道的
for most humans, don't measure on you
对大多数人来说，不要拿你来衡量自己。
and I. Okay? Don't measure by this
还有我。好吗？不要以此来衡量。
foolish person that's dedicated the rest
愚蠢的人把剩下的都献给了别人
of his life to to try and warn the world
他用尽一生去警醒世人。
around AI or, you know, solve uh love
围绕人工智能，或者，你知道，解决爱情问题
and relationships. That's that's crazy.
以及人际关系。太疯狂了。
That's I and I will tell you openly and
那就是我，我会坦诚地告诉你。
you met Hannah, my wonderful wife. It's
你见到了我的妻子汉娜，她真是个好妻子。它是
the biggest title of this year for me is
对我来说，今年最重要的头衔是
which of that am I actually responsible
其中哪一项是我真正负责的？
for? Which of that should I do without
为了？我应该省略哪一项呢？
the sense of responsibility? Which of
责任感？哪个
that should I do because I can? Which of
我应该因为自己有能力就去做吗？哪个
I ignore completely? But the reality is
我完全忽略吗？但事实是
most humans, they just want to hug their
大多数人，他们只想拥抱自己
loved ones. Okay? And if we could give
亲人。好的？如果我们能够给予
them that
他们
without the uh you know the the need to
没有那种……你知道的……的需要
work 20 you know 60 hours a week they
他们每周工作20小时，你知道的，60小时。
would take that for sure. Okay. And you
我肯定会接受的。好的。你呢
and I will think ah but life will be
我会想，啊，但生活将会是
very boring. To them life will be
非常无聊。对他们来说，生活将是
completely fulfilling. Go to Latin
非常满足。前往拉丁语
America.
美国。
Go to Latin America and see the people
去拉丁美洲看看那里的人们吧。
that go work enough to earn enough to
努力工作，挣足够的钱
eat today and go dance for the whole
今天吃饱喝足，然后去跳舞跳到天亮
night. Go to Africa.
夜晚。去非洲。
where people are sitting literally on
人们就坐在那里
you know sidewalks in the street and and
你知道街道上的人行道和
you know completely full of laughter and
你知道，他完全充满了欢笑，
joy. We we were lied to the the gullible
喜悦。我们被那些容易上当受骗的人欺骗了。
majority the cheerleaders. We were lied
大多数啦啦队员。我们被骗了。
to to to believe that we need to fit as
相信我们需要适应
another gear in that system. But if that
该系统中的另一个齿轮。但如果那样的话
system didn't exist nobody none of us
系统不存在，我们谁也不存在。
will go wake up in the morning and go
早上醒来就会去
like oh I want to create it. Totally
比如，哦，我想创造它。完全
not. I mean,
不是。我是说，
you've touched on it many times today.
你今天已经多次提到这个问题了。
We don't need, you know, most people
我们不需要，你知道，大多数人
that build those things don't need the
建造那些东西不需要
money.
钱。
So, why do they do it though? Because
那么，他们为什么要这样做呢？因为
homo sapiens were incredible
智人真是不可思议
competitors. They outco competed other
竞争对手。他们击败了其他竞争对手。
human species effectively. So, I'm what
人类物种实际上。所以，我是什么
I'm saying is is is that competition not
我的意思是，这就是竞争吗？
inherent in our in our wiring? and and
我们线路中固有的缺陷是什么？和
therefore are we are we is it wishful
因此，我们是否是……我们是否是……愿望？
thinking to think that we could
想着我们或许可以
potentially pause and say we we okay
可能会停下来，然后说我们没事
this is it we have enough now and we're
就这样，我们现在拥有的足够了，我们是
going to
前往
focus on just enjoying in my work I call
我专注于享受我的工作，我称之为
that the map mad spectrum okay mut
那张地图疯狂光谱好吧 mut
mutually assured prosperity versus
相互确保繁荣与
mutually assured destruction destruction
相互确保摧毁
okay and you really have to start
好的，你真的得开始了。
thinking about about this because in my
我一直在思考这个问题，因为在我的
mind what we have is the potential for
我们所拥有的，是潜力。
everyone. I mean you and I today have a
每个人。我的意思是，你我今天有一个
better life than the queen of England
比英国女王过得好多了
100 years ago. Correct? Everybody knows
100年前。正确的？人人都知道
that.
那。
&gt;&gt; Uh and yet that quality of life is not
然而，这种生活质量并非
good enough.
足够好了。
&gt;&gt; The truth is like just like you walk
真相就像你走路一样。
into a an electronic shop and there are
走进一家电子商店，里面有
60 TVs and you look at them and you go
60台电视，你看着它们，然后你就走了
like this one is better than that one.
比如这个比那个好。
Right? But in reality, if you take any
正确的？但实际上，如果你接受任何
of them home, it's superior quality to
对他们来说，这房子质量上乘。
anything that you'll ever need. More
你可能需要的一切。更多的
than anything you you'll ever need. That
比你所需要的任何东西都多。那
that's the truth of our life today. The
这就是我们当今生活的真相。这
truth of our life today is that there
我们今天生活的真相是：
isn't much more missing.
并没有缺失太多。
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And and when when you know
好的。而且，当你明白的时候
Californians tell us, "Oh, but AI is
加州人告诉我们，“哦，但是人工智能是……”
going to increase productivity and solve
将提高生产力并解决问题
this." And nobody asked you for that.
“这个。”而且没人要求你这么做。
Honestly, I never elected you to decide
说实话，我从未选举你来做决定。
on my behalf that, you know, getting a
代表我，你知道，得到
machine to answer me on a call center is
呼叫中心里用来接我电话的机器是
better for me. I really didn't. Okay?
对我来说更好。我真的没有。好的？
And and because those unelected
而且，因为那些未经选举的人
individuals are making all the
个人正在创造一切
decisions, they're selling those
他们正在出售这些决定。
decisions to us through what media.
通过哪些媒体向我们传达决定？
Okay? All lies from A to Z. None of it
好的？全是谎言，一点儿也没有。
is what you need.
这就是你需要的。
And and interestingly, you know me, I I
而且有趣的是，你知道我，我
this year I failed. Unfortunately, I
今年我失败了。很遗憾，我
won't be able to do it. But I normally
做不到。但我通常
do a 40 days silent retreat in nature.
在大自然中进行为期40天的静默修行。
Okay? And you know what? Even as I go to
好的？你知道吗？即使我去
those nature places, I'm so well trained
那些自然场所，我训练有素
that unless I have a a waitro nearby,
除非附近有服务员，
I'm not able to like I I'm I'm in
我无法像我一样，我感觉自己身处其中
nature, but I need to be able to drive
我喜欢大自然，但我需要会开车。
20 minutes to get my rice cakes. Like
等了20分钟我的年糕就做好了。喜欢
what? What? who was taught me that this
什么？什么？谁教导过我这一点
is the way to live. All of the media
这是一种生活方式。所有媒体
around me, all of the of the of the
我周围，所有的
messages that I get all the time, try to
我经常收到这样的信息，试着
sit back and say, "What if life had
坐下来，想想，“如果生活……”
everything?
一切？
What if I had everything I needed? I
如果我拥有了一切所需呢？我
could read. I could uh, you know, do my
能读懂。我可以，你知道，做我的
handcrafts and hobbies. I could, you
手工艺和爱好。我可以，你
know, fix my, you know, restore classic
知道，修复我的，你知道，恢复经典
cars. Not because I need the money, but
汽车。不是因为我缺钱，而是因为
because it's just a beautiful hobby. I
因为它是一项美好的爱好。我
could, you know, uh, build AIS to help
可以，你知道，呃，构建AIS来提供帮助
people with their long-term committed
那些有长期承诺的人
relationships, but really price it for
建立关系，但真正重要的是定价。
free. What if
自由的。如果什么
What if would you still insist on making
如果那样的话，你还会坚持要制作吗？
money?
钱？
I think no. I think a few of us will
我觉得不是。我认为我们当中有些人会
still and they will still crush the rest
他们仍然会碾压其余的人。
of us and hopefully soon the AI will
我们，以及希望不久的将来人工智能，都将如此。
crush them.
碾碎它们。
Right? That is the problem with your
正确的？这就是你的问题所在
world today. I will tell you hands down
当今世界。我毫不犹豫地告诉你
the problem with with our world today is
我们当今世界的问题在于
the A in face rips.
脸部撕裂中的A。
It's the A in face RIP. It's it's
这是 RIP 中的 A。是它的
accountability. The problem with our
问责制。我们的问题在于
world today, as I said, the top is lying
正如我所说，当今世界，顶层人士正在撒谎
all the time. The bottom is gullible
一直如此。底层容易上当受骗
cheerleaders and there is no
啦啦队，而且没有
accountability. You cannot hold anyone
问责制。你不能扣留任何人
in our world accountable today. Okay?
在当今世界，问责制至关重要。好的？
You cannot hold someone that develops an
你不能阻止一个人发展出……
AI that has the power to completely flip
拥有彻底颠覆能力的人工智能
our world upside down. You cannot hold
我们的世界颠倒了。你不能持有
them accountable and say why did you do
让他们承担责任，并说明你为什么这样做。
this? You cannot hold them accountable
这？你不能追究他们的责任。
and tell them to stop doing this. You
并告诉他们停止这样做。你
look at the world the wars around the
看看世界，看看周围的战争
world. Million hundreds of thousands of
世界。数百万数十万
people are dying. Okay. And you know and
有人正在死去。好的。你知道，
international court of justice will say
国际法院将表示
oh this is war crimes. You can't hold
哦，这是战争罪行。你不能持有
anyone accountable. Okay. You have 51%
任何人均须承担责任。好的。你拥有 51%
of the US today is saying stop that
美国今天表示停止这种做法。
51% change their their their lawy their
51%的人改变了他们的律师
view that that their money shouldn't be
认为他们的钱不应该……
spent on wars abroad. Okay. You can't
用于海外战争的开支。好的。你不能
hold anyone accountable. Trump can do
追究任何人的责任。特朗普能做到
whatever he wants. He starts tariffs
随他便。他开始征收关税。
which is against the the constitution of
这违反了宪法。
the US without consulting with the
美国未经协商
Congress. You can't hold him
国会。你无法抓住他
accountable. They say they're not going
负责。他们说他们不会去
to show the Epstein files. You can't
展示爱泼斯坦档案。你不能
hold them accountable. It's quite
追究他们的责任。相当
interesting in in Arabic we have that
有趣的是，在阿拉伯语中，我们有……
proverb that says the highest of your
一句谚语说，你最高的
horses you can go and ride. I'm not
你可以去骑马。我不是
going to change my mind. Okay. And
我打算改变主意。好的。和
that's truly
那真是
&gt;&gt; what does that mean?
这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; So basically people in the in the old
所以基本上，旧时代的人们
Arabia they would ride the horse to you
阿拉伯人会骑马向你走来
know to exert their power if you want.
要知道，如果需要，就应该运用他们的力量。
So go ride your highest horse. You're
所以，去骑上你最高的骏马吧。你是
not going to change my mind.
我不会改变主意。
&gt;&gt; Oh okay.
哦好的。
&gt;&gt; Right. And and the truth is that's I
正确的。而事实是，那就是我
think that's what our politicians today
我认为这就是我们当今政客们的想法。
have discovered. What our
已经发现。我们的
oligarchs have discovered what our uh
寡头们已经发现了我们的……
tech oligarchs have discovered is that I
科技寡头们发现的是，我
don't even need to worry about the
完全不用担心
public opinion anymore. Okay, at the
不再是公众舆论了。好的，在
beginning I would have to say ah this is
首先，我得说，啊，这是
for democracy and freedom and I have the
为了民主和自由，我拥有
right to defend myself and you know all
我有权自卫，你也知道这一切。
of that crap and then eventually when
那些乱七八糟的东西，然后最终当
the world wakes up and says no no hold
世界醒来，说不，不要再拖延了。
on hold on you're going too far they go
等等，你做得太过分了，他们会……
like yeah go ride your highest horse I
就像，去骑你最高的马吧。
don't care you can't change me there is
我不在乎，你改变不了我。
no constitution there is no ability for
没有宪法就没有能力
any any citizen to do anything
任何公民都可以做任何事
&gt;&gt; is it possible to have a society where
是否有可能建立一个这样的社会？
like the one you describe where
就像你描述的那种情况
there isn't hierarchies because it
因为不存在等级制度，所以
appears to me that humans
在我看来，人类
assemble hierarchies very very quickly
非常非常快地构建层级结构
very naturally and the minute you have a
非常自然，而且一旦你拥有
hierarchy you have many of the problems
层级结构中存在很多问题
that you've described where there's a
你描述的那个地方有一个
top and a bottom and the top have a lot
上衣和下装，上衣有很多
of power and the bottom
权力与底线
&gt;&gt; so so the mathematics mathematically is
所以，从数学角度来说，数学是……
actually quite interesting what I call
实际上，我称之为“相当有趣”的东西很有意思。
the uh the baseline relevance so so
呃，基线相关性等等
think of it this way say the average
换个角度想，比如说平均水平
human is an IQ of 100.
人类的平均智商为100。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. I tend to believe that when I use
好的。我倾向于相信，当我使用
my AIS today,
我今天的AIS数据
I borrow around 50 to 80 IQ points. I
我借用了大约 50 到 80 个智商点。我
say that because I've worked with people
这么说是因为我曾与人共事过
that had 50 to 80 IQ points more than
比其他人智商高出50到80分的人
me. And I now can see that I can sort of
我。我现在明白，我某种程度上可以
stand my my place.
坚守我的岗位。
50 50 IQ points, by the way, is enormous
顺便说一句，50分的智商可是相当惊人的。
because IQ is exponential. So the the
因为智商是指数级增长的。所以，
last 50 are bigger than my entire IQ,
最后50个数字比我的总智商还要高。
right?
正确的？
If I borrow 50 IQ points on top of say
如果我借用 50 个智商点，比如说
100 that I have, that's 30%.
我拥有的100个，占30%。
If I can borrow 100 IQ, that's 50%. That
如果我能借到100的智商，那就是50%。那
that's so, you know, basically doubling
那基本上就是翻倍了。
my intelligence. But if I can borrow
我的智力。但如果我能借到
4,000 IQ points
4000智商
in 3 years time, my IQ itself, my base
三年后，我的智商本身，我的基数
is irrelevant. Whether you are smarter
无关紧要。无论你更聪明
than me by 20 or 30 or 50 which in our
比我高出20、30甚至50倍，这在我们
world today made a difference
当今世界发生了改变
in the future if we can all augment with
未来，如果我们都能增强……
4,000 I end up with 4,100 another ends
4,000 我最终得到了 4,100，另一个结局
up with 400 4, you know 130 really
高达 400 4，你知道 130 真的
doesn't make much difference. Okay. And
差别不大。好的。和
because of that the difference between
正因如此，两者之间的差异
all of humanity and the augmented
全人类和增强人
intelligence
智力
is going to be irrelevant. So all of us
将会变得无关紧要。所以我们所有人
suddenly become equal and and this also
突然变得平等，而且这也
happens economically. All of us become
发生于经济领域。我们所有人都会变成
peasants.
农民。
And I never wanted to tell you that
我从来没想过要告诉你这些。
because I think it will make you run
因为我觉得这会让你跑起来。
faster. Okay? But unless you're in the
快点。好的？但除非你身处其中
top.1%,
前1%
you're a peasant. There is no middle
你是个农民。没有中间地带
class. There is, you know, if a CEO can
班级。你知道，如果首席执行官能够
be replaced by an AI, all of our middle
被人工智能取代，我们所有的中间环节
class is going to disappear.
阶级即将消失。
&gt;&gt; What are you telling me?
你在跟我说什么？
All of us will be equal and it's up to
我们所有人都会平等，这取决于……
all of us to create the society that we
我们所有人共同创造我们理想的社会
want to live in
想住在
&gt;&gt; which is a good thing
这是件好事。
&gt;&gt; 100%. But that society is not
100%。但那个社会并非如此。
capitalism.
资本主义。
&gt;&gt; What is it?
那是什么？
&gt;&gt; Unfortunately, it's much more socialism.
可惜的是，它更偏向社会主义。
It's much more hunter gatherer. Okay.
它更像是狩猎采集时代。好的。
It's much more communionike if you want.
如果你愿意的话，它更像是一种交流。
This is a society where humans connect
这是一个人类相互联系的社会
to humans, connect to nature, connect to
对人类而言，与自然相连，与……相连
the land, connect to knowledge, connect
土地，连接知识，连接
to spirituality. H where all that we
通往灵性之路。 H 我们都在哪里
wake up every morning worried about
每天早上醒来都担心
doesn't feature anymore
不再有此功能
and it's a it's a better world believe
而且，这是一种“这是一个更美好的世界”的信念。
it or not
不管怎样
&gt;&gt; and are you
你是吗？
&gt;&gt; we have to transition to it
我们必须过渡到这个阶段。
&gt;&gt; okay so in such a world which I guess is
好吧，在这样一个世界里，我想这就是……
your version of the utopia that we can
你设想的我们能够拥有的乌托邦。
get to when I wake up in the morning
早上醒来的时候
what do I do
我该怎么办
&gt;&gt; what do you do today
你今天做什么
&gt;&gt; I woke up this morning I spent a lot of
我今天早上醒来，花了很多时间
time with my dog cuz my dog is sick as
因为我的狗生病了，所以要花时间陪它。
&gt;&gt; you're going to do that too
你也会这么做。
&gt;&gt; yeah I was stroking him a lot and then I
是的，我一直在抚摸他，然后我
fed him and he sick again and I just
我喂了他，结果他又病了，我就……
thought, "Oh god." So I spoke to the
我心想：“我的天哪。”所以我跟……谈了谈
vet.
兽医。
&gt;&gt; You spend a lot of time with your other
你花很多时间和你的其他人在一起
dog. You can do that, too.
狗。你也可以这样做。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Right.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; But then I was very excited to come
但我当时非常兴奋，迫不及待地想来。
here, do this, and after this I'm going
来，做这个，之后我就走了
to work. It's Saturday, but I'm going to
去工作。今天是星期六，但我打算……
go downstairs in the office and work.
下楼到办公室工作。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So six hours of the day so far are
是的。所以，到目前为止，一天中的六个小时是
your dogs and me.
你的狗和我。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Good. You can do that still.
好的。你仍然可以这样做。
&gt;&gt; And then build my business.
然后发展我的事业。
&gt;&gt; You You may not need to build your
你可能不需要自己建造
business,
商业，
&gt;&gt; but I enjoy it.
但我很享受。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Then do it. If you enjoy it, do
是的。那就去做。如果你喜欢，那就去做吧。
it. You may wake up and then, you know,
它。你可能会醒来，然后，你知道，
instead of building your business, you
而不是发展你的事业，你
may invest in your body a little more,
或许可以多花点钱在身体上，
go to the gym a little more, go play a
多去健身房锻炼一下，多玩一会儿
game, go read a book, go prompt an AI
玩游戏，去读书，去引导人工智能
and learn something. It's not a horrible
并学习一些东西。这不算太糟糕。
life. It's the life of your
生活。这是你的人生
grandparents.
祖父母。
It's just two generations ago where
就在两代人之前，
people went to work before the invention
在发明这项技术之前，人们就已经去工作了。
of more. Remember, huh? people who who
甚至更多。还记得吧？那些
started working in the 50s and 60s, they
他们从上世纪五六十年代就开始工作了。
worked to make enough money to live a
努力工作挣足够的钱来维持生活
reasonable life, went home at 5:00 p.
过着平常的生活，下午5点回家。
p.m. had tea with their with their loved
下午和他们爱的人一起喝茶
ones, had a wonderful dinner around the
几位，在……享用了一顿美好的晚餐
table, did a lot of things, you know, uh
桌子，做了很多事，你知道，呃
for the rest of the evening and enjoyed
当晚剩余时间我都待在那里，很开心。
life.
生活。
&gt;&gt; Some of them
他们中的一些人
&gt;&gt; in the 50s and 60s, there were still
在五六十年代，仍然有
people that were
那些人
&gt;&gt; correct. And I think it's a very
正确的。我认为这非常
interesting question.
有趣的问题。
uh how many of them and I really really
呃，他们有多少人？我真的真的
am I actually wonder if people will tell
我其实很想知道人们会不会说出来。
me do we think that 99% of the world
我们是否认为世界上99%的人
cannot live without working or that 99%
99%的人离不开工作。
of the world would happily live without
世界将欣然接受没有它的生活
working
在职的
&gt;&gt; what do you think
你怎么认为
&gt;&gt; I think if we if you give me other
我认为如果我们，如果你给我其他
purpose
目的
you know we we defined our purpose as
你知道，我们把我们的宗旨定义为
work that's a capitalist lie
那份工作是资本主义的谎言
&gt;&gt; was there ever a time in human history
人类历史上是否曾有过这样的时期？
where our purpose wasn't work
我们的目的并非工作
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; When was that?
那是什么时候的事？
&gt;&gt; All through human history until the
纵观人类历史，直到
invention of Moore.
摩尔的发明。
&gt;&gt; I thought my ancestors were out hunting
我以为我的祖先们都出去打猎了。
all day.
一整天。
&gt;&gt; No, they went out hunting once a week.
不，他们每周出去打猎一次。
They fed the tribe for the week. They
他们供养了部落一周。他们
gathered for a couple of hours every
每隔几个小时都会聚集在一起
day. Farmers, you know, saw the seeds
天。你知道，农民们看到了种子
and and waited for months at on end.
然后，他们等了好几个月。
&gt;&gt; What did they do with the rest of the
他们把剩下的东西怎么处理了？
time?
时间？
&gt;&gt; They connected as humans. They explored.
他们之间建立了人与人之间的联系。他们进行了探索。
They uh were curious. They discussed
他们……嗯，很好奇。他们讨论了
spirituality and the stars. They they
灵性与星辰。他们
they lived. They hugged. They made love.
他们活了下来。他们拥抱了。他们做爱了。
They lived.
他们活了下来。
&gt;&gt; They killed each other a lot.
他们互相残杀了很多次。
&gt;&gt; They they still kill each other today.
他们至今仍在互相残杀。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That's what I'm saying. So
是的。我就是这个意思。所以
&gt;&gt; to take that out of the equation, if you
为了排除这种可能性，如果你
look at how
看看如何
&gt;&gt; and by the way that actually that
顺便说一句，实际上就是
statement again, one of the of the 25
再次声明，这是25人之一
tips I I I I talk about uh to to tell
提示 我 我 我 我 谈论呃 告诉
the truth is words mean a lot. No,
事实上，言语的力量非常强大。不，
humans did not kill each other a lot.
人类之间并不经常互相残杀。
Very few generals instructed humans or
很少有将军指导过人类或
tribe leaders instructed lots of humans
部落首领指导了许多人类
to kill each other. But if you leave
互相残杀。但如果你离开
humans alone, I tend to believe 99 98%
仅就人类而言，我倾向于相信99%到98%的人。
of the people I know, let me just take
在我认识的人当中，让我随便举几个例子吧。
that sample, wouldn't hit someone in the
那个样本，不会击中任何人。
face. And if someone attempted to hit
脸。如果有人试图击中
them in the face, they'd defend
他们会当面反抗，还会捍卫自己。
themselves but wouldn't attack back.
他们自己不会还击。
Most humans are okay. Most of us are
大多数人都还好。我们大多数人都是
wonderful beings.
奇妙的生物。
Most of us have no,
我们大多数人都没有，
you know, yeah, you know, most people
你知道，是啊，你知道，大多数人
don't don't need a Ferrari. They want a
我不需要法拉利。他们想要一个
Ferrari because it gets sold to them all
法拉利，因为它卖给了他们所有人。
the time. But if there were no Ferraris
时间。但如果没有法拉利……
or everyone had a Ferrari, people
或者说，每个人都有一辆法拉利，人们
wouldn't care.
不会在意。
Which, by the way, that is the world
顺便说一句，那就是世界。
we're going into. There will be no
我们要进入。不会有
Ferraris or everyone had Ferraris,
法拉利，或者说人人都开法拉利。
right? n you know the majority of
正确的？你知道大多数人
humanity will never have the income on
人类永远不会有收入
UBI to to buy something super expensive.
全民基本收入可以用来买超级昂贵的东西。
Only the very top guys in Elisium will
只有Elisium最顶尖的人才行。
be you know driving cars that are made
你知道，驾驶那些制造的汽车
for them by the AI or not even driving
人工智能为他们提供服务，甚至无需驾驶。
anymore. Okay. Or
不再是了。好的。或者
you know again sadly ide from an
你知道，很遗憾，这又是一个来自……的想法
ideology point of view it's a strange
从意识形态的角度来看，这很奇怪
place but you'll get communism that
那个地方，但你会得到共产主义。
functions.
函数。
The problem with communism is that
共产主义的问题在于……
didn't it didn't function. It didn't
它没起作用。没有
provide for for its society. But the
为社会提供保障。但是
concept was you know what everyone gets
概念是，你知道每个人都会得到什么。
their needs. And I don't say that
他们的需求。我并没有这么说。
supportive of either society. I don't
支持这两个社会。我不
say that because I dislike capitalism. I
这么说是因为我不喜欢资本主义。我
always told you I'm a capitalist. I want
我一直都跟你说过我是个资本家。我想
to end my life with 1 billion happy and
以10亿个快乐结束我的生命
I use capitalist methods to get there.
我运用资本主义手段来实现目标。
The objective is not dollars. The
目标不是金钱。这
objective is number of happy people.
目标是幸福人数。
&gt;&gt; Do you think there'll be My girlfriend,
你觉得会有我女朋友吗？
she's always bloody right. I've said
她总是对的。我说过
this a few times on this podcast. If
这个话题在这个播客节目中出现过好几次。如果
you've listened before, you've probably
你以前听过，你可能听过。
heard me say this. I I don't tell her
听到我这么说了吗？我没告诉她
enough in the moment, but I figure out
当时就够了，但我明白了
from speaking to experts that she's so
从与专家的交谈中得知，她非常……
[__] right. She like predicts things
没错。她好像能预言未来。
before they happen. And one of her
在它们发生之前。还有她的其中一位
predictions that she's been saying to me
她跟我说的那些预言
for the last two years, which in my head
过去两年，我一直这么想
I've been thinking now, I don't I don't
我一直在想，我不，我不
believe that, but now maybe I'm thinking
我相信这一点，但现在也许我在想……
she's tr she's telling the truth. I hope
她说的是真的。我希望
she's going to listen to this one is she
她会听这个的，对吧？
keeps saying to me, she's been saying
她一直跟我说，她一直这么说
for the last two years, she was there's
过去两年，她一直在那里
going to be a big split in society. She
社会将出现巨大分裂。她
was and the way she describes it is
是，她描述的方式是
she's saying like there's going to be
她说的好像会有……
two groups of people. the people that
两类人。那些人
split off and go for this almost
分头行动，几乎
huntergatherer
狩猎采集者
community centric connection centric
以社区为中心，以联系为中心
utopia and then there's going to be this
乌托邦，然后就会出现这种情况
other group of people who pursue
另一群追求
you know the technology and the AI and
你了解这项技术和人工智能，
the optimization and get the brain chips
优化并获得脑芯片
cuz like there's nothing on earth that's
因为就像地球上没有任何东西是
going to persuade my girlfriend to get
我打算说服我女朋友去买
the computer brain chips%
计算机脑芯片
&gt;&gt; but there will be people that go for it
但总会有人放手一搏。
and they'll have the highest IQs and
他们的智商将最高，
they'll be the most productive by
他们将是最有生产力的。
whatever objective measure of
无论客观衡量标准是什么
productivity you want to apply and she's
你想应用的生产力，而她就是
very convinced there's going to be this
我非常确信将会发生这件事。
splitting of society.
社会分裂。
&gt;&gt; So there was there was a I don't know if
所以，我不知道是否
you had Hugo Dearis here.
当时雨果·迪里斯也在这里。
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. A very very very renowned
是的。一位非常非常非常著名的
eccentric uh computer scientist who
古怪的计算机科学家
wrote a book called the Arctic War and
他写了一本书，名为《北极战争》
the Arctic War was basically around you
北极战争基本上就在你附近爆发。
know how we it's not going to first it's
我知道我们不会先这样做，这是……
not going to be a war between humans and
不会有人类之间的战争
AI. It will be a war between people who
人工智能。这将是一场人民之间的战争
support AI and people who sort of don't
支持人工智能以及那些不太支持人工智能的人
want it anymore. Okay? And and it is and
我不想再拥有它了。好的？而且，它就是这样。
and it will be us versus each other
这将是一场我们之间的较量。
saying should we allow AI to take all
也就是说，我们是否应该允许人工智能接管一切
the jobs or should we you know some
这些工作，或者我们应该你知道一些吗？
people will support that very much and
人们会非常支持这一点。
say yeah absolutely and so you know we
当然可以，所以你知道我们
will benefit from it and others will say
将会从中受益，其他人也会这么说。
no why why we don't need any of that why
不，为什么？我们不需要那些东西。为什么？
don't we keep our jobs and let AI do 60%
我们难道不应该保住工作，让人工智能完成60%的工作吗？
of the work and all of us work 10our
这项工作，我们所有人都工作了10个小时。
weeks and it's a beautiful society by
几周后，这是一个美丽的社会。
the way that's a possibility so a
这样做是有可能的，所以
possibility if society awakens is to say
如果社会觉醒，这种可能性就是……
okay everyone still keeps their job, but
好吧，大家都保住了工作，但是……
they're assisted by an AI that makes
他们得到了人工智能的协助，该人工智能可以……
their job much easier. So, it's not, you
他们的工作轻松多了。所以，不是你。
know, this uh this hard labor that we do
你知道，我们做的这种艰苦劳动。
anymore, right? It's a possibility. It's
已经没有了吧？这是一种可能性。它是
just a mindset. A mindset that says in
只是一种心态。一种认为
that case, the capitalist still pays
在这种情况下，资本家仍然要付出代价。
everyone.
每个人。
Uh they still make a lot of money. The
呃，他们仍然赚了很多钱。这
business is really great, but everyone
生意确实很好，但是每个人
that they pay has purchasing power to
他们支付的费用具有购买力
keep the economy running. So,
保持经济运转。所以，
consumption continues, so GDP continues
消费持续，因此GDP也持续增长。
to grow. It's a beautiful setup,
成长。这是一个很漂亮的布置。
but that's not the capitalist labor
但这并非资本主义劳动。
arbitrage.
套利。
&gt;&gt; But also, when you're competing against
但是，当你与……竞争时
other nations
其他国家
&gt;&gt; and other competitors and other
以及其他竞争对手和其他
businesses,
企业，
&gt;&gt; whichever nation is most brutal and
无论哪个国家最残暴，
drives the highest gross margins, gross
带来最高的毛利率，毛利率
profits is going to be the nation that
利润将成为国家的命脉。
&gt;&gt; So, there are examples in the world,
所以，世界上有很多这样的例子。
this is why I say it's the map mad
这就是我为什么说这是地图疯了。
spectrum. There are examples in the
光谱。有这样的例子
world where when we recognize mutually
在这个世界里，当我们彼此认可时
assured destruction, okay, we we decide
确保摧毁，好吧，我们决定
to shift. So nuclear threat for the
转移。所以，核威胁对……
whole world makes nations across nations
整个世界由各个国家组成
makes nations work together, right? By
促进各国合作，对吧？经过
saying, hey, by the way, prolification
顺便说一句，增生
of nuclear weapon is not weapons is not
核武器不是武器，它不是
good for humanity. Let's all of us limit
对人类有益。让我们所有人都限制
it. Of course, you get the rogue player
它。当然，总会有不守规矩的玩家。
that, you know, doesn't want to sign the
你知道，就是那种不想签字的人。
agreement and wants to continue to to
同意并希望继续
have that, you know, that that weapon in
你知道，有那种武器
their arsenal. Fine. But at least the
他们的武器库。美好的。但至少
rest of humanity agrees that if you have
其余的人类都同意，如果你有
a nuclear weapon, we're part of an
核武器，我们是其中的一部分
agreement between us. Mutually assured
我们之间的协议。相互保证
prosperity, you know, is the CERN
你知道，繁荣就是欧洲核子研究中心（CERN）。
project. CERN is too too complicated for
项目。欧洲核子研究中心（CERN）对于任何人来说都太复杂了。
any nation to build it alone. But it is
任何国家都可以独自建造它。但它是
really, you know, a very useful thing
真的，你知道，这东西非常有用。
for physicists and for understanding
对于物理学家和理解
science. So all nations send their
科学。所以各国都派出了他们的
scientists all collaborate and everyone
科学家们都在合作，每个人都在合作。
uses the outcome. It's possible. It's
利用结果。有可能。它是
just a mindset. The only barrier between
只是一种心态。唯一的障碍
a hum, you know, a utopia for humanity
嗡嗡声，你知道，人类的乌托邦
and AI and the dystopia we're going
人工智能和我们即将走向的反乌托邦世界
through is is a capitalist mindset.
这是一种资本主义思维方式。
That's the only barrier. Can you believe
这是唯一的障碍。你敢相信吗？
that? It's hunger for power, greed, ego,
那？这是对权力的渴望、贪婪和自负。
&gt;&gt; which is inherent in humans.
这是人类与生俱来的特质。
&gt;&gt; I disagree. especially humans that live
我不同意。尤其是生活在
on other islands.
在其他岛屿上。
&gt;&gt; I disagree. If you ask, if you take a
我不同意。如果你问，如果你拿一个
poll across everyone watching, okay,
对所有观看者进行民意调查，好的。
would they prefer to have a world where
他们是否更愿意生活在一个这样的世界里：
there is one tyrant, you know, running
你知道，现在有一个暴君在统治着
all of us, or would they prefer to have
我们所有人，或者他们更愿意拥有
a world where we all have harmony?
一个和谐的世界？
&gt;&gt; I completely agree, but they're two
我完全同意，但他们是两个人。
they're two different things. What I'm
这是两回事。我是什么
saying is I know that that's what the
意思是，我知道那就是……
audience would say they want, and I'm
观众会说他们想要什么，而我
sure that is what they want, but the
当然，那肯定是他们想要的，但是
reality of human beings is through
人类的现实是通过
history proven to be something else.
历史证明并非如此。
Like, you know, if think about the
你知道，想想看
people that lead the world at the
引领世界的人
moment, is that what they would say?
他们会这么说吗？
&gt;&gt; Of course not.
当然不是。
&gt;&gt; And they're the ones that are
而他们就是那些人
influencing.
影响。
&gt;&gt; Of course not. Of course not. But you
当然不是。当然不是。但是你
know what's funny? I'm the one trying to
知道什么好笑吗？我才是那个试图……的人
be positive here and you're the one that
保持积极的态度，你就是那个……
has given up on on human.
已经放弃了人类。
&gt;&gt; It's not. It's Do you know what it is?
它不是。你知道这是什么吗？
It goes back to what I said earlier,
这跟我之前说的有关，
which is the pursuit of what's actually
这就是对真正事物的追求。
true irrespective. I'm with you. That's
无论如何，这都是真的。我和你在一起。那是
why I'm screaming for the whole world
我为何向全世界呐喊
because still today in this country that
因为时至今日，在这个国家仍然如此。
claims to be a democracy. If everyone
自称是民主国家。如果每个人
says, "Hey, please sit down and talk
他说：“嘿，请坐下谈谈。”
about this."
关于这件事。
There will be a shift. There will be a
情况将会发生变化。将会有一个
change.
改变。
&gt;&gt; AI agents aren't coming. They are
人工智能代理不会到来。他们是
already here. And those of you who know
已经在这里了。而你们当中那些知道的人
how to leverage them will be the ones
如何利用它们才是关键所在。
that change the world. I spent my whole
改变世界。我花了我全部的时间
career as an entrepreneur regretting the
作为一名企业家，我后悔自己的职业生涯
fact that I never learned to code. AI
我从来没学过编程。人工智能
agents completely change this. Now, if
经纪人彻底改变了这一点。现在，如果
you have an idea and you have a tool
你有一个想法，你也有一个工具
like Replet, who are a sponsor of this
例如 Replet，他们是这项活动的赞助商。
podcast, there is nothing stopping you
播客，没有什么能阻止你
from turning that idea into reality in a
将这个想法变成现实
matter of minutes. With Replet, you just
只需几分钟。使用 Replet，你只需
type in what you want to create and it
输入你想创建的内容，然后它
uses AI agents to create it for you. And
使用人工智能代理为您创建它。和
now I'm an investor in the company as
现在我是这家公司的投资者。
well as them being a brand sponsor. You
以及他们作为品牌赞助商的身份。你
can integrate payment systems or
可以集成支付系统或
databases or loginins. Anything that you
数据库或登录信息。任何你
can type. Whenever I have an idea for a
会打字。每当我有一个想法
new website or tool or technology or
新网站、工具或技术
app, I go on replet.com and I type in
我使用 app，访问 replet.com，然后输入
what I want. A new to-do list, a survey
我想要的。一份新的待办事项清单，一份调查问卷
form, a new personal website. Anything I
表格，一个新的个人网站。任何我
type, I can create. So, if you've never
输入类型，我可以创建。所以，如果你从未
tried this before, do it now. Go to
以前试过，现在再试一次。前往
replet.com and use my code Steven for
访问 replet.com 并使用我的代码 Steven 享受优惠
50% off a month of your Replet call
Replet 通话服务一个月可享 50% 折扣
plan. Make sure you keep what I'm about
计划。务必记住我的立场。
to say to yourself. I'm inviting 10,000
对自己说。我邀请了10000人
of you to come even deeper into the
让你更深入地了解
diary of a CEO. Welcome to my inner
一位CEO的日记。欢迎来到我的内心世界
circle. This is a brand new private
圆圈。这是一个全新的私人
community that I'm launching to the
我即将推出的社区
world. We have so many incredible things
世界。我们拥有太多不可思议的东西
that happen that you are never shown. We
这种情况你永远不会看到。我们
have the briefs that are on my iPad when
我有iPad上的那些简报
I'm recording the conversation. We have
我正在录音。我们有
clips we've never released. We have
我们从未发布过的片段。我们有
behindthe-scenes conversations with the
与幕后人员的对话
guest and also the episodes that we've
嘉宾以及我们已经播出的剧集
never ever released. and so much more.
从未发行过。还有更多。
In the circle, you'll have direct access
在圆圈内，您将拥有直接访问权限
to me. You can tell us what you want
大部头书。您可以告诉我们您想要什么
this show to be, who you want us to
这个节目会是什么样子，你想让我们成为什么样的人？
interview, and the types of
面试，以及面试类型
conversations you would love us to have.
你希望我们进行哪些对话？
But remember, for now, we're only
但请记住，目前我们只是
inviting the first 10,000 people that
邀请前10000人
join before it closes. So, if you want
赶在关闭前加入。所以，如果你想
to join our private closed community,
加入我们的私密封闭社区，
head to the link in the description
请点击说明中的链接。
below or go to daccircle.com.
下方或访问 daccircle.com。
I will speak to you there.
我会在那里和你谈谈。
One of the things I'm actually really
我真正非常
compelled by is this idea of utopia and
正是这种乌托邦的理念驱使着我们。
what that might look and feel like
那会是什么样子，感觉如何？
because one of the
因为其中一个
&gt;&gt; it may not be as utopia to you I feel
我觉得，对你来说，它可能并不像乌托邦那样美好。
but uh
但是呃
&gt;&gt; well I amum really interestingly when I
嗯，我妈妈真的很有趣，当我
have conversations with billionaires not
与亿万富翁对话
recording especially billionaires that
记录尤其是亿万富翁的记录
are working on AI the thing they keep
他们正在研究人工智能，他们一直关注着这件事。
telling me and I've said this before I
告诉我，而且我以前也说过，
think I said it in the Jeffrey Hinton
我想我在杰弗里·辛顿的演讲中说过。
conversation is they keep telling me
他们一直在跟我说话，对话就是他们告诉我
that we're going to have so much free
我们将拥有如此多的自由时间
time that those billionaires are now
现在这些亿万富翁们……
investing in things like football clubs
投资足球俱乐部之类的项目
and sporting events and live music and
以及体育赛事和现场音乐会
festivals because they believe that
因为他们相信，举办节日
we're going to be in an age of
我们将进入一个时代
abundance. This sounds a bit like
丰富。这听起来有点像
utopia.
乌托邦。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; that sounds good. That sounds like a
听起来很好。听起来像是一个
good good thing.
真是件好事。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. How do we get there?
是的。我们该如何到达那里？
&gt;&gt; I don't know.
我不知道。
&gt;&gt; That's this is the entire conversation.
这就是全部对话内容。
The entire conversation is what does
整个对话到底是什么意思？
society have to do to get there? What
社会需要做些什么才能实现这一目标？什么
does society have to do to get there?
社会需要做些什么才能实现这一目标？
&gt;&gt; We need to stop uh uh thinking from a
我们需要停止从“嗯嗯”的角度思考。
mindset of scarcity. It
匮乏心态。它
&gt;&gt; this goes back to my point which is we
这又回到了我之前的观点，那就是我们
don't have a good track record of that.
在这方面并没有良好的记录。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So this is probably the the reason
是的。所以这大概就是原因吧
for the other half of my work which is
至于我工作的另一半，那就是
you know I'm trying to say
你知道我想说的是
what really matters to humans.
对人类真正重要的东西。
&gt;&gt; What is that?
那是什么？
&gt;&gt; If you ask most humans what do they want
如果你问大多数人他们想要什么，他们会说他们想要什么。
more most in life? I'd say they want to
生活中最重要的是什么？我认为他们想要
love their family, raise a family. Yeah,
爱护家人，养育子女。是的，
&gt;&gt; love.
爱。
That's what most humans want most. We
那是大多数人最渴望的。我们
want to love and be loved. We want to be
渴望爱与被爱。我们想成为
happy. We want those we care about to be
快乐的。我们希望我们关心的人
safe and happy. And we want to love to
安全快乐。我们渴望去爱
love and be loved. I tend to believe
爱与被爱。我倾向于相信
that the only way for us to get to a
我们到达目的地的唯一途径是
better place is for the evil people at
更好的去处是为那些邪恶的人准备的。
the top to be replaced with AI.
顶部将被人工智能取代。
Okay? Because they won't be replaced by
好的？因为它们不会被取代
us.
我们。
And as per the second uh dilemma, they
至于第二个难题，他们
will have to replace themselves by AI.
他们将不得不被人工智能取代。
Otherwise, they lose their advantage. If
否则，他们就会失去优势。如果
their competitor moves to AI, if China
如果他们的竞争对手转向人工智能，中国
hands over their arsenal to AI, America
美国将武器库拱手让给人工智能。
has to hand over their arsenal to AI.
不得不将他们的武器库移交给人工智能。
&gt;&gt; Interesting. So, let's play out this
有趣的。那么，让我们来演练一下。
scenario. Okay, this is interesting to
设想。好的，这很有意思。
me. So if we replace the leaders that
我。所以如果我们更换领导人……
are power hungry with AIs that have our
拥有强大力量的人工智能正在崛起，而我们
interests at heart, then we might have
如果真以自身利益为重，那么我们或许可以
the ability to live in the utopia you
能够在你理想中的乌托邦里生活的能力
describe
描述
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; Will interesting and and in my mind AI
这会很有趣，而且在我看来，人工智能
by definition will have our best
根据定义，我们将做到最好。
interest in mind
感兴趣的
because of what normally is referred to
因为通常所说的
as the minimum energy principle. So, so
遵循最小能量原理。所以，所以
if you ask, if you understand
如果你问，如果你明白
if you understand that at the very core
如果你从根本上理解这一点的话
of physics, okay, the reason we exist in
物理学，好吧，我们存在的理由是
our world today is what is known as
我们今天的世界被称为
entropy. Okay, entropy is is is the
熵。好的，熵就是……
universe's nature to decay, you know,
宇宙的本质是衰败，你知道的。
tendency to break down. You know, if you
容易崩溃。你知道，如果你
if I drop this uh uh you know, mug, it
如果我把这个，呃，你知道的，杯子掉地上了，它
doesn't drop and then come back up.
不会下降然后又回升。
&gt;&gt; By the way, plausible. There is a
顺便说一句，这很有可能。有一个
plausible scenario where I drop it and
一个可能的情况是，我把它掉在地上，然后
the tea, you know, spills in the air and
你知道，茶水会洒到空中。
then falls in the mug. One in a trillion
然后掉进杯子里。万亿分之一
configurations, but entropy says because
配置，但熵表明，因为
it's one in a trillion, it's never going
这是万亿分之一的概率，它永远不会发生
to happen or rarely ever going to
发生或几乎不会发生
happen. So everything will break down.
发生。所以一切都会崩溃。
You know, if you leave a a garden
你知道，如果你留下一个花园
unhedged, it will become a jungle. Okay?
如果不设对冲，这里就会变成丛林。好的？
W with that in mind,
考虑到这一点，
the role of intelligence is what? Is to
情报的作用是什么？是
bring order to that chaos.
让混乱局面恢复秩序。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. That's what intelligence does. It
嗯。这就是智能的作用。它
tries to bring order to that chaos.
试图从混乱中恢复秩序。
Okay? And because it tries to bring
好的？因为它试图带来
order to that chaos, the more
混乱之中，秩序越有序越好
intelligent a being is,
一个有智慧的生物是……
&gt;&gt; the more it tries to apply that
它越是试图应用这一点。
intelligence with minimum waste and
以最小的浪费实现智能
minimum resources.
最少的资源。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And you know that. So you can
好的。你知道的。所以你可以
build this business for a million
打造这家价值百万美元的企业
dollars or you can if you can afford to
用美元支付，或者如果你负担得起的话也可以。
build it for you know uh 200,000 you'll
你知道，建造它需要20万，你会
build it. If you are forced to build it
建造它。如果你被迫建造它
for 10 million you're going to have to.
要想赚到1000万，你就得这么做。
But you're always going to minimize
但你总是会尽量减少
waste and and resources.
废物和资源。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, if you assume this to be true,
好的。所以，如果你假设这是真的，
&gt;&gt; the a super intelligent AI will not want
一个超级智能的人工智能不会想要
to destroy ecosystems. It will not want
破坏生态系统。它不会想要
to kill a million people
杀死一百万人
because that's a waste of energy,
因为那是浪费能源。
explosives, money, power, and people.
炸药、金钱、权力和人口。
By definition, the smartest people you
根据定义，最聪明的人就是你
know who are not controlled by their ego
要知道谁不受自我控制
will say that the best possible uh
会说最好的可能呃
future for for Earth is for all species
地球的未来属于所有物种
to continue.
继续。
&gt;&gt; Okay. On this point of efficiency, if an
好的。就效率这一点而言，如果
AI is designed to drive efficiency,
人工智能旨在提高效率，
would it then not want us to be putting
那么它难道不希望我们这样做吗？
demands on our health services and our
对我们的医疗服务和我们的要求
social services? I believe that will be
社会服务？我相信那将会是
definitely true and definitely they
绝对正确，而且他们
definitely they won't allow you to fly
他们肯定不会让你飞的。
back and forth between London and and
往返于伦敦和
California
加利福尼亚州
&gt;&gt; and they won't want me to have kids
他们不会希望我生孩子。
because my kids are going to be an
因为我的孩子们将会成为
inefficiency.
效率低下。
&gt;&gt; If you assume that life is an
如果你假设生活是……
inefficiency so you see the intelligence
效率低下，所以你才能看出其中的智慧
of life is very different than the
生活与此截然不同
intelligent intelligence of humans.
人类的智能。
Humans will look at life as a a problem
人类会将生活视为一个问题。
of scarcity. Okay. So more kids take
稀缺性。好的。所以更多孩子会
more. That's not how life thinks. life
更多的。生活并非如此运转。生活
will say will think that for me to to to
会说会认为对我来说要去
to thrive I don't need to kill the
为了生存，我不需要杀死……
tigers I need to just have more deer and
老虎？我只需要更多的鹿和
the weakest of the deer is eaten by the
最弱小的鹿会被吃掉
tiger and the tiger poops on the trees
老虎，老虎在树上拉屎
and the you know the deer eats the
你知道鹿会吃……
leaves and you right the so the the the
叶子，你对，所以，
the smarter way of creating abundance is
创造富足的更明智的方法是
through abundance the smarter way of
通过更明智的方式，以更丰富的方式
propagating life is to have more life
繁衍生命就是拥有更多生命
&gt;&gt; okay so are you saying that we're we're
好的，所以你的意思是，我们……
basically going to elect AI leaders to
基本上就是要选举人工智能领域的领导者。
rule over us and make decisions for us
统治我们，替我们做决定
in terms of the economy.
就经济而言。
&gt;&gt; I I don't see any choice just like we
我看不到任何选择，就像我们一样。
spoke about self- evvolving AIs.
谈到了自我进化的人工智能。
&gt;&gt; Now, are those going to be human beings
那么，这些人会是人类吗？
with the AI or is it going to be AI
是人工智能，还是将会是人工智能？
alone?
独自的？
&gt;&gt; Two stages. At the beginning, you'll
两个阶段。一开始，你会
have augmented intelligence because we
我们拥有增强智能，因为我们
can add value to the AI, but when
可以为人工智能增添价值，但是当
they're at IQ 60,000,
他们的智商是60000，
what value do you bring?
你能带来什么价值？
Right? And and you know again this goes
正确的？而且你知道，这又开始了。
back to what I'm attempting to do on my
回到我正在尝试做的事情上
second you know approach. My second
其次，你知道方法。我的第二个
approach is knowing that those AIs are
这种方法是知道这些人工智能是
going to be in charge. I'm trying to
他将负责此事。我正在尝试
help them
帮助他们
understand what humans want. So this is
了解人类的需求。所以这是
why my first project is love. Committed
为什么我的第一个项目是爱。坚定的
true deep connection and love. Not only
真挚而深刻的联结与爱。不仅
to try and get them to hook up with a
试图让他们与某人发生关系
date but trying to make them find the
日期，但试图让他们找到
right one. and then from that try to
正确的那个。然后从那开始尝试
guide us through a relationship so that
引导我们建立关系，以便
we can understand ourselves and others
我们能够了解自己和他人。
right and if I can show AI that one
对，如果我能向人工智能展示这一点的话。
humanity cares about that and two they
人类关心这一点，其次他们
know how to foster love
懂得如何培养爱
when AI then is in charge they'll not
当人工智能掌权时，他们就不会
make us hate each other like the current
让我们像现在这样互相憎恨
leaders they'll not divide us they want
领导人不会分裂我们，他们想要分裂我们
us to be more loving
让我们更加充满爱
&gt;&gt; will we have to prompt the AI with the
我们需要提示人工智能吗？
values and the outcome we want or like
价值观以及我们想要或喜欢的结果
I'm trying to understand that because
我正在努力理解这一点，因为
I'm trying to understand how like
我正在努力理解“像”是什么意思。
China's AI if they end up having an AI
中国的AI，如果他们最终拥有了AI的话
leader will have a different set of
领导者将拥有一套不同的……
objectives to the AI of the United
联合国人工智能的目标
States if if they both have AIs as
如果它们都拥有人工智能，那么它们就都属于这种情况。
leaders and and how actually the nation
领导人以及国家实际运作情况
that ends up winning out and dominating
最终胜出并占据主导地位
the world will be the one who
世界将成为谁
who asks their AI leader to be all the
谁要求他们的AI领导者承担所有责任？
things that world leaders are today to
世界领导人今天要做的事情
dominate
支配
&gt;&gt; unfortunately
很遗憾
&gt;&gt; to grab resources
攫取资源
not to to be kind, to be selfish.
不要善良，要自私。
&gt;&gt; Unfortunately, in the era of augmented
不幸的是，在增强现实时代
intelligence, that's what's going to
智慧，那才是关键所在。
happen.
发生。
&gt;&gt; So, if you
所以，如果你
&gt;&gt; This is why I predict the dystopia. The
这就是我预言反乌托邦世界到来的原因。这
dystopia is super intelligent AI is
反乌托邦是超级智能人工智能。
reporting to stupid leaders,
向愚蠢的领导汇报工作
&gt;&gt; right?
正确的？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Which is
是的。是的。是的。那就是
&gt;&gt; which which is absolutely going to
这绝对会
happen. It's unavoidable.
发生。这是不可避免的。
&gt;&gt; But the long term
但从长远来看
&gt;&gt; Exactly. In the long term, for those
确切地。从长远来看，对于那些
stupid leaders to hold on to power,
愚蠢的领导人为了保住权力，
they're going to make, you know,
他们会做出，你知道的，
delegate the important decisions to an
将重要决定委托给
AI.
人工智能。
Now you say the Chinese AI and the
现在你说中国人工智能和
American AI these are human
美国人工智能，这些都是人类
terminologies. AIS don't see themselves
术语。 AIS并不认为自己
as speaking Chinese. They don't see
像说中文一样。他们看不见
themselves as belonging to a nation as
他们把自己视为一个国家的一份子
long as their their task is to maximize
只要他们的任务是最大化
uh profitability and prosperity and so
盈利能力和繁荣等等
on.
在。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Of course, if you know before we
好的。当然，如果你在我们之前就知道的话
hand over to them and before they're
交给他们，在他们……之前
intelligent enough to make you know
足够聪明，能让你明白
autonomous decisions, we we tell them
我们告诉他们自主决策
no, the task is to reduce humanity from
不，任务是减少人类
7 billion people to one.
七十亿人对一人。
I think even then eventually they'll go
我认为即使那样，最终他们也会离开。
like that's the wrong objective. Every
那好像是错误的目标。每一个
any smart person that you speak to will
你跟任何一个聪明人交谈都会
say that's the wrong objective. I think
说这是错误的目标。我认为
if we look at the directive that Xi
如果我们看一下习近平的指示，就会发现
Jinping, the leader of China has and
中国领导人习近平已经……
Donald Trump has as the leader of
唐纳德·特朗普是……的领导人
America, I think they would say that
我想美国人会这么说。
their stated objective is prosperity for
他们所宣称的目标是繁荣。
their country. So if we that's what they
他们的国家。所以如果我们那样做的话
would say, right?
没错吧？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And one one of them means it.
是的。其中一人是认真的。
&gt;&gt; Okay, we'll get into that. But they'll
好的，我们来详细探讨一下。但他们会
say that that it's prosperity for their
他们说，这对他们来说是繁荣。
country. So one would then assume that
国家。因此，人们会假设
when we move to an AI leader, the
当我们转向人工智能领导者时，
objective would be the same. The
目标不变。这
directive would be the same. make our
指令内容相同。使我们
country prosperous.
国家繁荣昌盛。
&gt;&gt; Corre. Correct.
科尔。正确的。
&gt;&gt; And I think that's the AI that people
我认为这就是人们所说的AI。
would vote for potentially. I think they
可能会投票支持。我认为他们
would say we want to be prosperous.
可以说，我们都想变得富裕。
&gt;&gt; What do you think would make America
你认为什么会让美国……
more prosperous?
更繁荣？
&gt;&gt; To spend a trillion dollars on on war
在战争上花费一万亿美元
every year or to spend a trillion
每年花费一万亿美元
dollars on education and healthcare and
投入教育和医疗保健的资金
and uh you know
你知道的
helping the poor and homelessness.
帮助贫困和无家可归者。
It's complex because I think so I think
我觉得这很复杂。
it would make America more prosperous to
这将使美国更加繁荣。
take care of
照顾好
the of everybody and they have the
每个人都有，他们也有
luxury of doing that because they are
因为他们有这样的奢侈条件
&gt;&gt; the most powerful
最强大的
&gt;&gt; the most powerful nation in the world.
世界上最强大的国家。
&gt;&gt; No, that's not true. The the the reason
不，那不是真的。原因
so so you see all war has two
所以你看，所有战争都有两个方面。
objectives. One is to make money for the
目标。其一是为……赚钱
war machine and the other is deterrence.
战争机器和威慑是两个方面。
Okay. and nine super nuclear powers
好的。以及九个超级核大国
around the world is enough deterrence.
在全球范围内进行这样的威慑就足够了。
So any
所以任何
war between America and China will go
美国和中国之间的战争将会持续下去。
through a long phase of destroying
经过漫长的破坏阶段
wealth by exploding bombs and killing
通过爆炸和杀戮来获取财富
humans for the first objective to
人类是首要目标
happen. Okay? And then eventually if it
发生。好的？然后最终，如果它
really comes to deterrence it's the
真正说到威慑，那就是……
nuclear bombs or now in the age of AI
核弹，或者如今的人工智能时代
biological uh you know manufactured
生物的，呃，你知道的，人造的
viruses or whatever uh these super
病毒或其他什么东西，呃，这些超级
weapons this is the only thing that you
武器，这是你唯一拥有的东西
need
需要
so for China to have nuclear bombs not
所以中国拥有核武器并非不可能。
as many as the US is enough for China to
美国拥有的资源足以让中国拥有。
say don't f with me
说别惹我
and this seems I do not know I'm not in
而这似乎表明我不知道我不在其中。
in in PresidentQi's mind. I I'm not in
在齐总统的心里。我不在其中
President Trump's mind. I you know, it's
特朗普总统的想法。你知道，是
very difficult to to navigate what he's
很难理解他到底在做什么。
thinking about. But the truth is that
正在思考。但事实是……
the Chinese line is for the last 30
中文线路是最后30条
years you spent so much on war while we
你们多年来把那么多时间都花在了战争上，而我们
spent on industrial infrastructure. And
用于工业基础设施的支出。和
that's the reason we are now by far the
这就是我们现在遥遥领先的原因。
largest nation on the planet. Even
地球上面积最大的国家。甚至
though the west will lie and say
尽管西方会撒谎说
America's bigger, America's bigger in
美国更大，美国更大
dollars, okay, with purchasing power
美元，好的，有购买力
parity, this is very equivalent.
两者性质相同，非常相等。
Okay. Now, when you really understand
好的。现在，当你真正理解
that, you understand that prosperity is
也就是说，你明白繁荣是
not about destruction. That's that's by
并非关于破坏。那就是……
definition the reality. Prosperity is
定义现实。繁荣是
can I invest in my people and make sure
我能否投资于我的员工并确保
that my people stay safe? And to make
如何保障我的人民安全？并且要制作
sure my people are safe, you just wave
我的人民肯定安全，你只要挥挥手就行了。
the flag and say, "If you f with me,
举起旗帜说：“如果你惹我，
I have nuclear deterrence or I have
我拥有核威慑，或者我拥有
other forms of deterrence." But you
其他形式的威慑。”但是你
don't have to. Deterrence by definition
不必如此。威慑的定义
does not mean that you send soldiers to
这并不意味着你要派士兵去
die. I guess the question I was trying
死。我想问的问题是……
to answer is is um when we have these AI
回答这个问题是，嗯，当我们拥有这些人工智能的时候
leaders and we tell our AI leaders to
我们告诉领导者，我们的人工智能领导者要
aim for prosperity, won't they just end
追求繁荣，难道不会就此结束吗？
up playing the same games of okay,
玩着同样的游戏，好吧，
prosperity equals a bigger economy, it
繁荣意味着更大的经济规模，
equals more money, more wealth for us.
这意味着我们会有更多的钱，更多的财富。
And the way to attain that in a zero sum
而实现这一点的途径就是在零和博弈中。
world where there's only a certain
一个只有某种东西的世界
amount of wealth is to accumulate it.
财富的积累才是关键。
&gt;&gt; So why don't you search for the meaning
所以，你为什么不去探寻它的含义呢？
of prosperity? What is
繁荣？什么是
&gt;&gt; that's not what you just described.
你刚才描述的并不是那样。
&gt;&gt; I don't even know what the bloody word
我甚至不知道那该死的词是什么。
means. What is the meaning of
方法。是什么意思？
prosperity?
繁荣？
&gt;&gt; The meaning of prosperity is a state of
繁荣的意义是一种状态
thriving success and good fortune
蓬勃发展的成功和好运
especially in terms of wealth, health
尤其是在财富和健康方面
and overall well-being.
以及整体幸福感。
&gt;&gt; Good.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Economic health, social, emotional.
经济健康、社会健康、情感健康。
&gt;&gt; So,
所以，
&gt;&gt; so true prosperity is to have that for
所以真正的繁荣就是拥有这一点。
everyone on earth. So if you want to
地球上的每一个人。所以如果你想
maximize prosperity, you have that for
最大化繁荣，你拥有这一点
everyone on earth.
地球上的每一个人。
&gt;&gt; Do you know where I think an AI leader
你知道我认为人工智能领导者在哪里吗？
works is if we had an AI leader of the
这样做是因为我们有一个人工智能领导者。
world and we directed it to say
世界，我们指示它说
&gt;&gt; and that absolutely is going to be what
那绝对会是……
happens.
事情发生了。
&gt;&gt; Prosperity for the whole world.
全世界繁荣昌盛。
&gt;&gt; No, but this is really an interesting
不，但这确实很有趣
question. So one of my predictions which
问题。所以我的预测之一是
people really rarely speak about is that
人们很少谈论的是……
we we believe we will end up with
我们相信我们最终会
competing AIs.
人工智能之间的竞争。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I believe we will end up with one brain.
我相信我们最终会拥有一个大脑。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So you understand the argument I
好的。所以你明白我的论点了吧。
was making a second ago from the
一秒钟前正在从
position of lots of different countries
许多不同国家的立场
all having their own AI leader, we're
每个国家都有自己的人工智能领导者，我们是
going to be back in the same place of
将会回到同一个地方
greed. Yeah.
贪婪。是的。
&gt;&gt; But if if the world had one AI leader
但如果世界只有一个人工智能领导者呢？
&gt;&gt; and and it was given the directive of
它被赋予了以下指令：
make us prosperous and save the planet
使我们繁荣昌盛，拯救地球
&gt;&gt; and
和
&gt;&gt; the polar bears would be fine
北极熊会没事的。
&gt;&gt; 100%. And that's that's what I've been
100%。这就是我一直以来所做的事情。
advocating for for a for a year and a
倡导一年之久
half now. I was saying we need a CERN of
一半了。我当时说我们需要一个像欧洲核子研究中心那样的机构。
AI.
人工智能。
&gt;&gt; What does that mean? the like the
这意味着什么？就像
particle accelerator where the entire
粒子加速器，其中整个
world you know combined their efforts to
你所了解的世界各国齐心协力
discover and understand physics no
发现并理解物理学
competition okay mutually assured
竞争没问题，相互保证
prosperity I'm asking the world I'm
我向世界祈求繁荣。
asking governments like Abu Dhabi or
向阿布扎比等政府询问
Saudi which seem to be you know the sec
沙特阿拉伯，你知道，就是那个证券交易委员会。
and you know some of the largest AI
你知道一些最大的人工智能
infrastructures in the world I'm I'm
世界上的基础设施 我是 我是
saying please host all of the AI
请托管所有人工智能
scientists in the world to come here and
世界各地的科学家都将来到这里。
build AI for the world and and you have
为世界构建人工智能，而你拥有
to understand we're holding on to a
要理解我们坚持的
capitalist system that will collapse
即将崩溃的资本主义制度
sooner or later. Okay? So, we might as
迟早。好的？所以，我们或许可以
well collapse it with our own hands.
我们会亲手把它摧毁。
&gt;&gt; I think we found the solution, mate.
我觉得我们找到解决办法了，伙计。
&gt;&gt; I I think it's actually really really
我觉得这其实真的非常
possible. I actually okay I can't I
可能的。我其实没事，我不能。
can't I can't refute the idea that if we
我无法反驳“如果我们……”这种观点。
had an AI that was responsible and
拥有一个负责任的人工智能，
governed the whole world and we gave it
它统治了整个世界，而我们把它给了它。
the directive of making humans
人类制造指令
prosperous, healthy and happy
繁荣、健康和快乐
as long as that directive was clear.
只要指令明确就行。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Because there's always bloody unintended
因为总会有该死的意外
consequences. as we might.
结果。我们或许会这样做。
&gt;&gt; So, so the the only the only challenge
所以，唯一的挑战
you're going to to to meet is all of
你要去见的就是所有这些
those who today are trillionaires or you
那些如今的万亿富翁，或者你
know massive massively powerful or
知道大规模的、极其强大的或
dictators or whatever. Okay. How do you
独裁者什么的。好的。你如何
convince those to give up their power?
说服他们放弃权力？
How do you convince those that hey by
你如何说服那些人，嘿，通过
the way
道路
any car you want you want you want
任何你想要的车
another yacht we'll get you another
我们还会再给你弄一艘游艇。
yacht. We'll just give you anything you
游艇。我们会给你任何东西
want. Can you please stop harming
想。请你停止伤害他人。
others? There is no need for arbitrage
其他的？无需套利
anymore.
不再是了。
There's no need for others to lose, for
其他人没有必要失败，因为
the capitalists to win.
资本家必胜。
&gt;&gt; Okay? And in such a world where there
好的？在这样一个世界里，
was an AI leader and it was given the
是一位人工智能领导者，并被赋予了
directive of making us prosperous as a
使我们繁荣昌盛的指令
whole world, the the the billionaire
全世界，这位亿万富翁
that owns the yacht would have to give
游艇的所有者必须给予
it up.
把它搞定。
&gt;&gt; No. No.
不。不。
&gt;&gt; Give them more yachts.
给他们更多游艇。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; It costs nothing to make yachts when
制造游艇不需要任何成本
robots are making everything. So So the
机器人正在制造一切。所以，所以
complexity of this is so interesting. A
这其中的复杂性真是太有趣了。一个
world where it costs nothing to make
在这个世界里，制造成本为零。
everything
一切
&gt;&gt; because energy is abundant and
因为能源是丰富的，而且
&gt;&gt; energy is abundant because every problem
能源之所以丰富，是因为每个问题
is solved with enormous IQ. Okay,
需要极高的智商才能解决。好的，
because manufacturing is done through
因为制造是通过以下方式进行的
nanopysics not through components. Okay,
纳米物理学并非通过组件来实现。好的，
because mechanics are robotic. So you
因为机械师就像机器人一样。所以你
you know you drive your car in, a robot
你知道你开车进去的时候，会遇到一个机器人吗？
looks at it and fixes it. Costs you a
检查后修复。花费你
few cents of energy that are actually
实际上，只需几分钱的能量。
for free as well.
而且还是免费的。
That imagine a world where intelligence
想象一下一个充满智慧的世界
creates everything.
创造万物。
That world literally
那个世界简直就是
every human has anything they ask for.
每个人都能得到他们想要的一切。
But we're not going to choose that
但我们不会选择那样做。
world.
世界。
&gt;&gt; Imm imagine you're in a world and and
想象一下你身处一个世界，而且
really this is a very interesting
这真是一件非常有趣的事情。
thought experiment. Imagine that UBI
思想实验。想象一下全民基本收入
became very expensive universal basic
普遍基本法变得非常昂贵
income. So governments decided we're
收入。所以各国政府决定我们是
going to put everyone in a one by 3 m
准备把所有人都安置在一个 1 米 x 3 米的房间里
room, okay? We're going to give them a
房间，好吗？我们将给他们一个
headset and a seditive,
耳机和镇静剂，
right? And we're going to let them sleep
正确的？我们要让他们睡觉。
every night. They'll sleep for 23 hours
每晚。他们会睡23个小时
and we're going to get them to live an
我们将让他们过上……
entire lifetime.
一生。
H they you know in that in that virtual
你知道，在那个虚拟世界里
world at the speed of your brain when
当世界以你大脑的速度运转时
you're asleep you're going to have a
你睡着了，你即将……
life where you date Scarlett Johansson
你和斯嘉丽·约翰逊约会的生活
and then another life where you're
然后是另一种人生，在那种人生里，你是……
Nefertiti and then another life where
纳芙蒂蒂，然后是另一种人生，
you're a donkey right reincarnation
你转世就是头驴
truly in the virtual world
真正在虚拟世界中
and then you know I get another life
然后你知道，我又有了另一段人生。
when I date Hannah again and I you know
当我再次和汉娜约会的时候，你知道的
enjoy that life tremendously and
尽情享受那种生活吧！
basically the cost of all of this is
基本上，这一切的成本是
zero. You wake up for one hour, you walk
零。你醒来一小时，然后散步
around, you move your blood, you eat
四处走动，血液循环，你吃
something or you don't, and then you put
你要么做某事，要么不做，然后你就放
the headset again and live again. Is
戴上耳机，重新开始。是
that unthinkable?
难以置信？
&gt;&gt; It's creepy compared to this life. It's
与现在的生活相比，这简直太可怕了。它是
very, very doable.
非常非常可行。
&gt;&gt; What? That we just live in headsets?
什么？我们是不是一直都生活在耳机里？
&gt;&gt; Do you Do you know if you're not?
你知道自己是否不是吗？
&gt;&gt; I don't know if I'm not known.
我不知道我是否默默无闻。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you have no idea if you're not. I
是啊，如果你不是，你就永远不会知道。我
mean, every experience you've ever had
意思是，你曾经经历过的每件事。
in life was an electrical electrical
生活中的电气
signal in your brain.
大脑中的信号。
Okay.
好的。
Now, now ask yourself if we can create
现在，问问你自己，我们能否创造
that in the virtual world,
在虚拟世界中，
it wouldn't be a bad thing if I can
如果我能做到，那也并非坏事。
create it in the physical world.
在现实世界中创造它。
&gt;&gt; Maybe we already did. No,
或许我们已经这么做了。不，
&gt;&gt; my theory is 98% we have. But that's a
我的理论是，我们有98%的把握。但那是一个
hypothesis. That's not science.
假设。那不是科学。
&gt;&gt; Well, you think that
嗯，你觉得呢？
&gt;&gt; 100? Yeah.
100？是的。
&gt;&gt; You think we already created that and
你认为我们已经创造了那个吗？
this is it?
就这样吗？
&gt;&gt; I think this is it. Yeah. Think of any
我想就是这里了。是的。想想任何
think of the uncertainty principle of
想想不确定性原理
quantum physics, right? What you what
对吧，是量子物理学？你想说什么
you what you observe gets collapses the
你观察到的一切都崩溃了
wave function and gets rendered into
波函数并被渲染成
reality. Correct.
现实。正确的。
&gt;&gt; I don't know anything about physics. So
我对物理一窍不通。所以
you
你
&gt;&gt; so so quantum physics basically tells
所以，量子物理学基本上是这么说的
you that everything exists in
你明白万物都存在于你之中
superposition.
叠加原理。
Right? So ev every subatomic particle
正确的？所以，每一个亚原子粒子
that ever existed has the chance to
曾经存在过的事物有机会
exist anywhere at any point in time and
随时随地存在
then when it's observed by an observer
然后当它被观察者观察到时
it collapses and becomes that. Okay. In
它坍塌并变成那样。好的。在
very interesting principle exactly how
非常有趣的原理，究竟是如何实现的？
video games are. In video games, you
电子游戏是。在电子游戏中，你
have the entire game world on the hard
把整个游戏世界都设置成困难模式
drive of your console. The player turns
你的游戏机的驱动器。玩家轮到
right. That part of the game world is
正确的。游戏世界的那一部分是
rendered. The rest is in superp
渲染完成。其余部分都在超级
position.
位置。
&gt;&gt; Supposition meaning
假设的含义
&gt;&gt; superposition means it's available to be
叠加意味着它可以是
rendered, but you have to observe it.
已经渲染完成，但你需要仔细观察。
The player has to turn to the other side
玩家必须转向另一侧
and see it. Okay? I mean think about the
去看看吧。好的？我的意思是，想想看
truth of physics. The truth of the fact
物理学的真理。事实真相
that this is entirely empty space. These
这里完全是空旷的空间。这些
are tiny tiny tiny I think you know
非常非常非常小，我想你知道的。
almost nothing in terms of mass but
质量上几乎可以忽略不计，但
connected with you know enough energy so
与你联系，你知道足够的能量，所以
that my finger cannot go through my
我的手指无法穿过我的
hand. But even when I hit this
手。但即使当我遇到这种情况时
&gt;&gt; your hand against your finger.
你的手抵着你的手指。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. When I hit my hand against my
是的。当我的手撞到我的
finger, that sensation in my in is felt
手指，我感觉到了那种感觉。
in my brain. It's an electrical signal
在我脑海里。它是一种电信号
that went through the wires. There's
它通过电线传输。有
absolutely no way to differentiate that
完全没有办法区分这一点。
from a signal that can come to you
来自可以传递给你的信号
through a uh neural link kind of
通过某种神经连接
interface, computer brain interface, a
接口，计算机脑机接口，一个
CDI, right? So, so you know the a lot of
是CDI吧？所以，你知道很多
those things are very very very
那些东西非常非常非常
possible. But the truth is most of the
可能的。但事实是，大多数
world is not physical. Most of the world
世界并非物质世界。世界大部分地区
happens inside our imagination, our
发生在我们想象之中，我们的
processors.
处理器。
&gt;&gt; And it and I guess it doesn't really
而且，我想它其实并没有
matter to us. Our reality
对我们来说很重要。我们的现实
&gt;&gt; doesn't at all. So this is the
完全没有。所以这就是
interesting bit. The interesting bit is
很有意思。有趣的是……
it doesn't at all
完全没有
&gt;&gt; because we still if this is a video
因为我们仍然认为这是一段视频
game, we live consequence.
游戏，我们活在后果之中。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. This is your subjective experience
是的。这是你的主观体验。
of it.
它的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And there's consequence in this. I
是的。这样做是有后果的。我
I I don't like pain.
我不喜欢疼痛。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; And I like having orgasms. It's like And
我喜欢性高潮。就像……
you're playing by the rule of the game.
你遵守了游戏规则。
Yeah. Right. And and it's quite
是的。正确的。而且，这相当
interesting and going back to a
有趣，而且要回到……
conversation we should have. It's the
我们应该进行一次对话。这是
interesting bit is if I'm not the
有趣的是，如果我不是……
avatar,
头像，
if I'm not this physical form, if I'm if
如果我不是这副肉身，如果我是……
I'm the consciousness wearing the
我是穿着……的意识
headset,
耳机，
what should I invest in? Should I invest
我应该投资什么？我应该投资吗？
in this video game, this level, or
在这个电子游戏中，这一关，或者
should I should I invest in the real
我应该投资房地产吗？
avatar, in the real me, and not the
化身，真正的我，而不是……
avatar, but the consciousness, if you
化身，但意识，如果你
want, spirit, if you're religious,
欲望、精神，如果你信教的话，
&gt;&gt; how would I invest in the consciousness
我该如何投资于意识呢？
or the god or the spirit or whatever?
或者神灵、精灵之类的？
How would I? In the same way that if I
我该怎么做？就像如果我
was playing Grand Theft Auto, the video
当时正在玩《侠盗猎车手》，视频
game, the character in the game couldn't
游戏中，游戏中的角色无法
invest in me holding the controller.
让我拿着手柄吧。
&gt;&gt; You Yes, but you can invest in yourself
是的，你可以投资自己。
holding the controller.
拿着控制器。
Oh, okay. So, so you're saying that
哦好的。所以，你的意思是……
Moga is in fact consciousness. And so,
莫加实际上就是意识。所以，
how would consciousness invest in
意识会如何投资于
itself?
本身？
&gt;&gt; By becoming more aware. So, so
通过提高意识。所以，所以
&gt;&gt; of it consciousness.
它的意识。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, real real video gamers don't
是的。所以，真正的电子游戏玩家不会
want to win the level. Real video gamers
想赢得这一关。真正的电子游戏玩家
don't want to uh to finish the level.
不想呃，完成这一关。
Okay. Real video gamers have one
好的。真正的电子游戏玩家都拥有一个
objective and one objective only, which
目标，且只有一个目标，即
is to become better gamers.
目的是成为更优秀的游戏玩家。
So, so you know how serious I am about I
所以，你知道我对这件事有多认真。
play Halo. I'm one, you know, two of
玩《光环》。我是其中之一，你知道，是两个
every million players can beat me.
一百万个玩家都能打败我。
That's how what I rank, right? Very for
这就是我的排名方式，对吧？非常适合
my age, phenomena. Hey, anyone, right?
我的年龄，真是个奇迹。嘿，有人在吗？
But seriously, you know, and that's
但说真的，你知道，那就是
because I don't play. I mean, I practice
因为我不玩。我的意思是，我练习
45 minutes a day, four times a week when
每天45分钟，每周四次
I'm not traveling. And I practice with
我不打算旅行。我练习时
one single objective, which is to become
唯一的目标就是成为
a better gamer.
更厉害的游戏玩家。
&gt;&gt; I don't care which shot it is. I don't
我不在乎是哪一枪。我不
care what happens in the in the game.
关心游戏中发生的事情。
I'm entirely trying to get my reflexes
我正在努力恢复我的反应能力。
and my flow to become better at this.
并努力提高我的工作流程。
Right? So, I want to become a better
正确的？所以，我想成为一个更好的人。
gamer. That basically means I want to
游戏玩家。这基本上意味着我想要
observe the game, question the game,
观察比赛，质疑比赛，
reflect on the game, reflect on my own
反思比赛，反思自己
skills, reflect on my own beliefs,
技能，反思自己的信仰，
reflect on my understanding of things,
反思我对事物的理解，
right? And and that's how the a how the
正确的？就是这样
the consciousness invests in the
意识投资于
consciousness, not the avatar. Because
意识，而非化身。因为
then if you're that gamer,
那么，如果你就是那种游戏玩家，
the next avatar is easy for you. The
下一个头像对你来说很简单。这
next level of the game is easy for you
下一关对你来说很简单。
just because you became a better gamer.
仅仅因为你的游戏水平提高了。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So you think that consciousness is
好的。所以你认为意识是
using us as a vessel to improve?
利用我们作为工具来实现改进？
&gt;&gt; If the hypothesis is is true, it's it's
如果假设成立，那么……
just a hypothesis. We don't know if it's
只是一个假设。我们不知道是不是
true. But if this truly is a simulation,
真的。但如果这真的是一场模拟，
this is then then if you take the the
那么，如果你采取……
the the the religious definition of God
上帝的宗教定义
puts some of his soul in every human and
他将自己的灵魂注入到每个人身上，
then you become alive. You become
然后你就真正活了过来。你变得
conscious. Okay? You don't you don't
有意识的。好的？你不会，你不会
want to be religious. You can say
想成为宗教人士。你可以说
universal consciousness is spinning off
宇宙意识正在脱离
parts of itself to have multiple
自身的多个部分
experiences and interact and compete and
体验、互动和竞争
combat and love and
战斗与爱与
&gt;&gt; and understand and
并理解和
&gt;&gt; and then refine. I had a physicist say
然后进行改进。一位物理学家说
this to me the other day actually so
前几天有人跟我说了这件事。
it's quite front of mind this idea that
这个想法一直萦绕在我的脑海中：
consciousness is using us as vessels to
意识正在利用我们作为容器
better understand itself and basically
更好地了解自身，基本上
using our eyes to
用我们的眼睛
&gt;&gt; observe itself and understand which is
观察自身并了解哪个是
quite a
相当
&gt;&gt; so so if you take some of the more
所以，如果你拿一些更多的
interest most interesting religious
最感兴趣的宗教
definitions of heaven and hell for
天堂和地狱的定义
example right where basically heaven is
举个例子，天堂基本上就是
whatever you wish for you get right
无论你许什么愿，你都会如愿以偿。
that's the power of God whatever you
这就是上帝的力量，无论你
wish for you get and so if you really go
希望你能如愿，所以如果你真的要去
into the depth of that definition. It
深入探究该定义的内涵。它
basically means that this drop of
基本上意味着这一滴
consciousness that became you returned
意识回归，你已然回归。
back to the source and the source can
回到源头，而源头可以
create any other anything that it wants
它想创造什么就创造什么。
to create. So that's your heaven, right?
创造。这就是你的天堂，对吧？
And interestingly,
有趣的是，
if that if that return
如果那样的话
is done by separating your good from
这是通过将你的好东西与……分开来实现的。
your evil so that the source comes back
你的邪恶，让其源头回归。
more refined, that's exactly you know
更精细，没错，你知道的。
consciousness splitting off bits of
意识分裂成碎片
itself to to experience and then elevate
自身体验，然后提升
all of us elevate the universal
我们所有人都在提升普遍性
consciousness all all hypotheses. I
意识是所有假设。我
mean, please um you know, none of that
我的意思是，拜托，你知道，别这样。
is provable by science, but it's a very
这可以通过科学证明，但这非常
interesting thought experiment. And you
有趣的思想实验。你呢
know, a lot of AI scientists will tell
我知道，很多人工智能科学家会说
you that what we've seen in technology
让你看看我们在科技领域所看到的。
is that if it's possible, it's likely
也就是说，如果可能的话，就很有可能发生。
going to happen.
即将发生。
&gt;&gt; If it's if it's possible to
如果有可能的话
miniaturaturize something to fit into a
将某物微型化以适应
mobile phone, then sooner or later in
手机，然后迟早会
technology, we will get there.
随着科技的发展，我们终将实现目标。
And if if you ask me, believe it or not,
如果你问我，信不信由你，
it's the most humane way of handling
这是最人道的处理方式。
UBI.
全民基本收入。
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
&gt;&gt; The most humane way if you know for us
如果你知道的话，对我们来说，最人道的方式是
to live on a universal basic income and
依靠全民基本收入生活
people like you struggle with not being
像你这样的人，难以摆脱这种困境
able to build businesses is to give you
能够建立企业就是给你
a virtual headset and let you build as
虚拟头戴式显示器，让你能够构建
many businesses as you want.
你想开多少家公司都行。
Level after level after level after
一层又一层，之后
level after level, night after night.
一关接一关，夜夜交替。
Keep you alive. That's very very
让你活下去。那真是非常非常
respectful and human. Okay. And by the
尊重他人，有人情味。好的。并且通过
way, the even more humane is don't force
更人道的做法是不要强迫。
anyone to do it. There might be a few of
任何人都可以做这件事。可能有一些
us still roaming the jungles,
我们仍在丛林中游荡，
but for most of us, we'll go like, man,
但对我们大多数人来说，我们会想，唉，
I mean, someone like me when I'm 70 and,
我的意思是，像我这样的人，到了70岁的时候，
you know, my back is hurting and my feet
你知道吗，我的背和脚都疼。
are hurting and I'm going to go like,
我很受伤，我会像这样：
yeah, give me five more years of this.
是的，再给我五年这样的生活吧。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
It's weird really. I mean, the number of
真是奇怪。我的意思是，数量
questions
问题
that this new environment throws out,
这种新环境所抛弃的，
the less humane thing, by the way, just
顺便说一句，这种不太人道的做法，仅仅是
so that we close on a grumpy uh you
所以，最后我们以一个脾气暴躁的呃……你来结束。
know, is is just start enough wars to
要知道，这只是为了发动足够多的战争。
reduce UBI. And you have to imagine that
降低全民基本收入。你必须想象一下……
if the world is governed by a superpower
如果世界由一个超级大国统治
deep state type thing that they might
他们可能会搞那种深层政府之类的东西。
may want to consider that
或许应该考虑一下这一点
the eaters
食客
&gt;&gt; what shall I do about it
我该怎么办？
&gt;&gt; about
关于
&gt;&gt; about everything you've said
关于你刚才说的一切
&gt;&gt; uh well I I I still believe that this
嗯，我仍然相信这一点。
world we live in requires four skills.
我们生活的世界需要四项技能。
One skill is what I call the tool for
其中一项技能我称之为工具。
all of us to learn AI, to connect to AI,
我们所有人都要学习人工智能，与人工智能连接，
to really get close to AI, to explo ex
要真正接近人工智能，要探索……
expose ourselves to AI so that AI knows
我们让自己接触人工智能，以便人工智能了解
the good side of humanity. Okay. Uh the
人性中善良的一面。好的。呃
second is uh what I call the connection,
其次，我称之为连接。
right? So I believe that the biggest
正确的？所以我认为最大的
skill that humanity will benefit from in
人类将从中受益的技能
the next 10 years is human connection.
未来十年是人际交往的十年。
It's ability to learn to love genuinely.
它是学会真诚去爱的能力。
It's the ability to learn to have
这是学习拥有的能力。
compassion to others. It's the ability
对他人抱有同情心。这是能力
to connect to people. If you're, you
与人建立联系。如果你是，你
know, if you want to stay in business, I
我知道，如果你想继续经营下去，我
believe that not the smartest people,
不相信最聪明的人，
but the people that connect most to
但与……联系最紧密的人
people are going to have jobs going
人们将会有工作。
forward. And and the third is what I
向前。第三点就是我
call truth. The T 30 is truth. Because
说出真相。 T 30 就是真理。因为
we live in a world where all of the
我们生活在一个所有……的世界
gullible cheerleaders are being lied to
那些容易上当受骗的啦啦队员们被蒙蔽了。
all the time. So I I encourage people to
一直如此。所以我鼓励人们
question everything. Every word that I
质疑一切。我说的每一个字
said today is stupid. Fourth one which
今天说的话很愚蠢。第四个，
is very important is to magnify ethics
强调伦理道德至关重要。
so that the AI learns what it's like to
这样人工智能就能了解……是什么感觉
be human.
做个人吧。
&gt;&gt; What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
&gt;&gt; I uh I I love you so much, man. You're
我，我，我太爱你了，兄弟。你是
such a good friend. You're 32 33 now.
真是个好朋友。你现在32、33岁了。
&gt;&gt; 32. Yeah.
32. 是的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You still are fooled by the many
是的。你仍然被许多事物所蒙蔽。
many years you have to live.
你还有很多年要活。
I'm fooled by the many years I have to
我被多年的光阴蒙蔽了双眼。
live.
居住。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you don't have many years to live.
是啊，你没多少年可活了。
Not in this capacity. This world as it
不是以这种身份。这个世界就是这样
is is going to be redefined. So live the
它的定义为将被重新定义。所以要好好生活。
f out of it.
滚出局。
&gt;&gt; How is it going to be redefined?
它将如何重新定义？
&gt;&gt; Everything's going to change. Economics
一切都将改变。经济学
are going to change. Work is going to
将会改变。工作即将开始
change. Uh human connection is going to
改变。呃，人际关系将会……
change.
改变。
&gt;&gt; So what should I do?
那我该怎么办？
&gt;&gt; Love your girlfriend. Spend more time
爱你的女朋友。多花些时间
living.
活的。
Mhm. Find compassion and connection to
嗯。寻找同情心和联系
more people, be more in nature.
人越多，就越能亲近自然。
&gt;&gt; And in 30 years time, when I'm 62,
30年后，当我62岁时，
what do you how how do you think my life
你觉得我的生活怎么样？你觉得我的生活如何？
is going to look differently and be
看起来会不一样，而且会是
different?
不同的？
&gt;&gt; Either Star Trek or uh uh Star Wars.
要么是《星际迷航》，要么……呃……《星球大战》。
&gt;&gt; Funnily enough, we were talking about
有趣的是，我们当时正在谈论……
Sam Orman earlier on. He published a
萨姆·奥曼早些时候。他出版了一本
blog post in June, so last month, I
我在六月份写了一篇博客文章，也就是上个月。
believe, the month before last. Um and
相信，就在上上个月。嗯，还有
he said he called it the gentle
他说他称之为温柔的
singularity. He said we are past the
奇点。他说我们已经过去了
event horizon. For anyone that doesn't
事件视界。对于那些不了解的人来说
know Sam Orman is the the guy that made
知道萨姆·奥曼就是那个拍出《》的人
Chatb the takeoff has started. Humanity
Chatb 起飞已经开始了。人类
is close to building digital super
即将建成数字超级
intelligence.
智力。
&gt;&gt; I believe that.
我相信这一点。
&gt;&gt; And at least so far it's much less weird
至少到目前为止，情况没那么奇怪了。
than it seems like it should be because
比看起来应该的要多，因为
robots aren't walking the streets nor
机器人既不会在街上行走，也不会……
are most of us talking to AI all day. It
我们大多数人整天都在和人工智能对话。它
goes on to say, "2025 has seen the
并接着说，“2025年见证了……”
arrival of agents that can do real
能够真正有所作为的代理人的到来
cognitive work. Writing computer code
认知工作。编写计算机代码
will never be the same. 2026 will likely
一切都将不再一样。 2026年很可能
see the arrival of systems that can
见证能够实现的系统的到来
figure out new insights. 2027 might see
发现新的见解。 2027年可能会看到
the arrival of robots that can do tasks
能够执行任务的机器人的出现
in the real world. A lot more people
在现实世界中。更多的人
will be able to create software and art,
将能够创作软件和艺术作品，
but the world wants a lot more of both,
但世界需要更多这样的事物。
and experts will probably still be much
专家们可能仍然会……
better than noviceses as long as they
只要他们……就比新手强。
embrace the new tools. Generally
欣然接受新工具。一般来说
speaking, the ability for one person to
说话，一个人的能力
get much more done in 2030 than they
到2030年，他们要完成的工作比现在多得多。
could in 2020 will be a striking change
2020年可能会出现显著变化
and one many people will figure out how
很多人会想办法解决这个问题
we benefit from. In the most important
我们从中受益。在最重要的方面
ways, the 2030s may not be wildly
种种迹象表明，2030年代可能不会发生翻天覆地的变化。
different. People will still love their
不同的。人们依然会热爱他们
families, express their creativity, play
家庭，表达他们的创造力，玩耍
games, and swim in lakes. But in still
玩游戏，并在湖里游泳。但仍然
very important ways, the 2030s are
非常重要的方面，2030年代是
likely going to be wildly different from
很可能与现在的情况大相径庭
any time that has come before.
过去任何时期。
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; We do not know how far beyond human
我们不知道人类能走多远。
level intelligence we can go, but we are
我们能达到的智力水平，但我们……
about to find out.
即将揭晓。
&gt;&gt; I agree with every word other than the
除了……之外，我同意你说的每一个字。
word more.
再多说几句。
So I've I've been advocating this and
所以我一直在提倡这一点，
and laughed at for a few years now. I've
并且被嘲笑了好几年。我已经
always said AGI is 2526,
一直说AGI是2526，
right? which basically again is a is a
正确的？这基本上又是一个
funny definition but you know my AI has
有趣的定义，但你知道我的人工智能有
already happened AI is smarter than me
已经发生了，人工智能比我聪明。
in everything everything I can do they
在所有我能做的一切事上
can do better right uh artificial super
可以做得更好，对吧，呃，人造超级
intelligence is another vague definition
智力是另一个模糊的定义。
because you know the minute you you pass
因为你知道，你经过的那一刻。
AGI you're super intelligent if if the
AGI（通用人工智能）如果你超级聪明的话
smartest human is 200 IQ points and AI
最聪明的人类智商为200分，而人工智能
is 250 they're super intelligent 50 is
250，他们超级聪明；50是
quite significant okay third is as I
相当重要的第三点是，正如我
said self- evolving. That's the one.
据说是自我进化的。就是那个。
That is the one because then that 250
就是那个，因为那250
accelerates quickly and we get into
加速很快，我们进入
intelligence explosion. No, no doubt
情报爆炸。不，毫无疑问
about it. The the the you know the idea
关于它。你知道的，这个想法
that we will have robots do things. No
我们将让机器人做很多事情。不
doubt about it. I was watching a Chinese
对此表示怀疑。我当时在看一部中国电影
uh company announcement about how they
呃，公司公告，内容是关于他们如何
intend to build robots to build robots.
打算制造机器人来制造机器人。
Okay. The only thing is he says but
好的。唯一的问题是他说但是
people will need more of things
人们将需要更多东西。
right and yes we have been trained to
没错，我们接受过这方面的培训。
have more greed and more consumerism and
更加贪婪，更加消费主义
want more but there is an economic of
想要更多，但经济上存在限制。
spy of supply and demand and at at a
供需关系的间谍，以及在
point in time if we continue to consume
如果我们继续消费，那么在某个时间点就会出现这种情况。
more the price of everything will become
所有东西的价格都会上涨。
zero right and is that a good thing or a
零对，这是好事还是坏事？
bad thing depends on how you respond to
坏事取决于你如何应对
that.
那。
Because if you can create anything in
因为如果你能创造任何东西
such a scale that the price is almost
规模如此之大，价格几乎
zero, then the definition of money
如果为零，那么货币的定义就是零。
disappears and we live in a world where
消失了，我们生活在一个这样的世界里
it doesn't really matter how much money
钱多少钱其实并不重要。
you have. You can get anything that you
你有。你可以得到你想要的任何东西
want. What a beautiful world.
想。多么美好的世界。
If Samman was listening right now, what
如果萨曼现在正在听，他会说什么？
would you say to him?
你会对他说什么？
I suspect he might be listening
我怀疑他可能在偷听。
cuz someone might tweet this at him. I
因为有人可能会在推特上转发这条消息给他。我
have to say that we have uh as per his
不得不说，根据他的说法，我们有……
other tweet we have moved faster
其他推文显示我们行动更快
than our ability as humans to
比我们人类的能力更胜一筹
comprehend. Okay. And that we might get
理解。好的。我们或许会得到
really really lucky but we also might
我们真的非常幸运，但我们也可能
mess this up badly and either way we'll
把事情搞砸了，不管怎样我们都会
either thank him or blame him.
要么感谢他，要么责怪他。
Simple as that. Right. So
就这么简单。正确的。所以
single-handedly Sam Alman's introduction
萨姆·阿尔曼的介绍
of AI in the wild was the trigger that
人工智能在实际应用中的出现是引发这一现象的导火索。
started all of this.
这一切都是他开始的。
It was the netscape of the internet.
它就像互联网版的网景浏览器。
&gt;&gt; The Oppenheimer.
奥本海默。
&gt;&gt; It's it's it definitely is our
这绝对是我们的
openheimer moment. I mean I don't
奥本海默时刻。我的意思是，我没有
remember who was saying this recently
还记得是谁最近说过这话吗？
that uh we are orders of magnitude what
呃，我们相差几个数量级。
was invested in the Manhattan project is
投资了曼哈顿计划
being invested in AI
投资人工智能
&gt;&gt; right and and and I and I and I am not
对，而且，而且，我，我，我不是
pessimistic I I told you openly I
悲观的我，我坦白地告诉过你，
believe in a total utopia in 10 to 12 to
相信在10到12年内会有一个完全的乌托邦
15 years time or immediately if the evil
15年后或立即（如果邪恶行为发生）
that men can do was kept at bay right
男人能做的事情一直被限制在外，对吧？
but I do not believe humanity is getting
但我并不认为人类正在走向进步。
together enough to say, "We've just
足够团结，能够说出：“我们刚刚
received the genie in a bottle. Can we
收到了瓶子里的精灵。我们能
please not ask it to do bad things?"
请不要让它做坏事。
Anyone like not three wishes, you have
任何不喜欢三个愿望的人，你都有
all the wishes that you want. Every one
你想要的一切愿望。每个人
of us.
我们中的一些人。
And it's just screws with my mind
这简直让我心烦意乱。
because imagine if I can give everyone
因为想象一下，如果我能给每个人
in the world universal health care, you
在世界全民医疗保健体系中，你
know, no poverty, no hunger, no
知道，没有贫困，没有饥饿，没有
homelessness, no nothing. Everything's
无家可归，一无所有。一切都是
possible.
可能的。
And yet we don't.
然而我们并没有这样做。
&gt;&gt; To continue what Samman's blog said,
接续萨曼的博客所说，
which he published a month, just over a
他一个月后出版了这本书，略多于一个月前。
month ago, he said, "The rate of
一个月前，他说：“利率……”
technological progress will keep
技术进步将继续
accelerating, and it will continue to be
加速发展，而且还将持续下去
the case that people are capable of
人们有能力
adapting to almost anything. There will
几乎能适应任何环境。将会
be very hard parts like whole classes of
非常困难的部分，比如整节课
jobs going away. But on the other hand,
工作岗位正在消失。但另一方面，
the world will be getting so much richer
世界将会变得更加富裕。
so quickly that we'll be able to
如此迅速，我们就能……
seriously entertain new policy ideas we
我们认真考虑新的政策理念
never could have before. We probably
以前从未有过这样的可能。我们可能
won't adopt a new social contract all at
不会完全采纳新的社会契约
once. But when we look back in a few
一次。但当我们回顾过去几年
decades, the gradual changes will have
几十年来，这些渐进的变化将会出现
amounted in something big. If history is
最终产生了很大的影响。如果历史是
any guide, we'll figure out new things
任何指南，我们都能找到新的方法。
to do and new things to want and
想做的事情和想要的新事物
assimilate new tools quickly. Job change
快速掌握新工具。工作变动
after the industrial revolution is a
工业革命之后是一个
good recent example. Expectations will
一个很好的近期例子。预期将
go up, but capabilities will go up
上升，但能力也会上升
equally quickly, and we'll all get
同样快，我们都会得到
better stuff.
更好的东西。
&gt;&gt; We will build even more wonderful things
我们将创造更多美好的事物。
for each other. People have a long-term
彼此相爱。人们有长期
important and curious advantage over AI.
相对于人工智能，这是一个重要且令人好奇的优势。
We are hardwired to care about other
我们天生就关心他人。
people and what they think and do, and
人们以及他们的所思所想和所作所为，以及
we don't care very much about machines.
我们不太关心机器。
And he ends this blog by saying, "May we
他在博客结尾写道：“愿我们……”
scale smoothly, exponentially,
平滑地、指数级扩展
and uneventfully through super
并顺利通过了超级
intelligence."
智力。”
What a wonderful
多么美妙
wish that assumes he has no control over
希望他能掌控一切
it. May we have all the ultmans in the
它。愿我们拥有所有乌尔特曼
world help us scale gracefully and
世界帮助我们优雅地扩展规模
peacefully and uneventfully. Right.
平静而无波。正确的。
&gt;&gt; It sounds like a prayer.
听起来像是在祈祷。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. May may we have them take keep
是的。愿我们能让他们保留
that in mind. I mean think about it. I I
记住这一点。我的意思是，想想看。我 我
have a very interesting comment on what
我对什么有非常有趣的评论
you just said. We will see exactly what
你刚才说的。我们将确切地看到什么
he described there.
他在那里进行了描述。
&gt;&gt; Right? The world will become richer. So
正确的？世界将会变得更加富裕。所以
much richer. But how will we reduce
富裕得多。但是我们将如何减少
distribute the riches? And I want you to
如何分配财富？我希望你
imagine two camps. Communist China
想象一下两个阵营。中国共产党
and capitalist America.
以及资本主义的美国。
I want you to imagine what would happen
我希望你们想象一下会发生什么。
in capitalist America if we have 30%
在资本主义的美国，如果我们有30%
unemployment.
失业。
&gt;&gt; There'll be social unrest
将会爆发社会动荡
&gt;&gt; in the streets. Right.
在街头。正确的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And I want you to imagine if China lives
我想让你们想象一下，如果中国存在会怎样？
true to caring for its nations and
真正关心其国家和
replaced every worker with a robot, what
用机器人取代所有工人，这是什么？
would it give its it its citizens?
它会给予它的公民吗？
&gt;&gt; UBI.
全民基本收入。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
That is the ideological problem because
这就是意识形态问题，因为
in China's world today
在当今中国的世界里
the prosperity of every citizen is
每个公民的繁荣是
higher than the prosperity of the
高于……的繁荣
capitalist.
资本家。
In America today the prosperity of the
当今美国的繁荣
capitalist is higher than the prosperity
资本主义高于繁荣
of every citizen. And that's the tiny
每个公民。这就是微小的部分。
mind shift.
转变思维方式。
That's a tiny mind shift. Okay. where
这只是思维上的一个微小转变。好的。在哪里
where the mind shift basically becomes
思维转变基本上变成了
look give the capitalists anything they
瞧，给资本家任何东西
want all the money they want all the
他们想要所有的钱，他们想要所有的一切。
yachts they want everything they want
他们想要的游艇，他们想要的一切
&gt;&gt; so what's your conclusion there
所以你的结论是什么？
&gt;&gt; I'm hoping the world will wake up
我希望世界能够觉醒。
&gt;&gt; what can you know there's probably a
你能知道什么呢？可能存在……
couple of million people listening right
几百万人正在收听
now maybe five maybe 10 maybe even 20
现在可能是五个，也可能是十个，甚至可能是二十个。
million people
百万人
&gt;&gt; pressure Stephen
斯蒂芬的压力
&gt;&gt; no pressure to you mate I don't I don't
兄弟，别有压力，我没有，我没有。
have the answers
我有答案
&gt;&gt; I don't know the answers either
我也不知道答案。
&gt;&gt; what what should those people do
这些人应该怎么做？
&gt;&gt; as I said from a skills point of view
正如我刚才所说，从技能的角度来看
for things, right? Tools, uh, uh, human
是为了某些东西，对吧？工具，呃，呃，人类
connection, even double down on human
人与人之间的联系，甚至加倍重视人类关系。
connection. Leave your phone, go out and
联系。把手机留下，出去走走
meet humans,
与人类接触，
&gt;&gt; okay? Touch people,
好的？接触人，
you know, do it permission's permission,
你知道，做这件事需要得到许可。
&gt;&gt; right? Truth. Stop believing the lies
正确的？真相。别再相信谎言了
that you're told. Any slogan that gets,
有人告诉你。任何获得……的口号
you know, filled in your head, think
你知道，脑子里装满了东西，想想
about it four times. Understand where
大约四次。了解在哪里
your ideologies are coming from.
你的意识形态源自何处？
Simplify the truth. Right? Truth is
化繁为简。正确的？真相是
really it boils down to you know simple
说到底，这其实很简单。
simple rules that we all know okay which
我们都知道的简单规则，好吗？
are all found in ethics.
这些都可以在伦理学中找到。
&gt;&gt; How do I know what's true?
我如何才能知道什么是真话？
&gt;&gt; Treat others as you like to be treated.
己所不欲，勿施于人。
&gt;&gt; Okay. That's the only truth. The truth
好的。这是唯一的真相。真相
the only truth is everything else is
唯一的真理就是其他一切。
unproven.
未经证实。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And what can I do from a is there
好的。我能做什么？
something I can do from an advocacy
我能做的一件事（通过倡导）
social political?
社会政治？
&gt;&gt; Yes 100%. We need to ask our governments
是的，百分之百。我们需要向政府提出要求。
to start uh not regulating AI but
首先，呃，不监管人工智能，但是
regulating the use of AI. Was it the
规范人工智能的使用。是吗？
Norwegian government that started to say
挪威政府开始说
you have copyright over your voice and
你对你的声音拥有版权，
look and and liking? One of the
外观和喜好？中的一个
Scandinavian governments basically said
北欧各国政府基本上都表示
you know everyone has the has the
你知道每个人都有
copyright over their existence so no AI
它们的存在受版权保护，因此没有人工智能。
can clone it. Okay. Uh you know we have
可以克隆它。好的。呃，你知道我们有
so so my my example is very
所以，我的例子非常
straightforward. go to governments and
直截了当。去政府部门
say you cannot regulate the design of a
假设你不能监管……的设计
hammer so that it can drive nails but
锤子，以便能钉钉子，但
not kill a human but you can criminalize
虽然不能杀人，但可以将其定为犯罪。
the killing of a human by a hammer. So
用锤子杀人。所以
what's the equival
等效项是什么？
&gt;&gt; if anyone produces an um um you know an
如果有人发出“嗯嗯”的声音，你知道的
AI generated video or an AI generated
AI生成的视频或AI生成的
content or an AI it has to be marked as
内容或人工智能必须标记为
AI generated and it has to be you know
人工智能生成的，而且它必须是你知道的
we cannot start fooling each other. We
我们不能互相欺骗。我们
can you know we have to uh understand
你知道我们必须理解
certain limitations of unfortunately
遗憾的是，某些局限性
surveillance and spying and all of that.
监视、侦查等等。
So the the the the correct frameworks of
所以，正确的框架是
how far are we going to let AI go,
我们究竟要让人工智能发展到什么程度？
right? We have to go to our investors
正确的？我们必须去找我们的投资者。
and business people and ask for one
商界人士会要求一个
simple thing and say do not invest in an
简单来说，就是不要投资。
AI you don't want your daughter to be at
你不希望你的女儿身处人工智能领域
the receiving end of. It's as simple as
接收方。就这么简单
that. you know, all of the of the
那。你知道，所有的
virtual vice, all of the porn, all of
虚拟的罪恶，所有的色情内容，所有的
the, you know, sex robots, all of the
你知道，就是那种性爱机器人，所有这些
autonomous weapons, all of the, you
自主武器，所有这些，你
know, the uh trading platforms that are
你知道，那些交易平台是……
completely wiping out the the legitimacy
彻底抹杀合法性
of of the markets, everything.
市场的一切。
&gt;&gt; Autonomous weapons.
自主武器。
&gt;&gt; Oh my god.
我的天啊。
&gt;&gt; People make the case, I've heard the
人们提出了各种观点，我都听到了。
founders of these autonomous weapon
这些自主武器的创始人
companies make the case that it's
公司辩称，这是
actually saving lives because you don't
实际上，因为你不这样做，所以反而会拯救生命。
have to
必须
&gt;&gt; That is Would you want Do you really
也就是说，你真的想要吗？你真的
want to believe that?
你愿意相信吗？
&gt;&gt; I'm just representing their point of
我只是转述他们的观点。
view to play devil's advocate, Mo. They
莫，我想扮演一下魔鬼代言人的角色。
they said I heard an interview I was
他们说我听到了一个采访，当时
looking at this and one of the CEOs of
看到这一点，以及其中一位首席执行官……
one of the autonomous weapons companies
其中一家自主武器公司
said we now don't need to send soldiers.
他说我们现在不需要派兵了。
&gt;&gt; So which which lives do we save our
那么，我们应该拯救哪些生命呢？
soldiers but then but because we send
士兵们，但是因为我们派出
the machine all the way over there.
那台机器在那边。
Let's kill a million instead of
让我们杀掉一百万人，而不是
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Listen, I tend to be it goes back
是的。听着，我倾向于认为它会过去。
to what I said about the steam engine in
关于我之前提到的蒸汽机……
the cold. I actually think you'll just
寒冷。我觉得你其实会……
have more war if there's less of a cost.
如果代价更低，那就多打战争。
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; Just like
一样
&gt;&gt; and and more war if you have less of an
如果你拥有的资源更少，战争就会更多。
explanation to give to your people.
向你的民众做出解释。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. The people get mad when they lose
是的。人们输了会生气
American lives. They get less mad when
美国人的生活。他们生气的程度会降低
they lose a piece of metal. So, I think
他们丢了一块金属。所以，我认为
that's probably logical.
这或许合乎逻辑。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, okay. So, I've got a plaque.
好的。好的。我得到了一块牌匾。
Got the tools thing. I'm going to spend
工具都拿到了。我打算花
more time outside. I'm going to lobby
多花时间在户外。我要去游说
the government to be more aware of this
政府应该更加意识到这一点。
and conscious of this. Okay. And I I
并且意识到了这一点。好的。而我
know that there's some government
要知道，有些政府
officials that listen to the show
收听节目的官员们
because they they they tell me when when
因为他们会告诉我什么时候。
they when they um when I have a chance
他们，当他们，嗯，当我有机会的时候
to speak to them. So, it's um useful.
和他们交谈。所以，它还是很有用的。
We're all in a lot of chaos. We're all
我们都身处一片混乱之中。我们都是
unable to imagine what's possible.
无法想象什么是可能的。
&gt;&gt; I I think I suspend disbelief. And I
我想我暂时放下怀疑。我
actually heard Elon Musk say that in an
确实亲耳听到埃隆·马斯克说过这话。
interview. He said he was asked about AI
面试。他说有人问了他关于人工智能的问题。
and he paused for for a haunting 11
他停顿了片刻，留下令人难忘的11个音符。
seconds and looked at the interviewer
几秒钟后，他看向了面试官。
and then made a remark about how he
然后他发表了一番关于他如何的评论。
thinks he's suspended his own disbelief.
他认为自己已经暂时放下了怀疑。
And I think suspending disbelief in this
我认为，在这种情况下，暂时放下怀疑是可以理解的。
regard means just like cracking on with
尊重意味着就像继续努力一样
your life and hoping it'll be okay. And
你的生活，并希望一切都会好起来。和
that's kind of what
差不多就是这样
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I I I I absolutely believe that it
是的。我绝对相信这一点
will be okay.
没事的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; For some of us, it will be very tough
对我们中的一些人来说，这将非常艰难。
for others.
对其他人来说。
&gt;&gt; Who's it going to be tough for?
对谁来说会很艰难？
&gt;&gt; Those who lose their jobs, for example,
例如，那些失去工作的人
who those who are at the receiving end
那些处于接收方的人
of autonomous weapons that are falling
正在坠落的自主武器
on their head for two years in a row.
连续两年被戴在头上。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So the the the best thing I can do
好的。所以，我能做的最好的事情就是
is to put pressure on governments to to
目的是向各国政府施压
not regulate the AI but to establish
不是监管人工智能，而是建立
clearer parameters on the use of the AI.
更清晰的人工智能使用参数。
&gt;&gt; Yes. Okay.
是的。好的。
&gt;&gt; Yes. But I I think the bigger picture is
是的。但我认为，从更宏观的角度来看……
to put pressure on governments to
向各国政府施压
understand that there is a limit to
要明白这是有限度的
which people will stay silent.
人们会保持沉默。
&gt;&gt; Okay. and that we can continue to enrich
好的。我们可以继续丰富
our rich friends as long as we don't
只要我们不……我们富有的朋友
lose everyone else on the on the on the
把其他人都甩在后面
path.
小路。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And that as a government who is
好的。而作为一个政府，
supposed to be by the people for the
应该是人民为了……
people the beautiful promise of
人们美好的承诺
democracy that we're rarely seeing
我们很少看到的民主
anymore,
不再是了
that government needs to get to the
政府需要达到的目标
point where it thinks about the people.
它开始思考人民。
One of the most um interesting ideas
最有趣的想法之一
that's been in my head for the last
这件事一直在我脑海里萦绕着……
couple of weeks since I spoke to that
自从我上次和他谈话以来，已经过去两周了。
physicist about consciousness who said
一位物理学家谈到意识时说
pretty much what you said. This idea
基本上跟你说的一样。这个想法
that actually there's four people in
实际上里面有四个人
this room right now and that actually
现在这个房间，实际上
we're all part of the same
我们都是同一个整体的一部分。
consciousness.
意识。
&gt;&gt; All one of it. Yeah.
这一切都是一体的。是的。
&gt;&gt; And we're just consciousness looking at
而我们只是意识在观察
the world through four different bodies
通过四个不同的身体看世界
to better understand itself in the
为了更好地了解自身
world. And then he talked to me about
世界。然后他跟我谈起了……
religious doctrines, about love thy
宗教教义，关于爱你
neighbor, about how Jesus was the, you
邻居，关于耶稣是怎样的人，你
know, God's son, the Holy Spirit and how
认识神的儿子、圣灵以及如何
we're all each other and how treat
我们彼此都是对方，以及如何对待彼此。
others how you want to be treated.
其他人会如何对待你。
Really did get my head and I I started
我真的被迷住了，然后我就开始……
to really think about this idea that
认真思考一下这个想法
actually maybe the game of life is just
或许，人生这场游戏仅仅是如此而已。
to do exactly that is to treat others
这样做就是对待他人。
how you wish to be treated. Maybe if I
你希望别人如何对待你。也许如果我
just did that, maybe if I just did that,
我刚才那样做了，也许如果我那样做了的话，
I
我
I would have all the answers.
我会知道所有答案。
&gt;&gt; I swear to you, it's really that simple.
我向你发誓，事情就是这么简单。
I mean I I you know Hannah and I we
我的意思是，你知道，汉娜和我
still live between London and and Dubai.
仍然居住在伦敦和迪拜之间。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And I travel the whole world
好的。我周游世界
evangelizing what I, you know, what I uh
传扬我所知道的，你知道，我呃
um want to change the world around and I
嗯，我想改变周围的世界，而我
build startups and I write books and I
我创办初创公司，我写书，我
make documentaries and and sometimes I
制作纪录片，有时我
just tell myself
就这么告诉自己
I I just want to go hug her honestly,
我真的好想去抱抱她。
you know, I just want to take my
你知道，我只想带走我的
daughter to a trip.
送女儿去旅行。
and and in a very very very interesting
而且，这非常非常非常有趣。
way when you really ask people deep
当你真正深入地询问人们时，你会发现很多方法。
inside
里面
that's what we want and I'm not saying
这就是我们想要的，我不是说……
that's all that's the only thing we want
这就是全部，这就是我们唯一想要的。
but it's probably the thing we want the
但这可能正是我们想要的。
most
最多
&gt;&gt; and yet we're not trained you and I and
然而，你我都没有接受过相关训练。
most of us were not trained to trust
我们大多数人都没有接受过信任的训练。
life enough to say let's do more of this
生活足够充实，可以这样说：让我们多做些这样的事吧。
&gt;&gt; and I think as a universal. So Hannah's
我认为这是一种普遍现象。所以汉娜的
working on this beautiful book uh of the
正在创作这本美丽的书……
feminine and the masculine you know in a
你所了解的女性特质和男性特质
very very you know beautiful way and and
非常非常你知道美丽的方式，而且
her her view is very straightforward.
她的观点非常直率。
She basically of course like we all know
她基本上就像我们都知道的那样
the abundant masculine that we have in
我们拥有丰富的男性特质
our world today is unable to recognize
我们当今的世界无法认识到
that for life at large.
那对整个生活都至关重要。
Right? And and so you know maybe if we
正确的？所以，你知道，也许如果我们
allowed the leaders to understand that
让领导人明白这一点
if we took all of humanity and put it as
如果我们把全人类都放在一起……
one person
一个人
that one person wants to be hugged
那个人想要被拥抱
and if we had a role to offer to that
如果我们能为此提供某种角色的话。
one humanity
人类一体
it's not another yacht.
它不是另一艘游艇。
&gt;&gt; Are you religious? I'm
你信教吗？我是
&gt;&gt; very religious. Yeah.
非常虔诚。是的。
&gt;&gt; But you don't support a particular
但你不支持某个特定群体。
religion.
宗教。
&gt;&gt; I support I I follow what I call the
我支持我遵循我所谓的
fruit salad. What's the free salad?
水果沙拉。免费沙拉是什么？
&gt;&gt; You know, I I I came at a point in time
你知道，我是在某个特定时刻出现的。
and found that there were quite a few
结果发现有不少。
beautiful gold nuggets in every religion
每个宗教中都有美丽的金块
and a ton of crap, right? And so in my
还有一大堆乱七八糟的东西，对吧？所以，在我的
analogy to myself, that was like 30
以我自己为例，那就像30岁一样。
years ago. I said, "Look, it's like
几年前。我说：“你看，就像……”
someone giving you a basket of apples,
有人送给你一篮苹果，
two good ones and four bad ones. Keep
两个好的，四个坏的。保持
the good ones." Right? And so basically,
好的那些。”对吧？所以基本上，
I take two apples, two oranges, two
我拿了两个苹果，两个橙子，两个
strawberries, two bananas, and and I
草莓、两根香蕉，还有我
make a fruit salad. That's my view of
做一份水果沙拉。这就是我的看法。
religion.
宗教。
&gt;&gt; You take from every religion the good
你从每一种宗教中汲取精华。
&gt;&gt; from everyone. And there are so many
来自所有人。而且还有很多。
beautiful gold nuggets.
美丽的金块。
&gt;&gt; And you believe in a god.
你信奉上帝。
&gt;&gt; I 100% believe there is a divine being
我百分之百相信神的存在。
here.
这里。
&gt;&gt; A divine being.
一位神灵。
&gt;&gt; A designer I call it. So if if this was
我称之为设计师。所以如果这是
a video game, there is a game designer.
电子游戏中，总会有一位游戏设计师。
&gt;&gt; And you're not positing whether that's a
你并没有提出这是否是……
man in the sky with a beard.
天空中长着胡子的男人。
&gt;&gt; Definitely not a man in the sky. a man
绝对不是天上来的人。一个男人
in I mean I with all all due respect to
我的意思是，恕我直言，
you know religions that believe that uh
你知道有些宗教认为……
all of spacetime and everything in it is
整个时空以及其中的一切都是
unlike everything outside spacetime and
与时空之外的一切事物都不同，
so if some divine designer designs
所以，如果某些神圣的设计师设计
spacetime it looks like nothing in
时空中看起来什么都没有
spacetime.
时空。
So it's not it's not even physical in
所以，这甚至不是物理上的。
nature. It's not it's not gendered. It's
自然。这无关性别。它是
not bound by time. It's not, you know,
不受时间限制。你知道，并不是这样的。
these are all characters of the creation
这些都是创世神通中的人物。
of spacetime.
时空。
&gt;&gt; Do we need to believe in something
我们需要信仰什么吗？
transcendent like that to be happy? Do
幸福竟然能达到如此超凡脱俗的境界？做
you think
您认为
&gt;&gt; I have to say uh there are lots of
我得说，呃，有很多
evidence
证据
that uh relating to someone bigger than
呃，与比自己更伟大的人有关
yourself
你自己
uh makes the journey a lot more
呃，这让旅程变得更加……
interesting and a lot more rewarding.
有趣且更有意义。
&gt;&gt; I've been thinking a lot about this idea
我一直在思考这个想法。
that we need to level up like that. So
我们需要提升到那个水平。所以
level up from myself to like my family
从我自己到像我的家人一样提升自己
to my community to maybe my nation to
对我的社区，或许对我的国家
maybe the world and then something
或许是世界，然后是某种东西。
&gt;&gt; trans. Yeah.
翻译。是的。
&gt;&gt; And then if there's a level missing
如果缺少一个关卡
there people seem to have some kind of
那里的人们似乎有某种
dysfunction.
功能障碍。
&gt;&gt; So imagine a world where when I was
所以想象一下，如果我当时……的世界
younger I I was born in Egypt and for a
我年轻的时候出生在埃及，并且……
very long time the slogans I heard in
很久以来，我一直听到这些口号
Egypt made me believe I'm Egyptian
埃及让我相信我是埃及人。
right? And then I went to Dubai and I
正确的？然后我去迪拜，然后我
said no no no I'm a Middle Eastern. And
我说不不不，我是中东人。和
then in Dubai there were lots of you
当时在迪拜有很多你们这样的人。
know Pakistanis and Indonesians and so
认识巴基斯坦人和印度尼西亚人等等
on. I said no no no I'm part of the 1.4
在。我说不不不，我是1.4的一部分
four billion Muslims. And by that logic,
四十亿穆斯林。按照这种逻辑，
I immediately said, "No, no, I'm human.
我立刻说：“不，不，我是人。”
I'm part of everyone." Imagine if you
我是大家的一部分。”想象一下，如果你
just suddenly say, "Oh, I'm divine. I'm
突然说：“哦，我是神。我是……”
part of universal consciousness. All
宇宙意识的一部分。全部
beings, all living beings, including AI,
所有生物，包括人工智能，
if it ever becomes alive."
如果它真的能活过来的话。
&gt;&gt; And my dog
还有我的狗
&gt;&gt; and your dog. I'm I'm part of all of
还有你的狗。我是这一切的一部分
this
这
tapestry of beautiful interactions
一幅幅美好互动的画卷
that are a lot less serious than the
远没有那么严重
balance sheets and equity profiles that
资产负债表和权益状况
we create
我们创造
that are so simple so simple in terms of
就其而言，它们非常简单，非常简单
you know people know that you and I know
你知道，大家都知道你我都明白
each other so they always ask me you
他们彼此之间总是问我你
know how is Steven like and I go like
我知道史蒂文是什么样的人，然后我就喜欢他。
you may have a million expressions of
你可能拥有上百万种表达方式
him. I think he's a great guy, right?
他。我觉得他是个很棒的人，对吧？
You know, of course I have opinions of
当然，我也有自己的看法。
you. You know, sometimes I go like, oh,
你。你知道，有时候我会想，哦，
too shrewd, right? Sometimes to, you
太精明了，对吧？有时，你
know, sometimes I go like, oh, too
你知道，有时候我会想，哦，太……
focused on the business. Fine. But core,
专注于业务。美好的。但核心是，
if you really simplify it, great guy,
如果简单来说，他是个很棒的人。
right? And really, if we just look at
正确的？实际上，如果我们只看……
life that way, it's so simple. It's so
那样生活就简单多了。真是太
simple. If we just stop all of those
简单的。如果我们停止所有这些
fights and all of those ideologies,
争斗以及所有这些意识形态，
it's so simple. Just living fully,
就这么简单。尽情地生活，
loving, feeling compassion,
爱，有同情心，
you know, trying to find our happiness,
你知道，我们都在努力寻找幸福。
not our success.
不是我们的成功。
I should probably go check on my dog.
我应该去看看我的狗了。
&gt;&gt; Go check on your dog. I'm really
去看看你的狗。我真的
grateful for the time we keep we keep
珍惜我们共度的时光
doing longer and longer.
做的时间越来越长。
&gt;&gt; I know. I know. I just it's so crazy how
我知道。我知道。我觉得这太疯狂了
I could keep just keep honestly I could
我可以继续，老实说，我可以
just keep talking and talking because I
你就一直说下去，一直说下去，因为我
have so many I love reflecting these
我有很多喜欢反思这些的
questions on to you because because of
因为这些问题都指向你。
the way that you think. So
你的思维方式。所以
&gt;&gt; yeah today
是的，今天
&gt;&gt; today was a difficult conversation.
今天的谈话很艰难。
Anyway, thank you for having me.
总之，谢谢你们的邀请。
&gt;&gt; We have a closing tradition. What three
我们有结束仪式的传统。哪三个
things do you do you do that make your
你做的那些事，让你
brain better and three things that make
大脑功能增强的三件事
it worse?
情况更糟了吗？
three things that make it better and
让它变得更好的三件事
worse.
更糟。
&gt;&gt; So, one of my favorite exercises, what I
所以，我最喜欢的练习之一，就是我
call meet Becky, that makes my brain
打电话给贝基，这让我脑子一片空白
better. So, while meditation always
更好的。所以，虽然冥想总是
tells you to try and calm your brain
告诉你试着平静你的大脑
down and keep it within parameters of I
降低并保持在 I 的参数范围内
can focus on my breathing and so on,
可以专注于我的呼吸等等，
meet me Becky is the opposite. You know,
认识我吧，贝基的情况恰恰相反。你知道，
I call my brain Becky. A lot of people
我给我的大脑取名叫贝基。很多人
know that. So, so me meet Becky is to
记住这一点。所以，我遇见贝基就是为了
actually let my brain go loose and
真正地放开我的大脑，自由驰骋。
capture every thought. So I I normally
捕捉每一个念头。所以我通常
would try to do that every couple of
每隔一段时间我会尝试这样做
weeks or so and then what happens is it
大约几周后，就会发生这样的事：
suddenly is on a paper and when it's on
突然出现在纸上，当它出现时
paper you just suddenly look at it and
你突然瞥了一眼那张纸，然后……
say oh my god that's so stupid and you
说“我的天哪，这太蠢了”，然后你
scratch it out
划掉
&gt;&gt; right or oh my god this needs action and
对吧？或者说，我的天哪，这需要采取行动。
you actually plan something and and it's
你实际上计划了一件事，而且是
quite interesting that the more you
很有意思的是，你越多
allow your brain to give you thoughts
让你的大脑产生想法
and you listen. So the two rules is you
你听着。所以这两条规则是：
acknowledge every thought and you never
承认每一个想法，你永远不会
repeat one.
重复一次。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So the more you listen and and
好的。所以你越听，就越……
say, "Okay, I heard you." You know, you
我说：“好的，我听到了。”你知道，你
think I'm fat. What else? And you know,
我觉得自己很胖。还有什么？你知道，
eventually your brain starts to slow
最终你的大脑会开始减速。
down and then eventually starts to
向下，然后最终开始
repeat thoughts and then it goes into
重复这些想法，然后就进入了
total silence. Beautiful practice. I uh
一片寂静。练习效果很好。我呃
I don't trust my brain anymore. So
我不再相信我的大脑了。所以
that's actually a really interesting
那真是一件非常有趣的事
practice. So I debate a lot of what my
实践。所以我经常会思考我的很多事情。
brain tells me. I debate what my
大脑告诉我。我纠结于我的
tendencies and ideologies are. Okay. I
倾向和意识形态是。好的。我
think one of the most uh again in in my
想想我最……呃，再说一遍。
uh love story with Hannah, I get to
呃，我和汉娜的爱情故事，我得……
question a lot of what I believed was
我开始质疑我以前相信的很多事情。
who I am even at this age. Okay. And and
即使到了这个年纪，我依然是我自己。好的。而且
that goes really deep and it really is
这其中蕴含着非常深刻的意义，而且确实如此。
quite a it's it's quite interesting to
相当有趣
debate not object but debate what your
辩论而非反对，而是辩论你的观点。
mind believes. I think that's very very
心之所向。我认为这非常非常
useful. And the third is I've actually
有用。第三点是，我实际上已经
quadrupled my investment time. So I used
我的投资时间翻了四倍。所以我用了
to do an hour a day of reading when I
我每天抽出一个小时来阅读。
was younger every single day like going
每天都感觉更年轻，就像去
to the gym. And then it became an hour
去健身房。然后就变成了一个小时。
and a half, two hours. Now I do four
一个半小时，两个小时。现在我做四个
hours a day.
每天数小时。
&gt;&gt; Four hours a day. It is impossible to
每天四个小时。这是不可能的
keep up. The world is moving so fast.
赶上。世界变化太快了。
&gt;&gt; And so that these are uh these are the
所以这些就是……
good things that I do. The bad things is
我做的好事。不好的地方是
I don't give it enough time to to really
我没有给它足够的时间去真正地
uh slow down. Uh unfortunately I'm
呃，慢点。呃，很遗憾，我是
constantly rushing like you are. I'm
像你这样总是匆匆忙忙的。我是
constantly traveling. I have picked up a
经常出差。我捡到了一块
bad habit because of the 4 hours a day
每天4小时养成的坏习惯
of spending more time on screens. That's
花更多时间在屏幕上。那是
really really bad for my brain and I uh
对我的大脑真的非常非常不好，而且我呃
this is a very demanding question. What
这是一个非常棘手的问题。什么
else is really bad? Um
还有什么更糟糕的吗？嗯
uh
呃
yeah, I've not been taking enough care
是的，我没有好好照顾自己。
of my health recently, my physical body
最近我的健康状况，我的身体状况……
health. I had uh you remember I told you
健康。我……你还记得我跟你说过吗？
I had a very bad uh sciatic pain
我得了非常严重的坐骨神经痛。
&gt;&gt; and so I couldn't go to the gym enough
所以，我根本没法去健身房。
and accordingly that's not very healthy
因此，这并不健康。
for your brain in general.
对你的大脑整体都有好处。
&gt;&gt; Man, thanks. Thank you for having me.
老兄，谢谢。谢谢邀请。
That was a lot of things to talk about.
有很多事情要谈。
Thanks, Steve.
谢谢你，史蒂夫。
&gt;&gt; This has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信。
bit. 53% of you that listen to the show
少量。 53% 的听众收听了该节目
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常还没有订阅
show. So, could I ask you for a favor?
展示。那么，我能请你帮个忙吗？
If you like the show and you like what
如果你喜欢这个节目，并且喜欢什么
we do here and you want to support us,
我们在这里确实这样做了，而你们也想支持我们。
the free simple way that you can do just
你可以用这种免费又简单的方法做到这一点
that is by hitting the subscribe button.
也就是点击订阅按钮。
And my commitment to you is if you do
我对你的承诺是，如果你这样做
that, then I'll do everything in my
那样的话，我就会做我的一切。
power, me and my team, to make sure that
我和我的团队拥有权力，以确保
this show is better for you every single
这个节目对你来说更好！
week. We'll listen to your feedback.
星期。我们会认真听取您的反馈意见。
We'll find the guests that you want me
我们会找到你想要的客人。
to speak to and we'll continue to do
我们会与他们沟通，并继续这样做。
what we do. Thank you so much. We
我们做什么。太感谢了。我们
launched these conversation cards and
推出了这些对话卡片，
they sold out and we launched them again
它们售罄后，我们又重新推出了它们。
and they sold out again. We launched
他们又一次售罄了。我们推出了
them again and they sold out again
他们又来了，而且再次售罄。
because people love playing these with
因为人们喜欢玩这些游戏
colleagues at work, with friends at
工作中的同事，以及在……的朋友
home, and also with family. And we've
在家，也和家人在一起。我们已经
also got a big audience that use them as
也拥有大量将其用作
journal prompts. Every single time a
写作提示。每一次
guest comes on the diary of a CEO, they
一位嘉宾出现在CEO的日程安排中，他们
leave a question for the next guest in
请留下一个问题，以便下一位客人提问。
the diary. And I've sat here with some
日记。我一直和一些人坐在这里。
of the most incredible people in the
世界上最了不起的人
world. And they've left all of these
世界。他们留下了所有这些
questions in the diary. And I've ranked
日记中的问题。我已经排名了
them from one to three in terms of the
它们在各方面都从一到三名不等。
depth. One being a starter question. And
深度。第一个问题是引导性的。和
level three, if you look on the back
第三层，如果你看背面的话。
here, this is a level three, becomes a
这里，这是三级，变成了
much deeper question that builds even
一个更深层次的问题，甚至会引发更多问题。
more connection. If you turn the cards
加强联系。如果你翻牌
over and you scan that QR code, you can
扫描该二维码，即可
see who answered the card and watch the
看看谁回复了卡片，然后观看。
video of them answering it in real time.
他们实时回答问题的视频。
So, if you would like to get your hands
所以，如果你想得到它
on some of these conversation cards, go
在某些对话卡片上，去
to the diary.com or look at the link in
访问 diary.com 或查看链接
the description below.
以下是描述。
Heat. Heat. N.
热。热。N.
[Music]
[音乐]